{
  "quiz": {
    "name": "My Quiz",
    "section": [
      {
        "name": "Measurement",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Measure frequency",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Select the synonym to “Frequency”.",
                "correctAnswer": "Count",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "Duration",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Many refer to “Rate” as synonymous to Frequency, but according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task list, Frequency and Rate are separate measures. “Frequency” is synonymous with “Count”."
              },
              {
                "question": "Frequency is:",
                "correctAnswer": "A simple count of the total occurrences of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The number of occurrences of the behavior across time",
                  "The amount of time from the discriminative stimulus to the occurrence of the behavior",
                  "The amount of time between occurrences of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Many refer to “Rate” as synonymous to Frequency, but according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List, Frequency and Rate are separate measures. “Frequency” is synonymous with “Count”."
              },
              {
                "question": "Select the example that uses the measure of frequency",
                "correctAnswer": "Robert called on his phone three times.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Robert called on his phone three times in one day.",
                  "Robert called on his phone every five minutes",
                  "Robert calls on his phone every day."
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Select the example that uses the measure of frequency",
                "correctAnswer": "Jeff engaged in five angry outbursts.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Jeff engaged in angry outbursts frequently.",
                  "Jeff engaged in five angry outbursts per hour.",
                  "Jeff engaged in more angry outbursts today than he did yesterday."
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Select the example that uses the measure of frequency",
                "correctAnswer": "Erin didn’t engage in any hand flapping.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Erin engaged in hand flapping for 3.5 minutes.",
                  "Erin engaged in hand flapping for 3.5 minutes during the last hour.",
                  "Erin engaged in hand flapping five times during a five minute session."
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Select the word the means the same as “Count”",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "Latency",
                  "Inter-response time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What was the frequency of Dylan’s physical aggression if he engaged in the behavior 2 times during a 10 minute session?",
                "correctAnswer": "2",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 times/10 minutes",
                  "5 minutes",
                  "Undeterminable"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What was the frequency of Donald’s appropriate responses if he engaged in the behavior about once every hour during the day?",
                "correctAnswer": "Undeterminable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "16",
                  "24",
                  "12"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What was the frequency of the student’s “appropriate hand raising” behavior given she raised her hand twice per hour for the first hour, then none during the second hour?",
                "correctAnswer": "2",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "1",
                  "Undeterminable",
                  "1 per hour"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Frequency (Count) is usually a sufficient measure while creating and updating a behavior plan. ",
                "correctAnswer": "False",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "True",
                  "Not enough information",
                  "Sometimes"
                ],
                "explanation": "A count of the behavior is not very beneficial without the duration of the observation. Two occurrences of angry outbursts during five minutes of observation is very different from two occurrences of angry outbursts in four hours of observation. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measure rate",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Define “rate”",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequency (Count) across time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The total occurrences counted",
                  "The amount of time the behavior lasts",
                  "The amount of time from the Sd to the response"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is defined as the number of responses per unit of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Frequency across time is referred to as",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Frequency",
                  "Inter-response time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is defined as the number of responses per unit of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Rate is an appropriate measure for which of the following behaviors:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free operants",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behaviors within discrete trials",
                  "Continuous behaviors (behaviors that last a long time)",
                  "All answers provided are correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behaviors within discrete trials are not usually appropriate to measure with Rate because the antecedents are artificially contrived. Percent correct is usually a more appropriate measure, or trials-to-criterion. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is a BCBA conducting discrete trials with an individual. She is targeting appropriate responses. What would be the best measure for Mary to use?",
                "correctAnswer": "Trials to Criterion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency",
                  "Rate",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behaviors within discrete trials are not usually appropriate to measure with Rate because the antecedents are artificially contrived. Percent correct is usually a more appropriate measure, or trials-to-criterion. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a BCBA wanting to measure how often George engages in tongue clicking. What would be an appropriate measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trials to Criterion",
                  "Frequency (Count)",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is usually the best measure for free operant behaviors. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA observed her student engaging in typing during a 2 minute session. During that session, the student pressed 22 keys. What is the rate of key pressing observed by the BCBA?",
                "correctAnswer": "22 key presses per 2 minutes",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "22 ",
                  "Undeterminable",
                  "11 words per minute"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is defined as the number of responses per unit of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Rate is not an appropriate measure for which of the behaviors below?",
                "correctAnswer": "Playing on the playground",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Shouting",
                  "Raising their hand",
                  "Sticking out their tongue"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is generally not an appropriate measure for continuous behaviors (behaviors that have a long duration). Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Rate is measured using which measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Repeatability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Temporal locus",
                  "Temporal locus AND temporal extent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is based on the measurable dimension of behavior “Repeatability”. Repeatability states that instance of a response class can occur repeatedly through time. You can count behavior. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "The measurable dimension of behavior “repeatability” can be defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Instances of behavior can occur repeatedly through time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior occurs during time",
                  "Every instance of behavior occurs at a certain point in time",
                  "Behavior always repeats if it has happened before"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is based on the measurable dimension of behavior “Repeatability”. Repeatability states that instance of a response class can occur repeatedly through time. You can count behavior. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "What are the critical components of measuring rate of a behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Count of the behavior AND Observation Time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Count of the behavior AND Duration of the behavior",
                  "Duration of the behavior AND Observation time",
                  "Duration of the behavior AND Latency of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is defined as the number of responses per unit of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measure duration",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Duration is based on which measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal Extent",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Locus",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Repeatability AND Temporal Locus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is based on the measureable dimension of behavior “Temporal Extent”. Temporal extent explains that every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Temporal Extent is defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Instances of behavior can occur repeatedly through time",
                  "Every instance of behavior occurs at a certain point in time",
                  "Behavior is temporary"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is based on the measureable dimension of behavior “Temporal Extent”. Temporal extent explains that every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Appropriate units of measure to use when measuring duration include all but the following:",
                "correctAnswer": "Instances of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Seconds",
                  "Minutes ",
                  "Hours"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is usually measured with seconds, minutes, or hours. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Define “duration” with regards to measuring behavior",
                "correctAnswer": "The amount of time in which behavior occurs",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "How many times the behavior occurred",
                  "The amount of time from the Sd to the beginning of the behavior. ",
                  "Count of the behavior across time. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is the amount of time in which behavior occurs. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "During a single session, Mary observed John engaging in angry outbursts for 2 minutes, then again for 3 minutes, then again for 2 minutes. What is the total duration of angry outbursts during that session?",
                "correctAnswer": "7 minutes",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 minutes 30 seconds",
                  "3",
                  "2 minutes"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total duration per session is the duration of each occurrence of behavior during the session added together. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeremy engages in on task behavior for extended periods of time. Which measure would be most beneficial to use to measure this behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "IRT",
                  "Frequency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is usually the best measure for continuous behaviors. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a BCBA wanting to measure how often George engages in tongue clicking. What would be an appropriate measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trials to Criterion",
                  "Frequency (Count)",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is usually the best measure for free operant behaviors. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Katy engages in isolation for hours at a time. What would be an appropriate measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "Trials to Criterion",
                  "Frequency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is usually the best measure for continuous behaviors. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Fred engaged in 20 instances of yelling during a one hour observation. What was the total duration of the behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Undeterminable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "20",
                  "1 hour",
                  "3 minutes"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total duration per session is the duration of each occurrence of behavior during the session added together. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behavior is most often measured by duration?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continuous behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free operants",
                  "Behaviors within discrete trials",
                  "All types of behavior should be measured with duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is usually the best measure for continuous behaviors. Cooper, John O., Heron, Timothy E.Heward, William L.. (2007) Applied behavior analysis /Upper Saddle River, N.J. : Pearson/Merrill-Prentice Hall."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measure latency",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Latency is defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "The amount of time between the stimulus and the response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Count per unit of time",
                  "Amount of time in which a behavior occurs",
                  "The amount of time between two responses"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Latency is based on which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal Locus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Extent",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Temporal Extent AND Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is based on the dimension “Temporal Locus” Temporal locus refers to that behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Define Temporal Locus",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior occurs during some amount of time",
                  "Behavior can occur repeatedly.",
                  "Behavior always occurs after an antecedent."
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is based on the dimension “Temporal Locus” Temporal locus refers to that behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After 3.5 seconds of prompting Mary, she finally got up and placed her dishes in the dishwasher, which took her 6 seconds to complete. What is the latency of Mary complying with the prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "3.5 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "9.5 seconds",
                  "6 seconds",
                  "100%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After 3.5 seconds of prompting Mary, she finally got up and placed her dishes in the dishwasher, which took her 6 seconds to complete. In this scenario 3.5 seconds refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Latency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Duration",
                  "Inter-Response Time",
                  "Percent of compliance"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After 3.5 seconds of prompting Mary, she finally got up and placed her dishes in the dishwasher, which took her 6 seconds to complete. In this scenario 6 seconds refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Inter-Response Time",
                  "Percent of compliance"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The stoplight turned green. 1.2 seconds later James pressed the gas pedal. James pressed the gas pedal for 17 seconds until he saw a police car. .5  seconds after seeing the police car James pressed the brake pedal. What was the Latency of pushing the gas pedal?",
                "correctAnswer": "1.2 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "17 seconds",
                  ".5 seconds",
                  "18.2 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The stoplight turned green. 1.2 seconds later James pressed the gas pedal. James pressed the gas pedal for 17 seconds until he saw a police car. .5  seconds after seeing the police car James pressed the brake pedal. What was the Latency of pushing the brake pedal?",
                "correctAnswer": ".5 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "17 seconds",
                  "1.2 seconds",
                  "17.5 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The stoplight turned green. 1.2 seconds later James pressed the gas pedal. James pressed the gas pedal for 17 seconds until he saw a police car. .5  seconds after seeing the police car James pressed the brake pedal. What was the duration of pushing the gas pedal?",
                "correctAnswer": "17 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  ".5 seconds",
                  "1.2 seconds",
                  "17.5 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James pressed the brake pedal for 33 seconds. The stoplight turned green. 1.2 seconds later James pressed the gas pedal. James pressed the gas pedal for 17 seconds until he saw a police car. .5  seconds after seeing the police car James pressed the brake pedal for 3 seconds. What duration of pushing the brake pedal?",
                "correctAnswer": "36 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "33 seconds",
                  "3 seconds",
                  ".5 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Interresponse time (IRT)",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Define Interresponse time (IRT)",
                "correctAnswer": "The amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The amount of time between the stimulus and the response",
                  "The amount of time in which behavior occurs",
                  "The Count of the behavior across time"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response?",
                "correctAnswer": "IRT",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Rate",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },              {
                "question": "What is the amount of time between the stimulus and the response?",
                "correctAnswer": "Latency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "IRT",
                  "Rate",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "IRT is based on which dimension of behavior? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal locus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Temporal extent AND Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is based on the dimension ”temporal locus”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Define Temporal Locus",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior occurs during some amount of time",
                  "Behavior can occur repeatedly.",
                  "Behavior always occurs after an antecedent."
                ],
                "explanation": "Temporal locus refers to that behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a session of observation, Rachel hits her head. 8 seconds later, she hits her head again. 3 seconds later she starts yelling which lasts for 30 seconds. 18 seconds later she yells again. What is the IRT of head hitting during this session?",
                "correctAnswer": "8 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "3 seconds",
                  "30 seconds",
                  "18 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a session of observation, Rachel hits her head. 8 seconds later, she hits her head again. 3 seconds later she starts yelling which lasts for 30 seconds. 18 seconds later she yells again. What is the IRT of yelling during this session?",
                "correctAnswer": "18 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "3 seconds",
                  "30 seconds",
                  "8 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a session of observation, Rachel hits her head. 8 seconds later, she hits her head again. 3 seconds later she starts yelling which lasts for 30 seconds. 18 seconds later she yells again for 20 seconds. What is the total duration of yelling?",
                "correctAnswer": "50 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "30 seconds",
                  "20 seconds",
                  "18 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a 3 minute session of observation, Rachel hits her head. 8 seconds later, she hits her head again. 3 seconds later she starts yelling which lasts for 30 seconds. 18 seconds later she yells again. There are no other problem behaviors during the session. What is the rate of head hitting?",
                "correctAnswer": "2 per 3 minutes",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2",
                  "50 seconds",
                  "4"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John puts a potato chip in his mouth. 3 seconds later he does it again. 4 seconds later he does it again. And finally, 2 seconds later he does it one last time. What is the average Interresponse time between these 4 instances of chip consumption?",
                "correctAnswer": "3 seconds",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 seconds",
                  "4 seconds",
                  "9 seconds"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measure percent of occurrence",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Define percent of occurrence ",
                "correctAnswer": "A ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Amount of time between two consecutive responses",
                  "Time between the stimulus and the initiation of a response",
                  "A measure of how response rates change over time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Calculate the percent of occurrence of completed tasks for John. He was prompted to complete 20 different tasks and refused only 3 times. He complied following all other prompts. ",
                "correctAnswer": "85%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "15%",
                  "17",
                  "3"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary (BCBA) conducted discrete trials in which she gave her client 10 opportunities to make a correct response. The individual made 8 correct responses. What is the percent of correct responses made?",
                "correctAnswer": "80%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2",
                  "8",
                  "20%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of behavior is used when reporting a percentage?",
                "correctAnswer": "None",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Extent",
                  "Temporal Locus",
                  "Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percentages use ratios of the same dimensional quantity. The dimensional quantity is canceled out in the ratio equation and no longer contains those dimensional quantities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }, 
              {
                "question": "The following is a list of the amount of hours Jason has slept the past 10 days: 8, 6.5, 9, 7, 9, 10.5, 6, 8, 7, 7.5. What is the percent of nights Jason slept at least 8 hours?",
                "correctAnswer": "50%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "40%",
                  "60%",
                  "70%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA observed her student over 20 sessions. During those sessions, the BCBA observed physical aggression in 60% of sessions. How many occurrences of physical aggression did the BCBA observe?",
                "correctAnswer": "At least 12",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Less than 12",
                  "12",
                  "60%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA conducted a trial based functional analysis. The client engaged in hand flapping during 7 of the 10 alone sessions. What percent of occurrence is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "70%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "7",
                  "30%",
                  "100%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jim used 10 second whole interval recording to measure angry outbursts across 20 intervals. The individual engaged in angry outbursts during 4 entire intervals. What percent of occurrence of angry outbursts was observed?",
                "correctAnswer": "20%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "80%",
                  "10%",
                  "40%"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When would it be appropriate to use the measure “percent of occurrence”",
                "correctAnswer": "Correct responses in a discrete trial",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continuous behavior with a long duration",
                  "Measuring free operants in a natural environment",
                  "When you need to determine the amount of time elapsed between two behaviors."
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are testing for behavioral contrast between John’s behavior at home and at school. John engaged in disruptive behavior 4/5 days at school and 1/5 at home. What is the percent of occurrence of disruptive behavior at school and home?",
                "correctAnswer": "80% school 20% home",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "20% school 80% home ",
                  "10% school 40% home",
                  "40% school 10%home"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measure trials to criterion",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Define trials to criterion",
                "correctAnswer": "The number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities",
                  "The amount of time between two consecutive responses",
                  "The amount of time from the stimulus to the response"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is one of the uses of collecting trials to criterion data?",
                "correctAnswer": "For the BCBA to look back at the “cost” of treatment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To make function based decisions in your behavior program",
                  "For the learner to see their own progress",
                  "To see the frequency of problem behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Define trials to criterion",
                "correctAnswer": "The number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities",
                  "The amount of time between two consecutive responses",
                  "The amount of time from the stimulus to the response"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When using trials to criterion, you measure the amount of “trials” it takes for the learner to reach a set level of performance. Which of the following is NOT an example of a trial?",
                "correctAnswer": "The number of occurrences of disruptive behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Each attempt at tying his shoe",
                  "A block of 10 opportunities for the learner to discriminate letter pronunciation",
                  "Each attempt at identifying the written word “cat”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You want to measure how long it takes your client to learn how to put on his pants independently. What would be an appropriate measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Trials to Criterion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Percent of Occurrence",
                  "Frequency",
                  "IRT"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. Trials to Criterion is used to measure how many attempts it took the learner to achieve the level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You want to measure how often your client puts his pants on independently. What would be an appropriate measure? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Percent of Occurrence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trials to Criterion",
                  "Frequency",
                  "IRT"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. Trials to Criterion is used to measure how many attempts it took the learner to achieve the level of performance.  (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "It took John 7 trials to count to 5. What can the behavior analyst get from these data?",
                "correctAnswer": "The BCBA “spent” 7 trials to teach this skill.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "John will take less than 7 additional trials to count to 10",
                  "John will take 7 additional trials to count to 10",
                  "John will take more than 7 additional trials to count to 10"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "It took John 7 trials to count to 5, 5 additional trials to count to 10, and only 3 additional trials to count to 15. What can the behavior analyst get from these data?",
                "correctAnswer": "John is increasingly acquiring skills related to numbers and counting",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "John will count to 20 in only 1 trial",
                  "John is learning too quickly and will likely forget how to count later on",
                  "The BCBA “spent” 18 trials to teach this skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When would it NOT be appropriate to use trials to criterion?",
                "correctAnswer": "You are determining which behavior of concern to address",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It is important to identify if the speed at which the learner is progressing is accelerating",
                  "The behavior analyst wants to determine the “cost” of the progress",
                  "The learner’s parents ask how quickly their child is learning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion will not help determine which behavior of concern to address. The other situations are all appropriate examples of using trials to criterion. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is one of the uses of collecting trials to criterion data?",
                "correctAnswer": "To determine if the learner’s progress is accelerating",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To make function based decisions in your behavior program",
                  "For the learner to see their own progress",
                  "To see the frequency of problem behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "Trials to criterion is defined as the number of response opportunities needed to achieve a predetermined level of performance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Assess and interpret interobserver agreement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a purpose of collecting IOA?",
                "correctAnswer": "To determine if the behavior plan is being followed",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To determine the competence of new observers",
                  "To detect interobserver drift",
                  "To increase confidence in your behavior definitions"
                ],
                "explanation": "all of these are benefits of IOA except for determining if a behavior plan is being run. That is a purpose of running a treatment integrity check."
              },
              {
                "question": "Identify the formula to calculate Total Count IOA.",
                "correctAnswer": "(Smaller count/Larger count) x100 ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "(int 1 IOA + Int 2 IOA + Int N IOA)/ n intervals   x 100",
                  "(Number of intervals of 100% IOA)/n intervals  x 100",
                  "Number of trials agreement/total number of trials  x 100"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Total Count IOA is (Smaller count/Larger count) x 100. This is the simplest method, however is not always appropriate to use. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Identify the formula to calculate Exact Count-per Interval IOA",
                "correctAnswer": "(Number of intervals of 100% IOA)/n intervals  x 100",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "(Smaller count/Larger count) x100 ",
                  "(int 1 IOA + Int 2 IOA + Int N IOA)/ n intervals   x 100",
                  "Number of trials agreement/total number of trials  x 100"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Exact Count-per Interval IOA is (Number of intervals of 100% IOA)/n intervals  x 100. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Identify the formula to calculate Trial-by-Trial IOA.",
                "correctAnswer": "Number of trials agreement/total number of trials  x 100",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "(Smaller count/Larger count) x100 ",
                  "(int 1 IOA + Int 2 IOA + Int N IOA)/ n intervals   x 100",
                  "(Number of intervals of 100% IOA)/n intervals  x 100"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Trial-by-Trial IOA is Number of trials agreement/total number of trials  x 100."
              },
              {
                "question": "Calculate the Total Count IOA for Interval 5 from the table:",
                "correctAnswer": "75%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "100%",
                  "60%",
                  "50%"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Total Count IOA is (Smaller count/Larger count) x 100. This is the simplest method, however is not always appropriate to use. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Calculate the Exact Count-per-Interval IOA from the table:",
                "correctAnswer": "60%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "75%",
                  "100%",
                  "50%"
                ],

                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Exact Count-per Interval IOA is (Number of intervals of 100% IOA)/n intervals  x 100. In this example interval 2, 3, and 4 have 100% total count IOA. So (3 intervals/5 intervals) x100 = 60%."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which method of calculating IOA would be appropriate for the data below?",
                "correctAnswer": "Trial-by-trial IOA",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Total Count IOA",
                  "Mean Count-per-Interval IOA",
                  "Exact Count-per-Interval IOA"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trial-by-trial IOA would be most appropriate because we are measuring the occurrence or non-occurrence of behavior. There are only two options each trial: “yes” or “no”."
              },
              {
                "question": "Calculate the trial-by-trial IOA from the data below.",
                "correctAnswer": "80%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "50%",
                  "100%",
                  "90%"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Trial-by-Trial IOA is Number of trials agreement/total number of trials  x 100."
              },
              {
                "question": "During a session of observing behavior, observer 1 measured 18 occurrences of problem behavior. Observer 2 measured 20 occurrences of problem behavior. To calculate IOA for this session, which IOA measure should be used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Total Count IOA",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trial-by-trial IOA",
                  "Exact Count-per-interval IOA",
                  "Mean Count-per-interval IOA"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total count IOA can be used to measure IOA of two observers during a single session."
              },
              {
                "question": "During a session of observing behavior, observer 1 measured 18 occurrences of problem behavior. Observer 2 measured 20 occurrences of problem behavior. Calculate the total count IOA for this session.",
                "correctAnswer": "90%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "80%",
                  "100%",
                  "70%"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formula to calculate Total Count IOA is (Smaller count/Larger count) x 100. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Evaluate the accuracy and reliability of measurement procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "With regards to behavior analytic measurement procedures, reliability refers to",
                "correctAnswer": "The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value",
                  "The extent to which the measured value is believable",
                  "The extent to which the behavior is affected by those observing the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "With regards to behavior analytic measurement procedures, accuracy refers to",
                "correctAnswer": "The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The extent to which the measured value is believable",
                  "The extent to which the behavior is affected by those observing the behavior",
                  "The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest"
                ],
                "explanation": "Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Cassidy steps on the scale and weighs 125lbs. She steps off, then back on and it says exactly 125lbs again. Cassidy actually weighs 130lbs. The scale demonstrates:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reliability but not accuracy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Accuracy but not reliability",
                  "Reliability and accuracy",
                  "Neither reliability nor accuracy"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Cassidy steps on the scale and weighs 125lbs. She steps off and back on and weighs 130lbs. This scale demonstrates:",
                "correctAnswer": "Neither reliability nor accuracy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reliability but not accuracy",
                  "Accuracy but not reliability",
                  "Reliability and accuracy"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is a BCBA working with a client who engages in elopement. Mary has two RBTs collecting data. The two RBT’s typically have the same score, however Mary is concerned that the data is truly reflective of what is happening with her client. What should Mary do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conduct an accuracy assessment on the measure of elopement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Measure and calculate IOA",
                  "Implement corrective action on the RBT’s so they collect more accurate data ",
                  "Praise the RBT’s for good data collection practices, and ask them to do a little bit better"
                ],
                "explanation": "An accuracy assessment can be collected to determine if the data collected is truly reflective of what is happening. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is a BCBA and has a RBT collecting data on a client engaging in elopement. Mary suspects the RBT to be making up data, but isn’t sure. What should Mary do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Measure and calculate IOA",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Implement corrective action on the RBT’s so they collect more accurate data ",
                  "Praise the RBT’s for good data collection practices, and ask them to do a little bit better",
                  "Conduct an accuracy assessment on the measure of elopement"
                ],
                "explanation": "IOA should be calculated regularly to ensure the data is reliable. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Observer I measured the occurrences of angry outbursts to be 12 during the session. Observer II also measured 12. After reviewing a recording of the session the BCBA finds the true value of angry outbursts to be 18. The data reported indicate the measure to be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Neither reliable nor accurate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reliable but not accurate",
                  "Accurate but not reliable",
                  "Reliable and accurate"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Observer I measured the occurrences of angry outbursts to be 12 during the session. Observer II also measured 12. After reviewing a recording of the session the BCBA finds the true value of angry outbursts to be 12. The data reported indicate the measure to be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reliable and accurate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Neither reliable nor accurate",
                  "Reliable but not accurate",
                  "Accurate but not reliable"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Inter-Observer Agreement measures:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reliability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Accuracy",
                  "Reliability and accuracy",
                  "Neither reliability nor accuracy"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If a measure is not reliable, can the measure be accurate?",
                "correctAnswer": "No",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Yes",
                  "Sometimes",
                  "Unable to determine"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reliability is defined as “The extent to which a measurement procedure produces the same value when repeatedly contacting the behavior of interest”. Accuracy is defined as “The extent to which the measurement corresponds to the true value”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design, plot, and interpret data using equal-interval graphs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is the most commonly used graphic display used by behavior analysts?",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Line graphs are most commonly used. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line.",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Line graphs allow for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This graph is also referred to as a histogram",
                "correctAnswer": "Bar graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The bar graph is also called a histogram. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled.",
                "correctAnswer": "Bar graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The bar graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to discover the temporal distribution of a target behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What kind of graph is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of a scatterplot."
              },
              {
                "question": "What kind of graph is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Scatterplot",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of a line graph."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the x axis (or abscissa)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Horizontal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Vertical",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Ordinate"
                ],
                "explanation": "The x axis is also known as the horizontal axis, or abscissa. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the y axis (or ordinate)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Vertical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Horizontal",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Abscissa"
                ],
                "explanation": "The y axis is the vertical axis, or ordinate. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design plot and interpret data using a cumulative record to display data.",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This type of graph was developed by Skinner to collect data in the experimental analysis of behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Cumulative record",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The cumulative record was developed by Skinner. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation.",
                "correctAnswer": "Cumulative record",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The cumulative record displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a semilogarithmic chart?",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph"
                ],
                "explanation": "The standard celeration chart is a semilogarithmic chart. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments.",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph"
                ],
                "explanation": "The standard celeration chart is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In this cumulative record, what is likely measured across the x axis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Sessions",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency of the target behavior",
                  "Total frequency of the target behavior",
                  "Rate of the target behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Sessions is likely recorded along the x axis (horizontal axis)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In this cumulative record, what is likely measured across the y axis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Total frequency of the target behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Sessions",
                  "Frequency of the target behavior",
                  "Rate of the target behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total frequency of the target behavior is the likely measured along the y axis (vertical axis)."
              },
              {
                "question": "In a cumulative record, what is indicated by a steeper slope?",
                "correctAnswer": "A higher response rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A lower response rate",
                  "A longer response duration",
                  "A shorter response duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "In a cumulative record, the steeper the slope, the higher the response rate."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the x axis (or abscissa)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Horizontal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Vertical",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Ordinate"
                ],
                "explanation": "The x axis is also known as the horizontal axis, or abscissa. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the y axis (or ordinate)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Vertical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Horizontal",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Abscissa"
                ],
                "explanation": "The y axis is the vertical axis, or ordinate. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which measure is typically used while graphing on a cumulative record?",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Duration",
                  "Interresponse time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is typically used while graphing on a cumulative record."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and implement continuous measurement procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a continuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Time Sampling",
                  "Planned Activity Check"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording and Timing are common procedures used when collecting continuous measurement data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a continuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Timing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time sampling",
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "PLACHECK"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording and Timing are common procedures used when collecting continuous measurement data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Wrist counters, hand-tally digital counters, tally marks, are all devices that can be used with which measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Timing",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "Whole-Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Wrist counters, digital counters, or simple tally marks on paper can all be used with event recording procedures. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stopwatches/timers are necessary for which measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Timing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "Whole-Interval Recording",
                  "Event Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Timing measurement procedures require a device to track time for accurate time measures. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jacob engages in hand clapping frequently, but it is easy to distinguish one instance of the behavior from another. Which measurement procedure should you use?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Timing",
                  "Whole-interval recording",
                  "Planned Activity Check"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording should be used to measure frequency of behavior if one instance of the behavior is distinguishable from another. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jacob engages in hand clapping frequently, and it is difficult to distinguish one instance of the behavior from another. Which measurement procedure should you use?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole-interval recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Event Recording",
                  "Timing",
                  "Planned Activity Check"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole-interval recording is a discontinuous measurement procedure best used when one instance of behavior is not distinguishable from another. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Alice engages in episodes of screaming. You want to measure continuous duration of this behavior. Which measurement procedure do you use?",
                "correctAnswer": "Timing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned Activity Check",
                  "Whole-interval recording",
                  "Event Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording and Timing are common procedures used when collecting continuous measurement data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is measured using Event Recording procedures only?",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Duration",
                  "Latency",
                  "Rate"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording is used to measure frequency of behavior. Timing is used to measure duration, latency, and IRT. Both procedures are used in measuring Rate of behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can be measured using Timing procedures only?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency",
                  "Rate",
                  "IOA"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording is used to measure frequency of behavior. Timing is used to measure duration, latency, and IRT. Both procedures are used in measuring Rate of behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can be measured using both Event Recording and Timing procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency",
                  "Duration",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording is used to measure frequency of behavior. Timing is used to measure duration, latency, and IRT. Both procedures are used in measuring Rate of behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and implement discontinuous measurement procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "All of the following are discontinuous measurement procedures EXCEPT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Whole Interval Recording",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling"
                ],
                "explanation": "Discontinuous measurement procedures do not require constant measurement of behavior, rather behavior is observed in intervals, measuring occurrence or non-occurrence of behavior. This includes partial interval and whole interval recording, as well as momentary time sampling, and PLACHECK. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed.",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole Interval Recording is when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session observed.",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK",
                  "Whole Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording occurs when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “yes” if the behavior was occurring at the end of the interval.",
                "correctAnswer": "Momentary Time Sampling",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "PLACHECK",
                  "Whole Interval Recording",
                  "Partial Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Momentary time sampling occurs when the observer marks “yes” if the behavior was occurring at the end of the interval. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the teacher momentarily observes a group of students and records the amount of children engaging in the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "PLACHECK",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole Interval Recording",
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling"
                ],
                "explanation": "Planned Activity Check (PLACHECK) occurs when the teacher momentarily observes a group of students and records the amount of children engaging in the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “no” if the behavior does not occur throughout the entire session.",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole Interval Recording is when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “no” if the behavior did not occur at all during the session. If there were any occurrences they mark “yes”.",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK",
                  "Whole Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording occurs when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a 10 second interval, Ruby engages in disruptive behavior twice for 5 seconds total duration. Using a whole interval recording procedure, what would be marked on the data sheet?",
                "correctAnswer": "“no”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "“yes”",
                  "5 seconds",
                  "2"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole Interval Recording is when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a 10 second interval, Ruby engages in disruptive behavior twice for 5 seconds total duration. Using a partial interval recording procedure, what would be marked on the data sheet?",
                "correctAnswer": " “yes”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "“no”",
                  "5 seconds",
                  "2"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording occurs when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ruby engaged in disruptive behavior for 9 seconds, but stopped right before the end of the 10 second interval. Using a momentary time sampling at the end of the 10 second interval, what would be marked on the data sheet?",
                "correctAnswer": "“no”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "“yes”",
                  "5 seconds",
                  "2"
                ],
                "explanation": "Momentary time sampling occurs when the observer marks “yes” if the behavior was occurring at the end of the interval. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and implement choice measures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Stimulus Preference Assessments are used to identify:",
                "correctAnswer": "Appetitive Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Aversive Stimuli",
                  "Reinforcers",
                  "Punishers"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus preference assessments are used to identify preferred (appetitive) stimuli. Appetitive stimuli are not always reinforcers."
              },
              {
                "question": "All of the following are trial based methods for determining preferred stimuli EXCEPT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free Operant Observation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free operant observation can be used to determine preferred stimuli, but it is not trial based. Single stimulus, paired stimuli, and multiple stimuli are all trial based methods."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, stimuli are measure consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents a stuffed toy and measures how long the individual interacts with the toy. The BCBA removes the stuffed toy and presents a backpack and measures the interaction with the item. The BCBA removes the backpack and presents a spinner toy. What type of preference is the BCBA conducting?",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, 2 stimuli are presented to the individual, creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents the child with a stuffed toy and a fidget spinner, and the child selects the fidget spinner. The BCBA then presents a fidget spinner and a backpack, and the child selects the fidget spinner. This is done repeatedly, varying the pairing of items. What type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": " Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA places the item back into the array of items. The BCBA says “choose one” again. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA removes that item from sight. The BCBA says “choose one” again with only the remaining 5 items displayed. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Experimental Design",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Use the dimensions of ABA to evaluate whether interventions are behavior analytic in nature",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Sally is a BCBA and decides to show her client’s parents what ABA is capable of. She teaches the child to walk in circles with the child’s hands behind his back. This behavior has no socially acceptable purpose, and was trained entirely to impress the parents. What dimension of ABA is Sally violating?",
                "correctAnswer": "Applied",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Technological"
                ],
                "explanation": "Applied refers to the behaviors behavior analysts address. Behavior analysts should address behaviors which have a socially significant change in the individual’s life. In the example above, the behavior analyst addresses a behavior that will not positively affect the person’s life. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jake creates a behavior intervention plan and addresses “Angry Outbursts” in the plan. His definition for Angry Outbursts states “Defined as whenever Yolanda gets upset”. Which dimension of behavior is Jake violating?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Applied",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Effective"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral refers to a couple things. First, behavior needs to be measurable. The observers need to know when the behavior happens with clear behavioral definitions. Second, we study behavior, not about behavior. If we want to improve behavior of an individual, we look at the specific behavior and the environment, not indirect measures such as questionnaires. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA wants to find out why a client is engaging in problem behavior. The BCBA distributes a questionnaire about the individual’s mood. He determines that the client is engaging in the problem behavior because the client’s mood is frequently poor. This violates which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Applied",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Effective"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral refers to a couple things. First, behavior needs to be measurable. The observers need to know when the behavior happens with clear behavioral definitions. Second, we study behavior, not about behavior. If we want to improve behavior of an individual, we look at the specific behavior and the environment, not indirect measures such as questionnaires. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Melanie measured the occurrences of her client’s tantrum behavior in baseline. She then implemented an intervention, and shortly after returned to baseline. She was able to determine the intervention’s effect on the client’s tantrum behavior. Melanie exemplified which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Analytic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Technological",
                  "Conceptually Systematic",
                  "Effective"
                ],
                "explanation": "Analytic refers to the need for behavior analysts to determine a functional relationship between the intervention and change in the targeted behavior. A simple report that things are improving isn’t good enough for behavior analysts. Demonstrating that the intervention helped improve the behavior is necessary. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a BCBA that just received a new client. The new client received services prior and already had a behavior intervention plan in place. John was able to read his prior behavior plan and know completely what interventions were being run before, to the extent he could replicate the interventions. This demonstrates which dimension of ABA?",
                "correctAnswer": "Technological",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conceptually systematic",
                  "Effective",
                  "Behavioral"
                ],
                "explanation": "Technological refers to the need for behavior analysts to operate under sufficient detail to where the interventions would be able to be replicated with the same results. Detail and clarity is essential for this to take place. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jared is a BCBA and decides to implement a strategy known as “Astronaut Training”. This involves having the child sit in a rotating chair while playing space sound effects. Jared states that he does this because he heard it’s an effective treatment for Autism, even though it doesn’t use the basics of behavior analysis. Jared is violating which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conceptually systematic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Technological",
                  "Effective",
                  "Generality"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conceptually systematic refers to the behavior analyst’s need to be grounded in the well-researched basics of ABA including reinforcement and punishment. Our interventions shouldn’t stray from these technologies, even when applying them differently. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "With ABA strategies, Amy was able to improve greatly in the frequency of appropriate questions in the classroom. She is asking questions applicable to the learning content, and is not asking distracting questions. Which dimension of ABA is evident?",
                "correctAnswer": "Effective",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Generality",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Technological"
                ],
                "explanation": "Effective refers to the behavior analyst’s drive for effective interventions. Our interventions should lead toward progress. Behavior analysts continue to implement interventions until the behavior is occurring at the desired level of performance. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ted received behavior analytic services, addressing his cursing behavior. These services were terminated 3 months ago after reaching his goals. Ted continues to not curs and is frequently making appropriate comments. Which dimension of ABA is evident?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generality",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Effective",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Technological"
                ],
                "explanation": "Generality refers to behavior change that lasts over time, that appears in novel environments, or leads to other untrained improved behavior. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Susan learned how to write her name while at her school desk with a pencil. Her mom notices her independently writing her name at home with crayons. Which dimension of ABA is evident?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generality",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Effective",
                  "Analytic",
                  "Technological"
                ],
                "explanation": "Generality refers to behavior change that lasts over time, that appears in novel environments, or leads to other untrained improved behavior. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Adam wrote a behavior support plan and included an immense amount of detail on how to implement the interventions. This is an example of which dimension of ABA?",
                "correctAnswer": "Technological",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conceptually systematic",
                  "Effective",
                  "Behavioral"
                ],
                "explanation": "Technological refers to the need for behavior analysts to operate under sufficient detail to where the interventions would be able to be replicated with the same results. Detail and clarity is essential for this to take place. (Baer, Wolf, & Risley, 1968)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Review and interpret articles from the behavior-analytic literature",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Jerry conducts research, and his study concludes that the intervention had a positive effect on behavior. This turned out to be false, and a misinterpretation of the data. What kind of error is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Type I error",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Type II error",
                  "Social validity",
                  "External validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Type I error (false positive) is made when the researcher concludes that the independent variable had an effect on the dependent variable, with no such relation occurs in nature. Type II error (false negative) is made when the researcher concludes that the independently did not have an effect on the dependent variable, when in fact it did. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry conducts research, and his study concludes that the intervention did not have an effect on behavior. This turned out to be false, and a misinterpretation of the data. The intervention did in fact have an effect on the behavior. What kind of error is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Type II error",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Social validity",
                  "External validity",
                  "Type I error"
                ],
                "explanation": "Type I error (false positive) is made when the researcher concludes that the independent variable had an effect on the dependent variable, with no such relation occurs in nature. Type II error (false negative) is made when the researcher concludes that the independently did not have an effect on the dependent variable, when in fact it did. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of error is also known as a false positive. They report a functional relation between the independent and dependent variables, when there actually is not one.",
                "correctAnswer": "Type I error",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Type II error",
                  "Social validity",
                  "External validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Type I error (false positive) is made when the researcher concludes that the independent variable had an effect on the dependent variable, with no such relation occurs in nature. Type II error (false negative) is made when the researcher concludes that the independently did not have an effect on the dependent variable, when in fact it did. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of error is also known as a false negative. They report no functional relation between the independent and dependent variables, when one actually occurred.",
                "correctAnswer": "Type II error",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Social validity",
                  "External validity",
                  "Type I error"
                ],
                "explanation": "Type I error (false positive) is made when the researcher concludes that the independent variable had an effect on the dependent variable, with no such relation occurs in nature. Type II error (false negative) is made when the researcher concludes that the independently did not have an effect on the dependent variable, when in fact it did. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of error occurs most frequently in behavior-analytic literature?",
                "correctAnswer": "Type II errors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Type I errors",
                  "External validity",
                  "Social validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts use visual inspection to interpret data and graphs. This results in an increased commission of type II errors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is the most common, and most recommended method for interpreting data for behavior analysts?",
                "correctAnswer": "Visual inspection",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Statistical analysis",
                  "Systematic replication",
                  "Maintenance of behavior change"
                ],
                "explanation": "Visual inspection is the most common and most recommended method for interpreting data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of validity refers to the extent to which the study shows that the changes to the independent variable were due to the dependent variable, as opposed to other uncontrolled variables.",
                "correctAnswer": "Internal validity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "External validity",
                  "Social validity ",
                  "Generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Internal validity refers to the extent to which the study shows that the changes to the independent variable were due to the dependent variable, as opposed to other uncontrolled variables. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of validity refers to the extent to which the changes made to the behavior were significant to the individual. The interventions used were humane and culturally accepted.",
                "correctAnswer": "Social validity ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Generalization",
                  "Internal validity",
                  "External validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Social validity refers to the extent to which the changes made to the behavior were significant to the individual. The interventions used were humane and culturally accepted. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of validity refers to the degree to which the findings from the study have generalized to other behaviors, settings, and/or subjects.",
                "correctAnswer": "External validity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Internal validity",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Social validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "External validity refers to the degree to which the findings from the study have generalized to other behaviors, settings, and/or subjects. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What process needs to occur for research findings to have external validity",
                "correctAnswer": "Replication",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Generalization",
                  "Expert Evaluation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Replication of research findings needs to occur for the research findings to have external validity. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Systematically arrange independent variables to demonstrate their effects on dependent variables",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "In behavior analytic experiments, this variable is typically the behavior of interest. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent variable",
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The dependent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it changes “dependent” on the independent variable. It’s usually a target behavior in behavior analytic research. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In behavior analytic experiments, this variable is usually the intervention implemented.",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable",
                  "Dependent variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The independent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it affects the dependent variable. In behavior analytic research it is typically the intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In behavior analytic experiments, this type of variable are those stimuli the researchers take in to account and hold to a constant as to not interfere with the integrity of the study. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Extraneous variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dependent variable",
                  "Independent variable",
                  "Confounding variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extraneous variables are those stimuli the researchers take in to account and hold to a constant as to not interfere with the integrity of the study. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In behavior analytic experiments, this type of variable are those stimuli that haven’t been controlled for, and are suspected to have influence on the dependent variable. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Confounding variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extraneous variable",
                  "Dependent variable",
                  "Independent variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "Confounding variables are those stimuli that haven’t been controlled for, and are suspected to have influence on the dependent variable. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Albert wants to determine if implementing a DRA procedure will decrease the occurrences of yelling for his client. The DRA procedure is a ",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable",
                  "Dependent variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The independent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it affects the dependent variable. In behavior analytic research it is typically the intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Albert wants to determine if implementing a DRA procedure will decrease the occurrences of yelling for his client. In this study, the occurrences of yelling are the",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent variable",
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The dependent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it changes “dependent” on the independent variable. It’s usually a target behavior in behavior analytic research. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeff conducted a study, and found that providing immediate and positive feedback to his employee resulted in increased work performance. In this study, work performance is the",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent variable",
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The dependent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it changes “dependent” on the independent variable. It’s usually a target behavior in behavior analytic research. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeff conducted a study, and found that providing immediate and positive feedback to his employee resulted in increased work performance. In this study, delivering immediate and positive feedback is the",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Confounding variable",
                  "Extraneous variable",
                  "Dependent variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "The independent variable in an experiment is used to determine if it affects the dependent variable. In behavior analytic research it is typically the intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeff conducted a study, and found that providing immediate and positive feedback to his employee resulted in increased work performance. However, at the same time the employee was given a raise, which may have impacted his performance as well. In this study, the raise given to the employee is a",
                "correctAnswer": "Confounding variable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extraneous variable",
                  "Dependent variable",
                  "Independent variable"
                ],
                "explanation": "Confounding variables are those stimuli that haven’t been controlled for, and are suspected to have influence on the dependent variable. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeff conducted a study, and found that providing immediate and positive feedback to his employee resulted in increased work performance. Before conducting the study, Jeff made sure that the employee wouldn’t be getting a raise, and ensured the employee’s environment would remain consistent throughout the study including lighting, temperature, and noise level. These stimuli being accounted for are:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extraneous variables",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dependent variables",
                  "Independent variables",
                  "Confounding variables"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extraneous variables are those stimuli the researchers take in to account and hold to a constant as to not interfere with the integrity of the study. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use withdrawal/reversal designs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is another name for the withdrawal experimental design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reversal",
                  "ABA",
                  "ABAB"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are names to this experimental design.  (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is another name for the withdrawal experimental design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reversal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Alternating treatments ",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reversal is another name for the withdrawal experimental design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When conducting an A-B-A reversal design, how many data points at a minimum should be present before moving from baseline to treatment?",
                "correctAnswer": "3",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2",
                  "5",
                  "1"
                ],
                "explanation": "At least 3 data points are required to constitute a trend. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In an A-B-A reversal design, what does “A” stand for?",
                "correctAnswer": "Baseline",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Treatment",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Applied"
                ],
                "explanation": "the “A” phases are baseline phases. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is an A-B-A-B design better than A-B-A design",
                "correctAnswer": "Reintroducing treatment phase replicates the treatment effects, strengthening the demonstration of experimental control.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The longer the study, the more reliable it is.",
                  "It enables the learner to better discriminate different phases",
                  "It Baseline phase is critical to the demonstration of control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reintroducing treatment phase replicates the treatment effects, strengthening the demonstration of experimental control. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is generally the most straightforward and powerful within-subject design for demonstrating a functional relation between an environmental manipulation and a behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A-B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Changing criterion"
                ],
                "explanation": "A-B-A-B design is generally the most straightforward and powerful within-subject design for demonstrating a functional relation between an environmental manipulation and a behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "A-B-A design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What effect did treatment have on the target behavior according to this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "The treatment increased the target behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The treatment decreased the target behavior",
                  "The treatment had no effect on the target behavior",
                  "Cannot be determined with this graph."
                ],
                "explanation": "The treatment increased the target behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A-B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an A-B-A-B design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an alternating treatments design."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use alternating treatments designs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which treatment design excels at comparing multiple treatments to determine which is most effective?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments design ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reversal",
                  "Changing criterion",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Alternating treatments design excels at comparing multiple treatments to determine which is most effective. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the results from treatment A depicted as the yellow data path.",
                "correctAnswer": "Resulted in an increasing trend, ending higher than all other treatments.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Resulted in a decreasing trend, ending lower than all other treatments.",
                  "Averaged the highest level of target behavior with zero trend",
                  "Averaged lowest level of target behavior with zero trend."
                ],
                "explanation": "Treatment A resulted in an increasing trend, ending higher than all other treatments."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the results from treatment B depicted as the Red data path.",
                "correctAnswer": "Averaged the highest level of target behavior with zero trend",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Averaged lowest level of target behavior with zero trend.",
                  "Resulted in an increasing trend, ending higher than all other treatments.",
                  "Resulted in a decreasing trend, ending lower than all other treatments."
                ],
                "explanation": "Treatment B averaged the highest level of target behavior with zero trend."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the results from treatment C depicted as the gray data path.",
                "correctAnswer": "Averaged lowest level of target behavior with zero trend.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Resulted in an increasing trend, ending higher than all other treatments.",
                  "Averaged the highest level of target behavior with zero trend",
                  "Resulted in a decreasing trend, ending lower than all other treatments."
                ],
                "explanation": "Treatment C averaged the lowest level of target behavior with zero trend."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a possible variation to the alternating treatments design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single-phase alternating treatments design without a no-treatment control condition",
                  "Single-phase design in which two or more conditions are alternated",
                  "Two-phase design consisting of an initial baseline phase followed by a phase with two or more treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are possible variations."
              },
              {
                "question": "What effect did treatment have on the target behavior according to this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "The treatment increased the target behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The treatment decreased the target behavior",
                  "The treatment had no effect on the target behavior",
                  "Cannot be determined with this graph."
                ],
                "explanation": "The treatment increased the target behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A-B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an A-B-A-B design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an alternating treatments design."
              },
              {
                "question": "How many treatments is the minimum amount to be tested in an alternating treatments design?",
                "correctAnswer": "2",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "3",
                  "1",
                  "4"
                ],
                "explanation": "2 treatments is the minimum amount of treatments to be tested. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage to the alternating treatments design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Does not require treatment withdrawal",
                  "Minimizes irreversibility problem",
                  "Minimizes sequence effects"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are advantages. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use changing criterion designs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is used, when the treatment is applied in a stepwise fashion to  a single behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Changing criterion design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Alternating treatments ",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe"
                ],
                "explanation": "Changing criterion design should be used when the treatment is applied in a stepwise fashion to a single behavior?"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors would benefit from a changing criterion experimental design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Slowly increasing the amount of ounces the learner drinks by setting a reward for 8 ounces. Once the learner responds at a steady rate increase to 16, 24, 32, and finally 40 oz. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing the rate of appropriate questions by using a reward program.",
                  "Comparing the effects of two different treatments to determine which is the most effective.",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Slowly increasing the amount of ounces the learner drinks by setting a reward for 8 ounces. Once the learner responds at a steady rate increase to 16, 24, 32, and finally 40 oz. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What criterion is set during the initial baseline phase of a changing criterion design?",
                "correctAnswer": "No criterion set",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "1",
                  "It depends on the individual circumstances",
                  "The end goal"
                ],
                "explanation": "No criterion is set during the initial baseline phase."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of the changing criterion design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It does not require a withdrawal or reversal",
                  "It enables an experimental analysis within the context of a gradually improving behavior, thus complementing the practice of many teachers",
                  "It is an effective design to demonstrate experimental control in many circumstances."
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are correct."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of the changing criterion design?",
                "correctAnswer": "It does not require a withdrawal or reversal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "The target behavior must already be in the subject’s repertoire.",
                  "Incorporating necessary features of the design may impede optimal learning rates."
                ],
                "explanation": "It does not require a withdrawal or reversal"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage of the changing criterion design?",
                "correctAnswer": "The behavior must already be in the subject’s repertoire",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "It does not require a withdrawal or reversal",
                  "It enables an experimental analysis within the context of a gradually improving behavior, thus complementing the practice of many teachers"
                ],
                "explanation": "One disadvantage is that the behavior must already be in the subject’s repertoire."
              },
              {
                "question": "In this graph, what do the horizontal lines going through the data points represent?",
                "correctAnswer": "The set criterion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The mean",
                  "The median",
                  "The goal"
                ],
                "explanation": "The horizontal lines represent the set criterion."
              },
              {
                "question": "In this graph, why does the second to last data set decrease substantially, and then increase during the last data set?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conducting this optional reversal design strengthens the experimental control in that the behavior followed the set criterion when it was increased as well as decreased.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It was likely a treatment error.",
                  "Behavior is not 100% predictable.",
                  "It was an extinction trial."
                ],
                "explanation": "Conducting this optional reversal design strengthens the experimental control in that the behavior followed the set criterion when it was increased as well as decreased."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Changing criterion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe"
                ],
                "explanation": "Changing criterion design is depicted."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an alternating treatments design."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use multiple baseline designs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is a variation of the multiple baseline design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple baseline across subjects",
                  "Multiple baseline across behaviors",
                  "Multiple baseline across settings"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are variations of the multiple baseline design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple baseline",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the multiple baseline design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the delayed multiple baseline design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of multiple baseline design is depicted in this graph? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Across behaviors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Across settings",
                  "Across subjects",
                  "Delayed multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph depicts the multiple baseline across behaviors"
              },
              {
                "question": "When might the multiple baseline design be more appropriate to use over the reversal design?",
                "correctAnswer": "When the target behavior is likely to be irreversible",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The multiple baseline design is always more appropriate",
                  "When reversing conditions is easily done",
                  "When you are measuring the effects of multiple treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is appropriate to use the multiple baseline design over the reversal design when the target behavior is likely to be irreversible or when it is undesirable, impractical, or unethical to reverse conditions. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When might the multiple baseline design be more appropriate to use over the reversal design?",
                "correctAnswer": "When it is undesirable, impractical, or unethical to reverse conditions",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The multiple baseline design is always more appropriate",
                  "When you are measuring the effects of multiple treatments",
                  "When the target behavior is easily reversible"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is appropriate to use the multiple baseline design over the reversal design when the target behavior is likely to be irreversible or when it is undesirable, impractical, or unethical to reverse conditions. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a multiple baseline design, once stable responding is achieved in the baseline, what can you predict about subsequent sessions assuming the environment remains constant and no treatment is implemented?",
                "correctAnswer": "It would remain at current levels",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It would increase",
                  "It would decrease",
                  "It would increase or decrease depending on the treatment effects"
                ],
                "explanation": "Baseline assumes that responding would maintain at that level if the environment were to remain constant. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are implementing a multiple baseline across three subjects. Your first subject moves from baseline to treatment phase. Which phase should the second and third subjects be in during the first three sessions of treatment for subject 1?",
                "correctAnswer": "Baseline",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Treatment",
                  "Post-treatment",
                  "Pre-treatment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Subjects 2 and 3 should be in baseline phase. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are implementing a multiple baseline across three subjects. Your second subject moves from baseline to treatment phase. Which phase should the First subject be in during the first three sessions of treatment for the second subject?",
                "correctAnswer": "Treatment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Baseline",
                  "Post-treatment",
                  "Pre-treatment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The first subject should be in treatment phase. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a variation of the multiple baseline design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple probe design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Alternating treatments design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "The multiple probe design is considered a variation of the multiple baseline design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use multiple probe designs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is uses intermittent measures to analyze the relation between the independent variable and the learning of a task sequence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple probe design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "The multiple probe design is used to analyze the learning of subsequent skills in a chain. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design uses an initial baseline and intervention, then subsequent baselines are added to the design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple probe design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "The delayed multiple baseline design"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple probe design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the multiple probe design."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Multiple probe design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the delayed multiple baseline design. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What is another term for intermittent measures to analyze the current levels of each phase?",
                "correctAnswer": "Probe",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Baseline",
                  "Criterion",
                  "Test"
                ],
                "explanation": "Probe is another term for intermittent measures used to analyze the current levels of each phase. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The multiple probe design would be appropriate to use for which behavior goal?",
                "correctAnswer": "Learning the steps to brush ones teeth",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing appropriate attention seeking behaviors",
                  "Decreasing tantrum behavior",
                  "Establish which treatment is most effective."
                ],
                "explanation": "learning the steps to brush ones teeth would be an appropriate behavior to address using a multiple probe design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a multiple probe design, while the first behavior is in baseline phase, the second behavior should be in which phase?",
                "correctAnswer": "Probe",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Baseline",
                  "Treatment",
                  "Follow up"
                ],
                "explanation": "Probes should be conducted while the first behavior is in baseline phase. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a multiple probe design, while the second behavior is in treatment/instruction phase, what should occur in the first phase?",
                "correctAnswer": "Probe",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Baseline",
                  "Treatment",
                  "Follow up"
                ],
                "explanation": "During the second behavior is in treatment, the first behavior is probed to ensure it is maintained at an appropriate level. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors would be appropriate to target using a multiple probe design?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Learning the steps to using the bathroom",
                  "Learning how to brush one’s teeth",
                  "Learning how to wash one’s clothes"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are appropriate behaviors to target during a multiple probe design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors would be appropriate to target using a multiple probe design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Leaning the steps to using the bathroom",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Increasing appropriate attention seeking behaviors",
                  "Decreasing tantrum behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Learning the steps to using the bathroom would be appropriate to target using a multiple probe design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use combinations of design elements",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is uses intermittent measures to analyze the relation between the independent variable and the learning of a task sequence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple probe design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "The multiple probe design is used to analyze the learning of subsequent skills in a chain. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design uses an initial baseline and intervention, and then subsequent baselines are added to the design?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple probe design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "The delayed multiple baseline design"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple probe design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the multiple probe design."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Multiple probe design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the delayed multiple baseline design. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple baseline",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Delayed multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the multiple baseline design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Changing criterion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Multiple probe"
                ],
                "explanation": "Changing criterion design is depicted."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an alternating treatments design."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A-B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an A-B-A-B design."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which treatment design excels at comparing multiple treatments to determine which is most effective?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternating treatments design ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reversal",
                  "Changing criterion",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Alternating treatments design excels at comparing multiple treatments to determine which is most effective. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A-B",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "A-B-A design. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conduct a component analysis to determine the effective components of an intervention package",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as systematically comparing two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package.",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "A component analysis is used to systematically compare two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A component analysis compares how many different independent variables?",
                "correctAnswer": "2 or more",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "1",
                  "1 or more",
                  " 0"
                ],
                "explanation": "a component analysis is used to identify which component of the intervention is affecting the desired change. This is done by systematically comparing 2 or more different components of the intervention package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry created a treatment package to address inappropriate sexual behavior. These components included the following components: DRA, Punishment, and response blocking. What should Jerry do to determine which parts of his treatment package are effective?",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "a component analysis is used to identify which component of the intervention is affecting the desired change. This is done by systematically comparing 2 or more different components of the intervention package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010) "
              },
              {
                "question": "When making conclusions from a component analysis, it is important to consider the possibility that the effects of individual components of the treatment package are independent of each other. This effect is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Additive effects",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiplicative effects",
                  "Sequence effects",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is known as additive effects. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When making conclusions from a component analysis, it is important to consider the possibility that the effects of one component might depend on the presence of another. This effect is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiplicative effects",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Additive effects",
                  "Sequence effects",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is known as multiplicative effects. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When making conclusions from a component analysis, it is important to consider the possibility that the effects of one condition may carry over and influence behavior in subsequent conditions. This effect is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Sequence effects",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiplicative effects",
                  "Additive effects",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Sequence effects occur when one condition may carry over and influence behavior in subsequent conditions. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry is conducting a component analysis on his treatment package consisting of DRA, punishment, and response blocking. He is currently using all three components in his treatment, and systematically removes treatments to determine which components are not necessary for improved behavior. Which method is Jerry using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Dropout analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Sequence effects",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Jerry is using the dropout analysis method by systematically removing components to determine which is not necessary to use. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry is conducting a component analysis on his treatment package consisting of DRA, punishment, and response blocking. He hasn’t implemented this treatment yet, and begins by systematically testing one intervention at a time, and combining the treatments to determine their effect. Which method is Jerry using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Add-in analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dropout analysis",
                  "Sequence effects",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Jerry is using the add-in analysis by systematically adding components of the treatment to determine their effects. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry is implementing a token economy, and wants to know how much reinforcement he needs to provide to see the desired improved behavior. What analysis should Jerry conduct?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Jerry should conduct a parametric analysis. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable.",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "A parametric analysis is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conduct a parametric analysis to determine the effective values of an independent variable",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Amy  is implementing a token economy, and wants to know how much reinforcement he needs to provide to see the desired improved behavior. What analysis should Amy conduct?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Jerry should conduct a parametric analysis. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable.",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "A parametric analysis is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as systematically comparing two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package.",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "A component analysis is used to systematically compare two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Amy created a treatment package to address inappropriate sexual behavior. These components included the following components: DRA, Punishment, and response blocking. What should Amy do to determine which parts of his treatment package are effective?",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "a component analysis is used to identify which component of the intervention is affecting the desired change. This is done by systematically comparing 2 or more different components of the intervention package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010) "
              },
              {
                "question": "How many independent variables are under investigation when conducting a parametric analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "1",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 or more",
                  "3 or more",
                  "4 or more"
                ],
                "explanation": "Parametric analyses investigate only one independent variable."
              },
              {
                "question": "A component analysis compares how many different independent variables?",
                "correctAnswer": "2 or more",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "1",
                  "1 or more",
                  " 0"
                ],
                "explanation": "a component analysis is used to identify which component of the intervention is affecting the desired change. This is done by systematically comparing 2 or more different components of the intervention package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You’re client has made amazing progress! You want to determine if it was the reward component, the extinction procedure, or the response cost. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "A component analysis is used to systematically compare two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are implementing praise as a reinforcer, and want to know how frequently (or on what schedule) it would be most effective. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "A parametric analysis is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are determining if the progress your client has made is due to the level program, the praise delivered, or the nickels delivered as reinforcement. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Component analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parametric analysis",
                  "Reversal",
                  "Alternating treatments design"
                ],
                "explanation": "A component analysis is used to systematically compare two or more independent variables that comprise a treatment package. (Ward-Horner & Sturmey, 2010)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You want to determine how many tokens to remove during a response cost program for increased effectiveness. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parametric analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Add-in analysis",
                  "Dropout analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "A parametric analysis is defined as experimentally discovering the differential effects of a range of values of an independent variable. (Sy, Borrero, Zarcone, 2009)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Behavior-Change Considerations",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "State and plan for the possible unwanted effects of reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This principle of behavior occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Punishment",
                  "Negative Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This principle of behavior occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Punishment",
                  "Negative Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary’s mother reprimands Mary when she swears. Mary is more likely to swear later on, following the reprimand. This reprimand is functioning as a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcer",
                  "Positive punisher",
                  "Negative punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Although a reprimand is usually aversive, in this example, it is functioning as a positive reinforcer for Mary. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "An appetitive stimulus is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Sometimes a reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Always a reinforcer",
                  "Sometimes a punisher",
                  "Always a punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "An appetitive stimulus only SOMETIMES functions as a reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Reinforcement procedures fail to produce substantial results when:",
                "correctAnswer": "Initial criterion for reinforcement is not easily achieved",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High quality reinforcers are used",
                  "Varied reinforcers are used",
                  "Naturally occurring reinforcers are used"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement procedures are most effective when high quality and varied reinforcers are used, contrived reinforcers are shifted to naturally occurring reinforcers, and the initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Reinforcement procedures fail to produce substantial results when:",
                "correctAnswer": "Low quality reinforcers are used",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Varied reinforcers are used",
                  "Naturally occurring reinforcers are used",
                  "Initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved."
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement procedures are most effective when high quality and varied reinforcers are used, contrived reinforcers are shifted to naturally occurring reinforcers, and the initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Reinforcement procedures fail to produce substantial results when:",
                "correctAnswer": "The same reinforcer is repeatedly used",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Varied reinforcers are used",
                  "Naturally occurring reinforcers are used",
                  "Initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement procedures are most effective when high quality and varied reinforcers are used, contrived reinforcers are shifted to naturally occurring reinforcers, and the initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Reinforcement procedures fail to produce substantial results when:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contrived reinforcers are not shifted to naturally occurring reinforcers",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Varied reinforcers are used",
                  "Initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved",
                  "High quality reinforcers are used"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement procedures are most effective when high quality and varied reinforcers are used, contrived reinforcers are shifted to naturally occurring reinforcers, and the initial criterion for reinforcement is easily achieved. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What happens when the initial criterion for reinforcement is not easily achieved?",
                "correctAnswer": "The individual does not contact the contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It sets the standard high, to promote quicker learning",
                  "The learner will initially increase the frequency of the behavior rapidly, then progress will slow",
                  "The learner will initially increase the frequency of the behavior slowly, then progress will accelerate"
                ],
                "explanation": "The individual will not contact the contingency if the initial criterion is set too high. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When starting an intervention using reinforcement:",
                "correctAnswer": "Each occurrence of the behavior should be reinforced",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior should be reinforced intermittently",
                  "Use a low quality reinforcer",
                  "Use the same reinforcer during each session"
                ],
                "explanation": "When starting an intervention using reinforcement, every response should be reinforced. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "State and plan for the possible unwanted effects of punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when there is a stimulus change following a behavior, and then there is a decrease if the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a stimulus change, which produces a decrease in behavior when it immediately follows a response.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "A punisher is the stimulus change in a punishment procedure. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The discontinuing of reinforcement is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction is the discontinuing of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Negative side effects of punishment include:",
                "correctAnswer": "An increase in other undesirable behaviors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior change doesn’t occur with punishment alone",
                  "You may lose BCBA certification for ethical violations",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment may result in an increase in other undesirable behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Negative side effects of punishment include:",
                "correctAnswer": "Appropriate behaviors may decrease",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior change doesn’t occur with punishment alone",
                  "You may lose BCBA certification for ethical violations",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment may result in appropriate behaviors decreasing. If you reprimand a child for an incorrect answer, they may refuse to attempt to answer the next time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Negative side effects of punishment include:",
                "correctAnswer": "Emotional outbursts",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior change doesn’t occur with punishment alone",
                  "You may lose BCBA certification for ethical violations",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment may result in emotional outbursts. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Negative effects of punishment include:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishing is reinforcing for the instructor",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior change doesn’t occur with punishment alone",
                  "You may lose BCBA certification for ethical violations",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishing is reinforcing for the instructor. This may lead the instructor to implement punishment procedures in excess outside of the intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Negative effects of punishment include:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishing is reinforcing for the instructor",
                  "Emotional outbursts",
                  "Appropriate behaviors may decrease"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are possible concerns with punishment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To use punishment appropriately, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use the least restrictive intervention that can be effective",
                  "Use reinforcement interventions as well",
                  "Use a punisher with sufficient magnitude"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To use punishment appropriately, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Use reinforcement interventions as well",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use a mild punisher, then increase the magnitude if needed",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Use only punishment to ensure the intervention is run correctly"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement interventions should be used on conjunction with punishment procedures. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "State and plan for the possible unwanted effects of extinction",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The discontinuing of reinforcement is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction is the discontinuing of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During extinction, a behavior may decrease to the point that the behavior no longer occurs, then, seemingly out of nowhere, the behavior occurs. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Spontaneous recovery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Resistance to extinction",
                  "Intermittent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is known as spontaneous recovery. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During extinction, there is typically an immediate increase in the frequency of the response. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction burst",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Resistance to extinction",
                  "Intermittent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinct bursts occur when there is an immediate increase in the frequency of the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During extinction:",
                "correctAnswer": "The behavior should increase initially",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior should decrease slowly but steadily",
                  "The behavior should increase",
                  "The behavior should decrease initially"
                ],
                "explanation": "During extinction, behavior tends to increase initially (extinction burst). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When using extinction, the instructor should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Withhold reinforcement for all occurrences of the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Withhold reinforcement for most occurrences of the behavior",
                  "Withhold reinforcement until an extinction burst occurs",
                  "Withhold reinforcement until spontaneous recovery occurs"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement must be withheld for ALL occurrences of the behavior, or there is potential for reinforcing an extinction burst. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Delivering reinforcement during an extinction burst would likely:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increase the frequency of the behavior even more",
                  "Be worse than reinforcing initial occurrences of the behavior",
                  "Calm the individual down"
                ],
                "explanation": "Delivering reinforcement during an extinction burst would do all of the above. Although it calms the individual down, it will also reinforce an increased frequency and intensity of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Unwanted effects of extinction include:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Extinction-produced aggression"
                ],
                "explanation": "all of the answers above are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Unwanted effects of extinction include:",
                "correctAnswer": "Increased aggression",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The problem behavior decreases",
                  "Can be combined with other interventions",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction can lead to increased aggression from the learner. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When dealing with dangerous behaviors such as serious self-harm behavior:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction should not be used as a single intervention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction must occur for every occurrence of the behavior",
                  "Punishment must be used",
                  "Intermittent extinction may be used"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction should not be used as a single intervention for very dangerous behaviors. Extinction may be combined with punishment, reinforcement, and/or antecedent interventions for a safer intervention package. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Informing the individual about the extinction procedure at the beginning of the session:",
                "correctAnswer": "May help diminish behavior more rapidly",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Is not recommended",
                  "May increase the extinction burst",
                  "May lead to unintentional extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Informing the individual about the extinction procedure at the beginning of the session may help diminish behavior more rapidly. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Fundamental Elements of Behavior Change",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Use positive and negative reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This principle of behavior occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Punishment",
                  "Negative Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This principle of behavior occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Punishment",
                  "Negative Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This principle of behavior occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that decreases the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Reinforcement",
                  "Positive Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment is discussed in a different quiz, but occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary’s mother reprimands Mary when she swears. Mary is more likely to swear later on, following the reprimand. This reprimand is functioning as a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcer",
                  "Positive punisher",
                  "Negative punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Although a reprimand is usually aversive, in this example, it is functioning as a positive reinforcer for Mary. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary’s mother reprimands Mary when she swears. Mary is less likely to swear later on, following the reprimand. This reprimand is functioning as a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcer",
                  "Positive reinforcer",
                  "Negative punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment is discussed in a different quiz, but this is an example of a positive punisher. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007) "
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of contingency most often requires an aversive antecedent from which the learner will escape or avoid.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement typically requires an aversive stimulus from which the learner will escape or avoid. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jared cleans his room, and he gets $5. Jared is more likely to clean his room in the future. This is an example of: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jared’s mom reprimands at him for not cleaning his room. Jared cleans his room and his mom immediately stops yelling. Jared is more likely to clean his room in the future. This is an example of: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Not enough information"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Claire lives in a group home with staff supervision during the day. The staff give Claire a token (as part of a token economy) every time she brushes her teeth. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not enough information",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "We don’t know if brushing teeth increased in frequency following the token delivery. This is an attempt at positive reinforcement, but we don’t know the outcome. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The seat belt alarm is going off in Manuel’s car. He buckles his seatbelt and the noise turns of. Manuel is more likely to engage in this behavior in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the removal of a stimulus that increases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use appropriate parameters and schedules of reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This Compound  schedule of reinforcement occurs when 2 contingencies are operating simultaneously and independently for two or more behaviors. This schedule provides choice for the individual, and occurs frequently in the natural environment.",
                "correctAnswer": "Concurrent schedule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules "
                ],
                "explanation": "Concurrent schedules of reinforcement occur when 2 contingencies are operating simultaneously and independently for two or more behaviors. This schedule provides choice for the individual, and occurs frequently in the natural environment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement occurs when two or more schedules of reinforcement occur in an alternating, usually random sequence. A discriminative stimulus is correlated with each schedule. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules ",
                  "Tandem Schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "Multiple schedules of reinforcement occur when two or more schedules of reinforcement occur in an alternating, usually random sequence. A discriminative stimulus is correlated with each schedule. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement occurs when two or more schedules of reinforcement are occurring successively and in a specific order. There is a discriminative stimulus correlated with each schedule. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Chained schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mixed schedules ",
                  "Tandem Schedules",
                  "Multiple schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "Chained schedules occur when two or more schedules of reinforcement are occurring successively and in a specific order. There is a discriminative stimulus correlated with each schedule. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement is identical to a multiple schedule ,however there is no discriminative stimulus. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Mixed schedules ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tandem Schedules",
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Chained schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mixed schedules are identical to a multiple schedule ,however there is no discriminative stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement is identical to the chained schedule, but there are no discriminative stimuli with the elements in the chain. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Tandem Schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "Tandem schedules are identical to chained schedule, but there are no discriminative stimuli with the elements in the chain. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement provides reinforcement whenever the requirement of EITHER a ratio schedule or an interval schedule is met.",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternative Schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conjunctive Schedules",
                  "Concurrent Schedules",
                  "Fixed Interval Schedule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Alternative schedules occur when reinforcement is provided whenever the requirement of EITHER a ratio schedule or an interval schedule is met. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement provided reinforcement when the requirement of BOTH a ratio schedule and an interval schedule are met.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conjunctive schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Concurrent schedules",
                  "Fixed Interval schedule",
                  "Alternative schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conjunctive schedules of reinforcement occur when reinforcement is provided when the requirement of BOTH a ratio schedule and an interval schedule are met. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Intermittent  schedule of reinforcement provides reinforcement whenever the learner engages in an exact number of responses.",
                "correctAnswer": "Fixed Ratio",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed Interval",
                  "Variable Ratio",
                  "Variable Interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "A fixed ratio schedule provides reinforcement whenever the learner engages in an exact number of responses. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Intermittent schedule of reinforcement provides reinforcement whenever the learner engages in a number of responses that vary from trial to trial, but average to the specific number of responses. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Variable Ratio",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed Ratio",
                  "Variable Interval",
                  "Fixed Interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "Variable ratio schedule provides reinforcement whenever the learner engages in a number of responses that vary from trial to trial, but average to the specific number of responses. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Intermittent Schedule of reinforcement provides reinforcement after the first response following a specific duration of time.",
                "correctAnswer": "Fixed Interval",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Variable Interval",
                  "Fixed Ratio",
                  "Variable Ratio"
                ],
                "explanation": "Fixed interval schedule provides reinforcement after the first response following a specific duration of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use prompts and prompt fading",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” he places his hand on hers, moving her hand until she selects the correct card. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Full physical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model",
                  "Gestural"
                ],
                "explanation": "Full physical prompts include hand over hand manipulation to aid the learner to the correct answer."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” he places his hand on hers moving her hand until she is moving her hand in the correct direction, then he lets go. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial physical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Model",
                  "Gestural",
                  "Full physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial physical prompts include moving the learner’s body in the direction of the correct response."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” Alex touches the correct response, demonstrating the correct response. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Model",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Gestural",
                  "Full physical",
                  "Partial physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Modeling includes the instructor demonstrating the correct response for the learner."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” Alex points in the direction of the correct card. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Gestural",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Full physical",
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model"
                ],
                "explanation": "Gestural prompts include pointing or gesturing towards the next step of completing the task."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” The red card is slightly larger than the pink card. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Visual",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Verbal",
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model"
                ],
                "explanation": "Visual prompts involve creating brighter colored or larger stimuli to indicate the correct response."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. Alex says “Where is the red card? Lift your hand up and touch the card closer to you.” This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Verbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model",
                  "Visual"
                ],
                "explanation": "Verbal prompts include telling the learner the steps necessary to complete the task."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which prompt method would be used first when using most to least prompting?",
                "correctAnswer": "Full physical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Visual",
                  "Verbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "most to least prompting involves using the most intrusive prompt first and gradually fades to less intrusive prompts."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which prompt method would most likely be used first when using least to most prompting",
                "correctAnswer": "Visual",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Verbal",
                  "Partial physical ",
                  "Full physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Visual prompts are the least intrusive answer above. Least to most prompting is completed by giving the learner an opportunity to respond correctly prior to moving on to more intrusive prompting."
              },
              {
                "question": "Sam is asked to brush his teeth. The instructor immediately puts his hand on Sam’s and guides him through the first steps. Which prompting method is used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Most-to-least prompting",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Least-to-most prompting",
                  "Verbal",
                  "Visual"
                ],
                "explanation": "most to least prompting involves using the most intrusive prompt first and gradually fades to less intrusive prompts."
              },
              {
                "question": "Sam is asked to brush his teeth. Sam doesn’t respond after 3 seconds so the instructor says “grab the toothpaste”. Which prompting method is likely being used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Least-to-most",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Most-to-least",
                  "Physical",
                  "Partial physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Least to most prompting is completed by giving the learner an opportunity to respond correctly prior to moving on to more intrusive prompting."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use modeling and imitation training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Modeling is a great teaching strategy, but requires the learner to have which skill prior to being effective?",
                "correctAnswer": "Both of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Imitative skills",
                  "Attending skills",
                  "None of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to modeling being effective, the learner must possess imitative skills. Attending is a prerequisite to imitating, so both skills are necessary."
              },
              {
                "question": "In modeling, how can you tell if there is a controlling relation between the learner and the model?",
                "correctAnswer": "If the learner engages in novel behaviors that have not been reinforced in the known history, following the model’s behavior.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "If the Model engages in novel behaviors that have not been reinforced in the known history, following the learner’s behavior.",
                  "If the learner engages in novel behaviors, different from those behaviors being modeled.",
                  "If the Model engages in novel behaviors, different from those behaviors being modeled. "
                ],
                "explanation": "There is a controlling relation when the learner engages in novel behaviors that have not been reinforced in the known history, following the model’s behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT an example of a controlling relation with modeling?",
                "correctAnswer": "Amy throws a ball to Paul, who throws the ball back to Amy. They play catch often.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Amy throws a ball to Paul, who throws the ball back to Amy. Paul had never thrown a ball before.",
                  "Both of the above.",
                  "None of the above."
                ],
                "explanation": "There is a controlling relation when the learner engages in novel behaviors that have not been reinforced in the known history, following the model’s behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to conducting imitation training, the learner should already possess which skill?",
                "correctAnswer": "Attending",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Modeling",
                  "Intrinsic motivation",
                  "Reading"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to conducting imitation training, the learner should already be able to attend to the instructor. If not, attending should be trained first."
              },
              {
                "question": "While starting imitation training, the instructor should reinforce: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Both prompted and imitative responses",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Only prompted responses",
                  "Only imitative responses",
                  "Any response that is correct or incorrect"
                ],
                "explanation": "While starting imitation training, the instructor should reinforce both prompted and imitative responses."
              },
              {
                "question": "Jane is just starting to conduct imitation training with Fred. Jane says “do this” as she touches her head. Fred doesn’t respond. What should Jane do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver a prompt so Fred responds correctly, then deliver a reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Move on to a different question",
                  "Keep asking until he responds correctly",
                  "Deliver a reinforcer "
                ],
                "explanation": "When an individual does not respond correctly, the instructor should prompt the individual so they respond correctly, then deliver a reinforcer."
              },
              {
                "question": "Jane is just starting to conduct imitation training with Fred. Jane says “do this” as she touches her head. Fred touches his belly.  What should Jane do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver a prompt so Fred responds correctly, then deliver a reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Move on to a different question",
                  "Keep asking until he responds correctly",
                  "Deliver a reinforcer "
                ],
                "explanation": "When an individual does not respond correctly, the instructor should prompt the individual so they respond correctly, then deliver a reinforcer."
              },
              {
                "question": "Jane is just starting to conduct imitation training with Fred. Jane says “do this” as she touches her head. Fred touches his head.  What should Jane do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver a reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver a prompt so Fred responds correctly, then deliver a reinforcer",
                  "Move on to a different question",
                  "Keep asking until he responds correctly"
                ],
                "explanation": "When an individual responds correctly, they should be reinforced."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mandy is conducting imitation training. Praise is not reinforcing for the learner at this time, but small edibles are. Mandy should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Use small edibles as reinforcement ALWAYS paired with praise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use small edibles as reinforcement SOMETIMES paired with praise",
                  "Use praise anyways, until it’s reinforcing",
                  "Use only small edibles."
                ],
                "explanation": "Tangible items may be used as reinforcement, however they should always be paired with praise, so praise can be established as a reinforcer."
              },
              {
                "question": "Training sessions for imitation training should be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Active and brief",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Active and long",
                  "Calm and brief",
                  "Calm and long"
                ],
                "explanation": "Training sessions for imitation training should be active and brief. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use Shaping",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Shaping is defined as",
                "correctAnswer": "Systematically and differentially reinforcing successive approximations to a terminal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing appropriate behavior",
                  "Reinforcement is provided for correct responses and withheld for incorrect responses",
                  "A stimulus whose presentation functions as reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Shaping is defined as systematically and differentially reinforcing successive approximations to a terminal behavior"
              },
              {
                "question": "Differential reinforcement is defined as ",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement is provided for correct responses and withheld for incorrect responses",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A stimulus whose presentation functions as reinforcement",
                  "Systematically and differentially reinforcing successive approximations to a terminal behavior",
                  "Increasing appropriate behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement is defined as reinforcement is provided for correct responses and withheld for incorrect responses"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior can be shaped in terms of",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency",
                  "Topography",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior can be shaped in terms of frequency, topography, duration, latency, or intensity. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Danny plays the cello. His mother wants him to increase the amount of time he practices the cello each day. He is currently practicing 20 minutes per day, on average. Using differential reinforcement how might the mother shape this behavior to increase his average time to 30 minutes per day?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforce only practices that go longer than 20 minutes, gradually changing the criteria as the average lengthens.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforce only practices that go 30 minutes or longer.",
                  "Reinforce practices that go longer than 15 minutes, gradually changing the criteria as the average lengthens.",
                  "Timing is optional. Reinforce any practice that feels longer than typical practices."
                ],
                "explanation": "The mother should reinforce only practices that go longer than 20 minutes, gradually changing the criteria as the average lengthens."
              },
              {
                "question": "Danny plays the cello. His mother wants him to increase the amount of time he practices the cello each day. Which dimension of behavior should be shaped?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Topography",
                  "Frequency",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is being shaped."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not a limitation of shaping?",
                "correctAnswer": "Shaping can change a variety of dimensions of behavior including duration, latency, and frequency.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Shaping can be time consuming",
                  "Shaping requires constant observation ",
                  "Progress is not always linear across criteria"
                ],
                "explanation": "Some limitations of shaping include that it is often time consuming, requires constant supervision, and progress is not always linear across criteria."
              },
              {
                "question": "John used to require hand over hand prompting to brush his teeth, but now only requires visual prompts. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Prompt fading",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus fading",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of prompt fading."
              },
              {
                "question": "John used to yell at loud volumes to get his mother’s attention. Using differential reinforcement, John now speaks in a soft voice as he’s requesting attention. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Shaping",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus fading",
                  "Prompt fading",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of shaping"
              },
              {
                "question": "John yells at loud volumes to get his mother’s attention. His mother reinforces close approximations to low volumes and ignores loud volumes. The process of reinforcing appropriate responses and not reinforcing inappropriate responses is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Shaping",
                  "Stimulus fading",
                  "Prompt fading"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of differential reinforcement."
              },
              {
                "question": "John wants to start eating healthier foods. He currently eats only foods with high amounts of sugar. He wants to have a more balanced diet with high amounts of nutrients. Changing this behavior would be shaping across which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Topography",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Duration",
                  "Frequency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Cooking and eating different foods changes the topography of the behavior."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use chaining",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is a behavior chain?",
                "correctAnswer": "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement",
                  "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior chains are a specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is Chaining?",
                "correctAnswer": "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement",
                  "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units.",
                  "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Chaining includes various methods used for linking specific sequences together. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses involve breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to using chaining, a ______must be completed.",
                "correctAnswer": "Task Analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Chaining",
                  "Behavior chain",
                  "Total task chaining"
                ],
                "explanation": "A task analysis is completed prior to chaining. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is learning to tie her shoes. The BCBA conducted a task analysis and is focusing on 8 smaller steps from “1. Placing on string in each hand” to “8. Pull the loops away from each other”. Mary is reinforced for correctly completing the first step. She then completes the first step and the second step and is reinforced after correctly completing both steps. What type of chaining is being used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Forward Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Backward Chaining",
                  "Total Task Chaining",
                  "Task Analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Forward chaining is completed by  reinforcing accurate responding of the first step. Then, progressing with the chaining, the learner must complete the first steps previously learned AND the new step to receive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is learning to tie her shoes. The BCBA conducted a task analysis and is focusing on 8 smaller steps from “1. Placing on string in each hand” to “8. Pull the loops away from each other”. The BCBA teaches each step during every session, providing prompts for correct responding, and reinforcement after correct responding.",
                "correctAnswer": "Total Task Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Forward Chaining",
                  "Backward Chaining"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total task chaining is completed by providing training for every step during every session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is learning to tie her shoes. The BCBA conducted a task analysis and is focusing on 8 smaller steps from “1. Placing on string in each hand” to “8. Pull the loops away from each other”. The BCBA completes the first 7 steps for Mary, and then provides prompting so Mary completes the last step correctly. The BCBA then provides reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Backward Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Total Task Chaining",
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Forward Chaining"
                ],
                "explanation": "Backward chaining is conducted by completing each step for the learner until the last step. Once the learner can correctly complete the last step, the instructor completes all steps except the last two steps. This process continues, providing reinforcement for correct responses, until all steps are mastered. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucas is learning to take a shower. 10 steps are broken down from turning the water on to an appropriate temperature, to drying the body with a towel. The BCBA begins working with Lucas by starting with turning the water on. During the first session she goes through each step of showering, providing prompts and reinforcement along the way. Which method of chaining is being used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Total Task Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Forward Chaining",
                  "Backward Chaining"
                ],
                "explanation": "Total task chaining is completed by providing training for every step during every session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucas is learning to take a shower. 10 steps are broken down from turning the water on to an appropriate temperature, to drying the body with a towel. The BCBA begins working with Lucas by starting with turning the water on. After correctly completing the first step independently (after several sessions), Lucas is required to complete the first AND the second step before receiving reinforcement Which method of chaining is being used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Forward Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Backward Chaining",
                  "Total Task Chaining",
                  "Task Analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Forward chaining is completed by  reinforcing accurate responding of the first step. Then, progressing with the chaining, the learner must complete the first steps previously learned AND the new step to receive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucas is learning to take a shower. 10 steps are broken down from turning the water on to an appropriate temperature, to drying the body with a towel. The BCBA begins working with Lucas by completing the first 9 steps of showering for Lucas. Then teaches Lucas how to correctly dry off with the towel and provides reinforcement for correct responding. Which method of chaining is being used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Backward Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Total Task Chaining",
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Forward Chaining"
                ],
                "explanation": "Backward chaining is conducted by completing each step for the learner until the last step. Once the learner can correctly complete the last step, the instructor completes all steps except the last two steps. This process continues, providing reinforcement for correct responses, until all steps are mastered. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conduct Task Analyses",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses involve breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a behavior chain?",
                "correctAnswer": "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement",
                  "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior chains are a specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following tasks would be most important to break up into smaller steps using a task analysis if it were to be taught to novice learner?",
                "correctAnswer": "Brushing teeth",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Open Container",
                  "Place clothes in the washer"
                ],
                "explanation": "task analyses are used to break up behaviors composed of multiple steps. Single step tasks would not usually need to be broken up further. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following tasks would be most important to break up into smaller steps using a task analysis if it were to be taught to novice learner?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Using dinner utensils",
                  "Doing a cartwheel",
                  "Asking someone on a date"
                ],
                "explanation": "task analyses are used to break up behaviors composed of multiple steps. Single step tasks would not usually need to be broken up further. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which is a research based method of developing a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Observing a competent performer",
                  "Consulting with an expert on the skill",
                  "Perform the behaviors oneself "
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses can be developed by observing a competent performer, consulting with an expert on the skill, or by performing the behaviors oneself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If you were to conduct a task analysis on putting on pants, which might be the first step outlined in the task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Select one pair of pants from the bottom drawer the dresser",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver one reinforcer as soon as the individual correctly puts their pants on",
                  "Select one pair of pants from the dresser and step in to the pants",
                  "Prompt the individual to put pants on. "
                ],
                "explanation": "The first step of a task analysis should be the first basic task necessary for the individual to complete. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units” is the definition of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Task Analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior Chain",
                  "Chaining",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses involve breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement” is the definition of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior Chain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Chaining",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior chains are a specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When teaching a new skill to an individual, what can be done only after completing a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior Chain",
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Chaining can be completed only after a task analysis. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a behavior chain, conditioned reinforcement for the first step, should also be the ______ for the next step.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "MO",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "In a behavior chain, condition reinforcement for the first step, should also be the SD for the next step. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use discrete-trial and free-operant arrangements",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the learner is given repeated contrived opportunities to emit the response.",
                "correctAnswer": "Discrete-trial",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free-operant procedure",
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Discrete-trials occur when the learner is given repeated contrived opportunities to emit the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs in the natural setting, and the instructor looks out for natural learning opportunities. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Free-operant procedure",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                  "Discrete-trial"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free-operant procedures occur in the natural setting, and the instructor looks out for natural learning opportunities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which measure would not be appropriate to use during discrete-trials?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Percentage Correct",
                  "All of these would be appropriate measures"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is not an appropriate measure for most discrete trials, because the responses occur in a contrived situation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Martha is learning how to read. An RBT is working with her using flashcards. Martha is most likely participating in:",
                "correctAnswer": "Discrete trials",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free-operant procedures",
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "Martha is most likely participating in discrete trials. Using flashcards is creating contrived contingencies for learning. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Martha is trying to lose weight. She is focusing on increasing exercise and decreasing caloric intake. She is tracking her calories, and her friend is providing reinforcement each day in the form of attention for following her plan. Martha is most likely participating in:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free-operant procedures",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Discrete trials",
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free-operant procedures occur in the natural setting, and the instructor looks out for natural learning opportunities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Discrete trials should be conducted by:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trained parents",
                  "RBTs",
                  "BCBA’s"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above can effectively implement discrete trials, even parents! (Lafasakis & Sturmey, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Luke is helping his student learn her colors. Luke presents a red card and a yellow card and says “touch the red card”. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Discrete trials",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free-operant procedures",
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "Discrete-trials occur when the learner is given repeated contrived opportunities to emit the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Martha earns a high five every time she independently makes her bed in the morning. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free-operant procedures",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Discrete trials",
                  "Mand training",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free-operant procedures occur in the natural setting, and the instructor looks out for natural learning opportunities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor may provide reinforcement for appropriate/correct responses during this procedure:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free-operant procedures",
                  "Discrete trials",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "delivering reinforcement for appropriate responses occurs in essentially every behavioral intervention whether it is a free operant procedure or a discrete trial. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Differential reinforcement may be used in:",
                "correctAnswer": "Both free operant procedures AND discrete trials",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Discrete trials only",
                  "Free operant procedures only",
                  "Neither discrete trials nor free operant procedures."
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement can be used in both free operant procedures as well as discrete trials. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use the verbal operants as a basis for language assessment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Tact is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and the verbal operant have point to point correspondence and formal similarity. It results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The echoic is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and the verbal operant have point to point correspondence and formal similarity. It results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant occurs when a speaker’s own verbal behavior functions as an SD or an MO for additional speaker verbal behavior. The speaker is the listener and observer. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Autoclitic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The autoclitic occurs when a speaker’s own verbal behavior functions as an SD or an MO for additional speaker verbal behavior. The speaker is the listener and observer. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant has point to point correspondence, but not formal similarity between the stimulus and response. It occurs when upon seeing a written word, the speaker “reads” the word. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Textual",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Transcription",
                  "Autoclitic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The textual operant has point to point correspondence, but not formal similarity between the stimulus and response. It occurs when upon seeing a written word, the speaker “reads” the word. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant has point to point correspondence, but not formal similarity between the stimulus and response. It occurs when the speaker hears a spoken word and then produces a written word. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Transcription",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Textual",
                  "Mand",
                  "Autoclitic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The transcription operant has point to point correspondence, but not formal similarity between the stimulus and response. It occurs when the speaker hears a spoken word and then produces a written word. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A young boy is tired and says “bed”. His mother puts him down for a nap. “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A young boy sees a bed and says “bed”. His mother responds by saying “That is a bed, good job!” “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Tact is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A mother asks her son “where do you go to sleep?” The boy responds with “bed”. “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Textual",
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use echoic training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and the verbal operant have point to point correspondence and formal similarity. It results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The echoic is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and the verbal operant have point to point correspondence and formal similarity. It results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A mother asks her son “where do you go to sleep?” The boy responds with “bed”. “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Textual",
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A mother says “bed”, her son replies “bed”.  “bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact"
                ],
                "explanation": "The echoic is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and the verbal operant have point to point correspondence and formal similarity. It results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is echoic training important?",
                "correctAnswer": "The ability to repeat words when asked to do so plays a major role in learning other verbal operants",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "So the individual can request items when and where the individual pleases",
                  "Tantrums will be avoided if a child can echo behavior",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic training because the ability to repeat words when asked to do so plays a major role in learning other verbal operants. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Andrew just started conducting echoic training with a young child. Andrew says “Ball”, and the child repeats back “Bubu”. This is the closest the child has come to saying ball. Andrew should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide praise or other generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Repeat the word “Ball” so the child will try again",
                  "Don’t respond until the child says “ball” more clearly",
                  "Deliver feedback. Say something like “Bubu” was pretty close, but I need you to say it more clearly like “Baaalllll”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic training uses shaping. Shaping takes place by reinforcing successive aproximations of the behavior. “bubu” is pretty close. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Andrew just started conducting echoic training with a young child. Andrew says “Ball”, and the child repeats back “Bubu”. The child is able to say “ball”, but did not do so during this opportunity. Andrew should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Repeat the word “Ball” so the child will try again",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide praise or other generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Don’t respond until the child says “ball” more clearly",
                  "Deliver feedback. Say something like “Bubu” was pretty close, but I need you to say it more clearly like “Baaalllll”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic training uses shaping. Shaping takes place by reinforcing successive aproximations of the behavior. If the child has recently said “ball”, “bubu” should not be accepted as a correct response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Shaping is defined as",
                "correctAnswer": "Systematically and differentially reinforcing successive approximations to a terminal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing appropriate behavior",
                  "Reinforcement is provided for correct responses and withheld for incorrect responses",
                  "A stimulus whose presentation functions as reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Shaping is defined as systematically and differentially reinforcing successive approximations to a terminal behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Josh just began conducting echoic training with a child. The child rarely emits vocal responses of any sort. When josh says a word for the child to repeat, he typically just sits there non-responsive to the prompt. What can Josh do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforce any vocalization that occurs, even if it doesn’t resemble the word at this time. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Wait until the child repeats the word to provide reinforcement",
                  "Deliver feedback to the child saying “you need to repeat what I’m saying”.",
                  "Continue to repeat the word until the child says the word. "
                ],
                "explanation": "If a child is not vocalizing very much, their opportunity for reinforcement is low. Reinforcing all occurrences of vocalization, starting out, is an appropriate direction to go. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Susan is working with a child helping him engage in echoic responses. Susan says “Train” and the child says “train”. The child has already said “train” in the past. Susan should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide praise or other generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Repeat the word “train” so the child will try again",
                  "Don’t respond until the child says “train” more clearly",
                  "Do not provide praise and move on to the next word."
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic training uses shaping. Shaping takes place by reinforcing successive aproximations of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use mand training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Tact is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is learning the mand so important for early development?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To prevent tantrums and other inappropriate behavior",
                  "So the learner can get what he wants, when he wants it",
                  "To establish a child’s role as a speaker, rather than just a listener"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are important reason to learn the mand in early development. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What must be present before conducting mand training?",
                "correctAnswer": "The relevant MO must be strong and present",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Edible reinforcers",
                  "Nonverbal SD’s must be present",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "The relevant MO must be strong and present for mand training to be effective. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following would probably NOT be a good item to use as reinforcement for mand training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Chores",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Food",
                  "Toys",
                  "Videos"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is important to select mands that have a powerful MO for the child. Chores, generally, would not be included. Every child is different so this will change based on the idiosyncrasies of the child. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During mand training, a child reaches for a pretzel.  The BCBA grabs the pretzel and says “pretzel”. The child repeats the word and says “pretzel”. What should the BCBA use as reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "The pretzel",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Praise",
                  "The child’s highest preferred edible",
                  "It depends on the result  of the preference assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "During mand training, the reinforcement should always be the specific item being asked for. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joey loves candy. Right after lunch, you have a bowl of Joey’s favorite candy and are ready to start mand training. Joey is watching Batman on TV (his favorite show) and isn’t showing interest in the candy. You should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Use the TV show as the focus of mand training.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Sit there and wait until he is interested in candy.",
                  "Use the candy ",
                  "Turn off the TV so the child can focus on the candy"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mand training can only be effective if there is a powerful MO in place. If the child isn’t hungry, changing the mand training to focus on another interest would be best. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During mand training, which responses are appropriate:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pictures",
                  "Vocal words",
                  "Written words"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above can be used as response forms for mands, however vocal words are most common. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During mand training, a child reaches for the TV remote to watch his show.  The BCBA grabs the remote and says “batman”. The child repeats the word and says “batman”. What should the BCBA use as reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Turning on Batman on TV",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Praise",
                  "Edible",
                  "Depends on the result of the preference assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "During mand training, the reinforcement should always be the specific item being asked for. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are teaching the word “pretzels” during mand training. The child is no longer showing interest in pretzels but is reaching for your water bottle. You should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Have him say “water”, and give him water",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Give him some water, then continue on with pretzels after he isn’t thirsty",
                  "Remove the water bottle, as it’s a distraction",
                  "Continue to use pretzels as the focus of the training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mand training can only be effective if there is a powerful MO in place. If the child isn’t hungry, changing the mand training to focus on another interest would be best. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use tact training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Tact is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Philip knows how to mand, but has no echoic or tact skills. Which type of tact training might benefit Philip? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand to tact training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact to mand training",
                  "Echoic to tact training",
                  "Tact to echoic training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mand to tact training takes place when the learner is able to mand and not able to tact. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Philip uses echoic operants, but does not have a history with tacts or mands. To train Philip on mands, which type of training would be best?",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic to tact training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand to tact training",
                  "Tact to mand training",
                  "Tact to echoic training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic to tact training would be useful if the individual has echoic abilities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When the child is hungry, Nathan presents a treat. The child says “treat”. Nathan delivers the treat AND praise. Nathan then fades the MO of hunger and the treat as reinforcement in following sessions. What tact training procedure is Nathan implementing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand to tact training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact to mand training",
                  "Echoic to tact training",
                  "Tact to echoic training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mand to tact training takes place when the learner is able to mand and not able to tact. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Nathan presents a toy tractor and says “What is this? Tractor”. The child says “Tractor”. Nathan delivers praise. Nathan then is able to present the tractor and says “What is this?” The child responds with “Tractor”. Nathan delivers praise once again. Next, Nathan simply presents the tractor, and the child says “Tractor”. This is an example of which kind of tact training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic to tact training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand to tact training",
                  "Tact to mand training",
                  "Tact to echoic training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic to tact training would be useful if the individual has echoic abilities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A young boy sees a bed and says “bed”. His mother responds by saying “That is a bed, good job!” “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Tact is under the functional control of a nonverbal SD and results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A young boy is tired and says “bed”. His mother puts him down for a nap. “Bed” in this example is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What should be the SD for a boy to tact “Airplane”? ",
                "correctAnswer": "The airplane",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The  written word “Airplane”",
                  "The vocal word “airplane” spoken by another person",
                  "The vocal word “airplane” spoken by the speaker himself. "
                ],
                "explanation": "The SD for a tact should be the item itself. In this example it is the airplane. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If a boy says “airplane” as a tact. What should reinforce this behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized Conditioned Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The toy airplane he is asking for",
                  "An edible",
                  "Nothing. The boy should be intrinsically motivated to tact without the need for reinforcement."
                ],
                "explanation": "Tacts result in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use intraverbal training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following verbal operants is typically most challenging to learn for individuals with developmental disabilities?",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Mand",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intraverbal repertoires are typically the most challenging for individuals with developmental disabilities to learn. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This verbal operant occurs when a speaker’s own verbal behavior functions as an SD or an MO for additional speaker verbal behavior. The speaker is the listener and observer. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Autoclitic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The autoclitic occurs when a speaker’s own verbal behavior functions as an SD or an MO for additional speaker verbal behavior. The speaker is the listener and observer. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA says “what time do you go to sleep?” The child responds “8” This is an example of which verbal operant?",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Textual",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intraverbal is under the functional control of a verbal SD. The SD and verbal operant do not have point-to-point correspondence. This operant results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The mother says “it’s 8pm, it’s time to go to sleep!” The child goes into bed. The mother’s verbal behavior is an example of which verbal operant?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Textual"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to conducting intraverbal training, the child should have a substantial repertoire of which behaviors?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to conducting intraverbal training, the child should have a substantial repertoire of mand, tact, echoic, imitation, receptive, and matching to sample. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to conducting intraverbal training, the child should have a substantial repertoire of which behaviors:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Imitation",
                  "Receptive",
                  "Matching to sample"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to conducting intraverbal training, the child should have a substantial repertoire of mand, tact, echoic, imitation, receptive, and matching to sample. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Early intraverbal training should teach simple responses, such as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Fill in the blank songs “twinkle twinkle little ______”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "What is your name?",
                  "Where do you live?",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "one of the most common mistakes made with early intraverbal training is starting with too complex of responses. Fill in the blank songs and activities is a good place to start. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jonah is thirsty. The BCBA just started conducting mand to intraverbal training. The BCBA says “You drink_____” and shows Jonah a water bottle.  Jonah says “water”. What reinforcer should be provided?",
                "correctAnswer": "Water",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Edible",
                  "Praise",
                  "None"
                ],
                "explanation": "In intraverbal training, it can be good to start with a mand to condition the verbal stimulus (e.g., “you drink____”) as the SD. The reinforcement should start out with the specific item until the verbal stimulus has been conditioned as the SD. Then Praise, or other GCR should be provided. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While conducting intraverbal training, Jonah is not thirsty, but has reliably filled in the blank correctly to “you drink_____”. The BCBA says “you drink____” and Jonah replies “water”. What reinforcer should be provided?",
                "correctAnswer": "Praise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Water",
                  "Edible",
                  "None"
                ],
                "explanation": "In intraverbal training, it can be good to start with a mand to condition the verbal stimulus (e.g., “you drink____”) as the SD. The reinforcement should start out with the specific item until the verbal stimulus has been conditioned as the SD. Then Praise, or other GCR should be provided. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use listener training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be considered expressive language skills?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand, tact and echoic are all examples of expressive language skills. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be considered receptive language skills?",
                "correctAnswer": "Listener responding",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "listener responding is a form of receptive language, where the listener emits motor responses to verbal stimuli. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A boy says “water” and his mother brings him some water. The boy’s behavior, is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tact",
                  "Listener responding",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of behavior occurs when the listener emits motor responses to verbal stimuli:",
                "correctAnswer": "Listener responding",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "listener responding is a form of receptive language, where the listener emits motor responses to verbal stimuli. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A boy says “water” and his mother brings him some water. The mother’s behavior, is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Listener responding",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "listener responding is a form of receptive language, where the listener emits motor responses to verbal stimuli. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": "At dinner, Danny says “pass the salt, please”. His sister then passes the salt. Danny says “Thank you.” In this example, “Pass the salt” is an example of what?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Listener responding",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Autoclitic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is under control of motivating operations and results in specific reinforcement. (Skinner, 1957)"
              },
              {
                "question": "At dinner, Danny says “pass the salt, please”. His sister then passes the salt. Danny says “Thank you.” In this example, the sister’s behavior is an example of what?",
                "correctAnswer": "Listener responding",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "listener responding is a form of receptive language, where the listener emits motor responses to verbal stimuli. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": "At dinner, Danny says “pass the salt, please”. His sister then passes the salt. Danny says “Thank you.” In this example, “thank you” is an example of what?",
                "correctAnswer": "Potential reinforcement for listener responding",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Listener responding"
                ],
                "explanation": "Listener responding is generally reinforced by generalized conditioned reinforcement such as praise. (Petursdottir, Carr, Lechago, & Almason, 2008)"
              },
              {
                "question": " Mary is conducting discrete trials with a young child. She is using errorless learning (least to most prompting) to teach receptive language skills (listener responding). Mary says “fold your arms”, and the child complies. Mary should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide praise, or other GCR",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Attempt a more challenging task",
                  "Wait for the child to vocalize that the task is complete",
                  "Implement a full physical prompt. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Praise or other GCR is used to reinforce listener responding during listener training."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is conducting discrete trials with a young child. She is using errorless learning (least to most prompting) to teach receptive language skills (listener responding). Mary says “fold your arms”, and the child doesn’t move. Mary should:",
                "correctAnswer": "model the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "use a partial physical prompt",
                  "use a full physical prompt",
                  "Provide praise, or other GCR"
                ],
                "explanation": "least to most prompting suggests that the least intrusive prompt (modeling) should be attempted prior to moving on to more intrusive prompts."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Identify punishers",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when there is a stimulus change following a behavior, and then there is a decrease if the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a stimulus change, which produces a decrease in behavior when it immediately follows a response.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "A punisher is the stimulus change in a punishment procedure. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is an unpleasant or noxious stimulus.",
                "correctAnswer": "Aversive stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punisher",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "An aversive stimulus is an unpleasant or noxious stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a stimulus whose presentation functions as punishment without any learning history",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned punisher is a stimulus whose presentation functions as punishment without any learning history. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a stimulus whose presentation function as punishment, as a result of a person’s learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned punisher is a stimulus whose presentation functions as punishment as a result of a person’s learning history. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a stimulus change that has been paired with numerous forms of unconditioned and conditioned punishers. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Generalized conditioned punisher is a stimulus change that has been paired with numerous forms of unconditioned and conditioned punishers. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary spanks her child for hitting. There is a decrease in hitting behavior in the future. Spanking, in this example, is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "A punisher is the stimulus change in a punishment procedure. Since there was a decrease in behavior, we know that punishment occurred. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary spanks her child for hitting. There is an increase in hitting behavior in the future. Spanking, in this example, is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Despite pain being an aversive stimulus, there was an INCREASE in hitting in the future. This indicates that spanking functioned as a reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is reprimanded for spitting. There was a decrease in problem behavior following the reprimand. What procedure took place in this example?",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punisher",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is reprimanded for spitting. There was an increase in problem behavior following the reprimand. What procedure took place in this example?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punisher",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. Since there was an increase in spitting, this was an example of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use positive and negative punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the presentation of a stimulus following a behavior results in a decrease in the frequency of the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive punishment occurs when the presentation of a stimulus results in a decrease in the frequency of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the termination of a stimulus following a behavior, results in a decrease in the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative punishment occurs when the termination of a stimulus following a behavior, results in a decrease in the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry’s child is cursing. Jerry turns off the TV and delivers a verbal reprimand. There is a decrease in cursing. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive and negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Not enough information"
                ],
                "explanation": "There was a decrease in cursing. This was an example of punishment. There was a removal of stimulus (TV off) and a presentation of stimulus (reprimand), so this is both positive and negative punishment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry’s child is cursing. Jerry turns off the TV and delivers a verbal reprimand. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not enough information",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive and negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "This example doesn’t state if there was a decrease in cursing. We don’t know if punishment occurred. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry’s child is cursing. Jerry turns off the TV and there is a decrease in future cursing. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive and negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Not enough information"
                ],
                "explanation": "There was a decrease in cursing. This was an example of punishment. There was a removal of stimulus (TV off) which indicates this was negative punishment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry’s child is cursing. Jerry delivers a verbal reprimand. There is a decrease in cursing. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Not enough information",
                  "Positive and negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "There was a decrease in cursing. This was an example of punishment. There was a presentation of stimulus (reprimand), so this is positive punishment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry’s child curses when Jerry is not there, but when Jerry is there no cursing occurs. Jerry appears to be a:",
                "correctAnswer": "SDP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "Punisher",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "SDP stands for “Discriminative stimulus for punishment”. Jerry appears to be an SDP. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Rachel is an RBT working with an adolescent boy who engages in boundary violations. Which of the following is an example of a positive punishment procedure that Rachel could implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingent exercise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response cost program",
                  "Ignore the behavior",
                  "Remain Neutral"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingent exercise involves requiring the individual to do exercise as punishment for a specific behavior. This is an example of positive punishment because requiring exercise is a presentation of a stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": " Rachel is an RBT working with an adolescent boy who engages in boundary violations. Which of the following is an example of a negative punishment procedure that Rachel could implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Response cost program",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ignore the behavior",
                  "Remain Neutral",
                  "Contingent exercise"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response cost programs as part of a token economy is an example of negative punishment because it removes the stimulus as punishment for the specific behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when there is a stimulus change following a behavior, and then there is a decrease if the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Aversive stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use appropriate parameters and schedules of punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Start with punishment of sufficient magnitude",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use only one punisher",
                  "Punish only some occurrences of the behavior",
                  "Wait to punish until the end of the behavior chain"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punish every occurrence of the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Start with low intensity punishment first, and gradually increase if necessary",
                  "Wait to punish until the end of the behavior chain",
                  "Use only one punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Use varied punishers",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Start with low intensity punishment first, and gradually increase if necessary",
                  "Wait to punish until the end of the behavior chain",
                  "Punish only some occurrences of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure it is important to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver the punisher as soon as the behavior chain begins",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punish only some occurrences of the behavior",
                  "Start with low intensity punishment first, and gradually increase if necessary",
                  "Use only one punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, DO NOT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Start with low intensity punishment first, and gradually increase if necessary",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver the punisher as soon as the behavior chain begins",
                  "Use varied punishers",
                  "Punish every occurrence of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, DO NOT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Use only one punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver the punisher as soon as the behavior chain begins",
                  "Punish every occurrence of the behavior",
                  "Start with punishment of sufficient magnitude"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, DO NOT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Wait to punish until the end of the behavior chain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use varied punishers",
                  "Punish every occurrence of the behavior",
                  "Start with punishment of sufficient magnitude"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, DO NOT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punish only some occurrences of the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver the punisher as soon as the behavior chain begins",
                  "Use varied punishers",
                  "Start with punishment of sufficient magnitude"
                ],
                "explanation": "When implementing a new punishment procedure, it is important to start with punishment of sufficient magnitude, punish every occurrence of the behavior, use varied punishers, and deliver the punisher as soon as the chain begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior analysts should:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Not shy away from punishment",
                  "Consider reinforcement before using punishment",
                  "Minimize any risk of harm while using punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts should not shy away from punishment, consider reinforcement before using punishment, and minimize any risk of harm while using punishment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When using punishment, behavior analysts should",
                "correctAnswer": "Use other interventions such as differential reinforcement.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Start with low intensity punishment first, and gradually increase if necessary",
                  "Wait to punish until the end of the behavior chain",
                  "Use only one punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment is typically not implemented without other interventions in place such as differential reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use extinction",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The discontinuing of reinforcement is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction is the discontinuing of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“Reinforcing ONLY those responses that meet a specific criteria and withholding reinforcement from those responses that do not meet the criteria” is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement is reinforcing ONLY those responses that meet a specific criteria and withholding reinforcement from those responses that do not meet the criteria. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Extinction occurs when:",
                "correctAnswer": "All reinforcement is withheld for the behavior of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "There is a decrease in behavior",
                  "The individual forgets prior learning history",
                  "Appetitive stimuli are delivered regardless of the individual’s behavior. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction occurs when all reinforcement is withheld for the behavior of interest. If done correctly this will result in a decrease in behavior; however, not all decreases in behavior are a result of extinction. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by positive reinforcement occurs by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Withholding the presentation of appetitive stimuli for the specific behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior of interest does not produce a removal of an aversive stimulus",
                  "The sensory consequence is blocked",
                  "Any occurrence of the behavior results in the delivery of aversive stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by positive reinforcement occurs by withholding the presentation of appetitive stimuli for the specific behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by negative reinforcement occurs by:",
                "correctAnswer": "The behavior of interest does not produce a removal of an aversive stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "masking or removing the sensory consequence",
                  "Any occurrence of the behavior results in the delivery of aversive stimuli",
                  "Withholding the presentation of appetitive stimuli for the specific behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by negative reinforcement occurs by the behavior of interest not producing a removal of an aversive stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by automatic reinforcement occurs by:",
                "correctAnswer": "masking or removing the sensory consequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Withholding the presentation of appetitive stimuli for the specific behavior",
                  "The behavior of interest does not produce a removal of an aversive stimulus",
                  "Any occurrence of the behavior results in the delivery of aversive stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction for behaviors maintained by automatic reinforcement occurs by masking or removing the sensory consequence. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During extinction, there is typically an immediate increase in the frequency of the response. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction burst",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Resistance to extinction",
                  "Intermittent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinct bursts occur when there is an immediate increase in the frequency of the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During extinction, a behavior may decrease to the point that the behavior no longer occurs, then, seemingly out of nowhere, the behavior occurs. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Spontaneous recovery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Resistance to extinction",
                  "Intermittent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is known as spontaneous recovery. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After completing a functional assessment, it was determined that attention maintains Frank’s aggressive behaviors. What would extinction look like?",
                "correctAnswer": "Withholding attention while Frank engages in aggressive behaviors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Not letting Frank get out of tasks while being aggressive",
                  "Giving Frank attention all the time, regardless of his behavior",
                  "All of the above."
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction needs to match the function of the behavior. In this instance, that would mean withholding attention while Frank engages in aggressive behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After completing a functional assessment, it was determined that escape from tasks maintains Frank’s aggressive behaviors. What would extinction look like?",
                "correctAnswer": "Not letting Frank get out of tasks while being aggressive",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Limit the amount of tasks given to Frank",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Withholding attention while Frank engages in aggressive behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction needs to match the function of the behavior. In this instance, that would mean not letting Frank get out of tasks while being aggressive. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use combinations of reinforcement with punishment and extinction",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Reinforcing responses that meet  specific criteria, and withholding reinforcement for responses that don’t meet the criteria, is defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement occurs by reinforcing responses that meet specific criteria, and withholding reinforcement for responses that don’t meet the criteria. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Differential reinforcement combines which procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement and extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Punishment and extinction",
                  "Punishment and reinforcement",
                  "Punishment, reinforcement, and extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement combines reinforcement and extinction. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a limitation of using extinction without other procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "No alternative behavior is being learned",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior can’t truly decrease without punishment",
                  "It is dangerous for the individual",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Combining extinction with reinforcement procedures allows for alternative behaviors to be learned. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a limitation of using extinction without other procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "Possible worsened side effects including elevated extinction bursts and aggression.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior can’t truly decrease without punishment",
                  "It is dangerous for the individual",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Combining extinction with other procedures may minimize extinction bursts and aggression. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "It has been established that access to edibles maintains John’s angry outbursts. The intervention package is as follows: John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately. He is not given edibles when he engages in the behavior. If he engages in angry outbursts, John loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior. Which component utilizes extinction?",
                "correctAnswer": "Not delivering edibles when he engages in the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately",
                  "He loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior",
                  "None of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Withholding the edibles during problem behavior is the example of extinction."
              },
              {
                "question": "It has been established that access to edibles maintains John’s angry outbursts. The intervention package is as follows: John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately. He is not given edibles when he engages in the behavior. If he engages in angry outbursts, John loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior. Which component utilizes reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "He loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior",
                  "None of the above",
                  "Not delivering edibles when he engages in the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Given edibles for appropriate behavior utilizes reinforcement, assuming there is an increase in appropriate requests."
              },
              {
                "question": "It has been established that access to edibles maintains John’s angry outbursts. The intervention package is as follows: John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately. He is not given edibles when he engages in the behavior. If he engages in angry outbursts, John loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior. Which component utilizes punishment?",
                "correctAnswer": "He loses 5 minutes of TV time for every episode of the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "None of the above",
                  "Not delivering edibles when he engages in the behavior",
                  "John is given edibles whenever he asks appropriately"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment is utilized by restricting his TV time contingent on the occurrence of his behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in attempted elopement, which is usually reinforced escaping a task. The intervention package is as follows: If Mary attempts to elope, the RBT continues to request that she complete the task every 2 minutes until completed. Mary is able to request a 15 minute break from the task demand by using break cards. Every time she elopes, the RBT removes a token as part of the token economy in place for Mary. Which component utilizes extinction?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continuing to prompt task completion",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Break cards",
                  "Response cost with the token economy",
                  "Elopement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction is utilized by continuing to prompt task completion."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in attempted elopement, which is usually reinforced escaping a task. The intervention package is as follows: If Mary attempts to elope, the RBT continues to request that she complete the task every 2 minutes until completed. Mary is able to request a 15 minute break from the task demand by using break cards. Every time she elopes, the RBT removes a token as part of the token economy in place for Mary. Which component utilizes reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Break cards",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response cost with the token economy",
                  "Elopement",
                  "Continuing to prompt task completion"
                ],
                "explanation": "Break cards reinforce appropriate requests, assuming we see an increase in break card uses."
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in attempted elopement, which is usually reinforced escaping a task. The intervention package is as follows: If Mary attempts to elope, the RBT continues to request that she complete the task every 2 minutes until completed. Mary is able to request a 15 minute break from the task demand by using break cards. Every time she elopes, the RBT removes a token as part of the token economy in place for Mary. Which component utilizes punishment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Response cost with the token economy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Elopement",
                  "Continuing to prompt task completion",
                  "Break cards"
                ],
                "explanation": "The response cost program utilizes punishment, assuming it resulted in a decrease in elopement. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use response independent schedules of reinforcement (i.e., NCR)",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is a procedure, in which stimuli with known reinforcing properties are presented on a time based schedule.",
                "correctAnswer": "Non-contingent reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement",
                  "Extinction",
                  "DRA"
                ],
                "explanation": "Non-contingent reinforcement occurs when stimuli with known reinforcing properties are presented on a time based schedule. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Is non-contingent reinforcement, actually reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "No, it is not contingent on behavior, and does not result in an increase in behavior.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "No, it doesn’t actually work",
                  "Yes, it is the delivery of appetitive stimuli",
                  "Yes, it can improve behavior, and is a research based intervention."
                ],
                "explanation": "NCR is an effective antecedent intervention, but despite the name, is not actually reinforcement because it does not result in an increase in behavior. It is however the most frequently used term for the procedure. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "NCR is a(n)",
                "correctAnswer": "Antecedent intervention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Consequential intervention",
                  "Extinction based intervention",
                  "Differential reinforcement intervention"
                ],
                "explanation": "Non-contingent reinforcement is an antecedent intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Before using non-contingent reinforcement to decrease problem behavior, you must:",
                "correctAnswer": "Establish the function of the behavior of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conduct a preference assessment",
                  "Conduct a functional analysis",
                  "Conduct a reinforce assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Before using NCR to decrease problem behavior, you must establish the function of the behavior of interest. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph engages in boundary violations, which is usually reinforced by attention. Using NCR to reduce problem behavior can be done by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Delivering attention to Joseph every 5 minutes regardless of his behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver reinforcement to Joseph when he asks appropriately",
                  "Do not deliver attention to Joseph when he engages in boundary violations",
                  "Send Joseph to time out whenever he engages in boundary violations"
                ],
                "explanation": "NCR is used in this example by delivering attention to Joseph every 5 minutes regardless of his behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Using NCR may decrease problem behaviors by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Functioning as an abolishing operation (AO), reducing motivation to engage in the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functioning as an establishing operation, reducing motivation to engage in the behavior",
                  "Withholding reinforcement for problem behaviors",
                  "Delivering reinforcement for appropriate behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "NCR procedures function as an AO, reducing motivation to engage in the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Amy engages in aggressive behaviors, usually resulting in getting out of difficult tasks. NCR procedures can be implemented by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Giving Amy a break from the task every 10 seconds, regardless of her behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continuing to prompt task completion when she refuses",
                  "Reinforce task completion",
                  "Withhold  TV time for aggressive behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "Giving Amy non-contingent breaks is the correct way to implement NCR in this example. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage to NCR procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "NCR may reduce motivation to engage in adaptive behavior.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "NCR is easy to implement",
                  "It may reduce extinction bursts",
                  "Helps create a positive environment"
                ],
                "explanation": "NCR may reduce motivation to engage in adaptive behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a disadvantage to NCR procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "It may disrupt the instruction process (NCR escape)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "NCR is easy to implement",
                  "It may reduce extinction bursts",
                  "Helps create a positive environment"
                ],
                "explanation": "NCR may disrupt the instructional process. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage to NCR procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "NCR is easy to implement",
                  "It may reduce extinction bursts",
                  "Helps create a positive environment"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use differential reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This type of differential reinforcement, delivers reinforcement contingent on the absence of behavior during a set amount of time.",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of alternative behavior (DRA)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRO delivers reinforcement contingent on the absence of behavior during a set amount of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tom receives praise every time he does not hit his head for 30 seconds. Praise is withheld if Tom engages in hitting his head. Which type of differential reinforcement is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of alternative behavior (DRA)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRO delivers reinforcement contingent on the absence of behavior during a set amount of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of differential reinforcement withholds reinforcement for inappropriate responses, and delivers reinforcement for more acceptable and functionally equivalent behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of alternative behavior (DRA)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRA withholds reinforcement for inappropriate responses, and delivers reinforcement for more acceptable and functionally equivalent behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA pays attention to Tom every time he requests for attention appropriately. Every time Tom engages in boundary violations, the BCBA ignores Tom. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of alternative behavior (DRA)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRA withholds reinforcement for inappropriate responses, and delivers reinforcement for more acceptable and functionally equivalent behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of differential reinforcement reinforces behavior that is topographically incompatible with the behavior of interest, while withholding reinforcement for inappropriate behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRI reinforces behavior that is topographically incompatible with the behavior of interest, while withholding reinforcement for inappropriate behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tom wears a glove on his hand to mask the sensation of slapping his own head. He is reinforced for holding a toy firmly with both hands. Which type of differential reinforcement is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRI reinforces behavior that is topographically incompatible with the behavior of interest, while withholding reinforcement for inappropriate behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of differential reinforcement delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively decreases in rates of responding.",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRL delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively decreases in rates of responding. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tom washes his hands 40 times an hour on average. The BCBA reinforces successively longer IRTs of washing his hands. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRL delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively decreases in rates of responding. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of differential reinforcement delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively increases in rates of responding.",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRH delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively increases in rates of responding. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tom only washes his hands once each day. The BCBA reinforces successively more frequent washing of hands, until it reaches a more acceptable rate. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Differential reinforcement of high rates of behavior (DRH)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement of other behavior (DRO)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of incompatible behavior (DRI)",
                  "Differential reinforcement of low rates of behavior (DRL)"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRH delivers reinforcement when the behavior successively increases in rates of responding. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Specific behavior-change procedures",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Use interventions based on manipulation of antecedents, such as motivating operations and discriminative stimuli",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "MO",
                  "AO",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "An SD is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as an environmental variable that alters the reinforcing or punishing value of a stimulus.",
                "correctAnswer": "MO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "AO",
                  "EO",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "Motivation operations (MOs) are defined as environmental variables that alter the reinforcing or punishing value of a stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as an environmental variable that decreases the value of a reinforcing or punishing stimulus.",
                "correctAnswer": "AO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "EO",
                  "SD",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Abolishing operation (AO) is defined as an environmental variable that decreases the value of a reinforcing or punishing stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as an environmental variable that increases the reinforcing or punishing value of a stimulus.",
                "correctAnswer": "EO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "MO",
                  "AO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Establish operation (EO) is defined as an environmental variable that increases the reinforcing or punishing value of a stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as any environmental condition or stimulus change that occurs before the behavior of interest. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Antecedent",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "EO",
                  "SD",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Antecedent is defined as any environmental condition or stimulus change that occurs before the behavior of interest. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stacy is hungry and sees a vending machine down the hall. Stacy walks over to the vending machine and purchases a candy bar. Stacy is now full, and does not purchase additional food. Hunger, in this example, is most likely functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "EO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "AO",
                  "SD",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Hunger in this example, is functioning as an establishing operation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stacy is hungry and sees a vending machine down the hall. Stacy walks over to the vending machine and purchases a candy bar. Stacy is now full, and does not purchase additional food. Being full, in this example, is most likely functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "AO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Being full is functioning as an abolishing operation (AO). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stacy is hungry and sees a vending machine down the hall. Stacy walks over to the vending machine and purchases a candy bar. Stacy is now full, and does not purchase additional food. The sight of the vending machine, in this example, is most likely functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "EO",
                  "AO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The sight of the vending machine is an SD. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "There is a bee flying around Joseph. Joseph grabs a nearby rolled up magazine and swats the bee. The bee leaves. In this example, the bee flying around Joseph is most likely functioning as a(n)",
                "correctAnswer": "EO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "AO",
                  "SD",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": " This can be a tricky one. The bee is functioning as an EO. For negative reinforcement contingencies, the aversive stimulus is typically functioning as an EO for escape. The SD is the magazine. Without the magazine, Joseph wouldn’t have been able to swat at the bee. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "There is a bee flying around Joseph. Joseph grabs a nearby rolled up magazine and swats the bee. The bee leaves. In this example, the magazine is most likely functioning as a(n)",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "EO",
                  "AO"
                ],
                "explanation": " This can be a tricky one. The magazine is functioning as an SD. For negative reinforcement contingencies, the aversive stimulus is typically functioning as an EO for escape. The SD is the magazine. Without the magazine, Joseph wouldn’t have been able to swat at the bee. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use discrimination training procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "MO",
                  "SΔ",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "An SD is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a stimulus that signals the unavailability of reinforcement.",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "MO",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "SΔ (S-Delta) (Stimulus Delta) is defined as a stimulus that signals the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Discrimination training is taking place with Alexander, by placing a green sign by the door when outside activities are available. A red sign is on the door when no outside activities are available. In this example, the red sign is functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "MO",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "SΔ (S-Delta) (Stimulus Delta) is defined as a stimulus that signals the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Discrimination training is taking place with Alexander, by placing a green sign by the door when outside activities are available. A red sign is on the door when no outside activities are available. In this example, the green sign is functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "MO",
                  "SΔ",
                  "EO"
                ],
                "explanation": "An SD is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Discrimination training is taking place with Alexander, by placing a green sign by the door when outside activities are available. A red sign is on the door when no outside activities are available. If Alexander asks to go on an activity very politely while the red sign is out, he should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not be allowed to go on the activity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Allow the activity, because he asked politely",
                  "Implement a punishment procedure to aid in the discrimination process",
                  "Allow only a brief activity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Red needs to signal the absence of reinforcement. He should not be allowed to go on the activity any time the red sign is on the door. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This procedure is used to establish an SΔ:",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction is used to establish that a stimulus does not produce reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This procedure is used to establish an SD",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement is used to establish an SD. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Fred is learning colors with discrimination training. The RBT shows Fred a blue card and displays 3 cards in front of Fred: Blue, Green, and Red. The presentation of blue card functions as a _____ for selecting the blue card and should result in________.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD / Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD / No reinforcement",
                  "SΔ/ No reinforcement",
                  "SΔ/ Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "An SD is defined as a stimulus that signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Fred is learning colors with discrimination training. The RBT shows Fred a blue card and displays 3 cards in front of Fred: Blue, Green, and Red. The presentation of the blue card functions as a _____ for selecting the green card and should result in________.",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ/ No reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD / Reinforcement",
                  "SD / No reinforcement",
                  "SΔ/ Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "SΔ (S-Delta) (Stimulus Delta) is defined as a stimulus that signals the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Fred is learning colors with discrimination training. The RBT shows Fred a blue card and displays 3 cards in front of Fred: Blue, Green, and Red. The presentation of the blue card functions as a _____ for selecting the red card and should result in________.",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ/ No reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD / Reinforcement",
                  "SD / No reinforcement",
                  "SΔ/ Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "SΔ (S-Delta) (Stimulus Delta) is defined as a stimulus that signals the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use instructions and rules",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This type of behavior is under control of a verbal statement explaining the contingency. This allows the behavior to be under the control of temporally remote, yet significant consequences.",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule governed behavior is under control of a verbal statement explaining the contingency. This allows the behavior to be under the control of temporally remote, yet significant consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a verbal statement explaining a behavioral contingency",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A rule is a verbal statement explaining a behavioral contingency. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of behavior is selected and maintained by controlled and temporally close consequences.",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is selected and maintained by controlled and temporally close consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary wears her seatbelt even though she has never been in an accident or been pulled over in the car. She has been told that if she gets in an accident she will likely die if she isn’t wearing a seatbelt. This is an example of: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule governed behavior is under control of a verbal statement explaining the contingency. This allows the behavior to be under the control of temporally remote, yet significant consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary didn’t usually wear a seatbelt. She got pulled over and received a ticket for not wearing her seatbelt. Next time Mary gets in her car, she puts on her seatbelt. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is selected and maintained by controlled and temporally close consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary was told that she should always wear a seatbelt because it will keep her safe in case of an accident. This is an example of a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A rule is a verbal statement explaining a behavioral contingency. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James is told that the vending machine is broken. He remains sitting and does not go attempt to purchase a candy bar, even though he is hungry. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule governed behavior is under control of a verbal statement explaining the contingency. This allows the behavior to be under the control of temporally remote, yet significant consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James goes to the vending machine, and pushes a button to purchase a candy bar. The machine is not working, so James leaves. The next day, James does not try to purchase a candy bar out of the vending machine. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is selected and maintained by controlled and temporally close consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank engages in yelling. He is told that if he yells, he is going to hurt his throat. Frank doesn’t yell the entire day. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule governed behavior is under control of a verbal statement explaining the contingency. This allows the behavior to be under the control of temporally remote, yet significant consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank engages in yelling. After yelling all day, his throat begins to hurt. Frank stops yelling, and the next day, doesn’t yell nearly as much. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule governed behavior",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is selected and maintained by controlled and temporally close consequences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use contingency contracting",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a document that specifies a contingent relationship between the completion of a specified behavior and access to a reward. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency contract",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Token Economy"
                ],
                "explanation": "A contingency contract (behavioral contract) is a document that specifies a contingent relationship between the completion of a specified behavior and access to a reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a verbal statement explaining a behavioral contingency",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency shaped behavior",
                  "Contingency contract",
                  "Rule governed behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A rule is a verbal statement explaining a behavioral contingency. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the literature, to create a contingency contract, what level of description is needed?",
                "correctAnswer": "Descriptively written and signed by both parties",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A verbal agreement is sufficient",
                  "At least one party should have it written down",
                  "Any rule-governed behavior is considered a contingency contract."
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency contracts (behavioral contracts) need to be descriptively written and signed by both parties. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following should be included in a behavioral contract?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A description of the task, or behavior of interest",
                  "A description of the reward, including who will deliver it, when it will be delivered, and how much will be given",
                  "A place to record progress with the task should be included on the behavioral contract"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above should be included in a behavioral contract. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not a necessary component of a behavioral contract?",
                "correctAnswer": "A detailed title to the behavioral contract",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Signatures from both parties",
                  "A place to record progress",
                  "None of the above are necessary components"
                ],
                "explanation": "A detailed title to the behavioral contract is not a necessary component. However, signatures from both parties and a place to record progress are important components. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "With regards to describing the behavior or task in a contingency contract, which of the following questions DO NOT need to be explained?",
                "correctAnswer": "Why must the task be completed?",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Who will perform the task?",
                  "When must the task be completed?",
                  "How well must the task be completed?"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above must be answered in a behavioral contract except for “why must the task be completed?” (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "With regards to describing the reward in a contingency contract, which of the following questions DO NOT need to be explained?",
                "correctAnswer": "Why was the specific reward chosen?",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Who will judge task completion?",
                  "What is the reward?",
                  "When will the reward be given?"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above must be answered in a behavioral contract except for “why was the specific reward chosen?” (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which principle of behavior is most closely related to how behavioral contracts control behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule-governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Non-contingent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contracts are most related to rule-governed behavior. The reward is too delayed to typically function as positive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John tells his son that if he goes 5 days in a row completing all of his homework, he will be given $20. Both John and his son agree on this and follow through with the contingency, even though nothing was written down. This contingency is an example of a?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency Contract",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Non-contingent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of a rule. It is a verbal statement of a contingency. Nothing was written down so there was no behavioral contract. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John writes down that if his son goes 5 days in a row completing all of his homework, he will be given $20. Specific criteria are outlined as to what exactly the boy needs to do and what the reward will be. John and his son sign this document. This contingency is an example of a?",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency contract",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Non-contingent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The contingency was written down with details laid out. The document was signed. This is an example of a contingency contract. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use independent, interdependent, and dependent group contingencies",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a common consequence is contingent on the behavior of one member of the group, part of the group, or everyone in the group. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency",
                  "Dependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Group contingencies occur when a common consequence is contingent on the behavior of one member of the group, part of the group, or everyone in the group. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a contingency is presented to all members of a group, but only those who meet the criterion receive reinforcement. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency",
                  "Dependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Independent group contingencies occur when a contingency is presented to all members of a group, but only those who meet the criterion receive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when all members of a group m ust meet the criterion of the contingency before any member earns the reward.",
                "correctAnswer": "Interdependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dependent group contingency",
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Interdependent group contingencies occur when all members of a group m ust meet the criterion of the contingency before any member earns the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when one member (or a few members) meets the established criterion, and then the entire group receives the reward.",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Dependent group contingencies (the hero procedure) occur when one member (or a few members) meets the established criterion, and then the entire group receives the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This procedure is also known as the “hero procedure”.",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Dependent group contingencies (the hero procedure) occur when one member (or a few members) meets the established criterion, and then the entire group receives the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Donna is a teacher and set a procedure in place where anyone in her class who gets over 90% on the spelling test gets an extra 30 minutes of recess.  Which group contingency is in effect?",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency",
                  "Dependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Independent group contingencies occur when a contingency is presented to all members of a group, but only those who meet the criterion receive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Donna is a teacher and set a procedure in place that the entire class will get an extra 30 minutes of recess if every student gets over 90% on the spelling test. Which group contingency is in effect?",
                "correctAnswer": "Interdependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dependent group contingency",
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Interdependent group contingencies occur when all members of a group must meet the criterion of the contingency before any member earns the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Donna is a teacher and set a procedure in place that the entire class will get an extra 30 minutes of recess if one student gets over 90% on the spelling test. The student’s name is drawn at random just prior to the test.  Which group contingency is in effect?",
                "correctAnswer": "Dependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Dependent group contingencies (the hero procedure) occur when one member (or a few members) meets the established criterion, and then the entire group receives the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "At a local business, each employee is given a $500 bonus as soon as their individual paperwork is completed and submitted. Any employees who turn in paperwork after the deadline does not receive the reward. Which group contingency is in effect?",
                "correctAnswer": "Independent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Group contingency",
                  "Interdependent group contingency",
                  "Dependent group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Independent group contingencies occur when a contingency is presented to all members of a group, but only those who meet the criterion receive reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "At a local business, each employee is given a $500 bonus only when every employee has completed and submitted their paperwork by the deadline. If one person fails to submit their paperwork, nobody receives the reward.",
                "correctAnswer": "Interdependent group contingency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dependent group contingency",
                  "Independent group contingency",
                  "Group contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Interdependent group contingencies occur when all members of a group must meet the criterion of the contingency before any member earns the reward. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use stimulus equivalence procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a description of the emergence of accurate responding to untrained and nonreinforced relations following the reinforcement of other relations.",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus equivalence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus equivalence is a description of the emergence of accurate responding to untrained and nonreinforced relations following the reinforcement of other relations. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when, in the absence of training, a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself.",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity occurs when in the absence of training a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A boy is shown a picture of a dog and the boy selects another picture of a dog (A = A). This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity occurs when in the absence of training a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs with the reversibility of the sample stimulus and comparison stimulus.",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry occurs with the reversibility of the sample stimulus and comparison stimulus. (if A = B, then B = A). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor presents a picture of a dog, and the boy selects a toy dog from an array of toys. The instructor then presents a toy dog, and the boy selects a picture of a dog. (If A = B, then B = A)This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry occurs with the reversibility of the sample stimulus and comparison stimulus. (if A = B, then B = A). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor demonstrates that the image of the dog and the toy dog are the same. He then teaches that the toy dog and the written word “DOG” are the same. Then, without direct training, the boy selects the written word “DOG” when shown an image of a dog. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A learner demonstrates that A = A without prior training. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity occurs when in the absence of training a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If A = B, then B = A. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry occurs with the reversibility of the sample stimulus and comparison stimulus. (if A = B, then B = A). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If A = B and B = C, then A = C. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Plan for behavioral contrast effects",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This phenomenon occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High-probability request sequences",
                  "Matching law",
                  "Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when there is a stimulus change following a behavior, and then there is a decrease if the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Matching law",
                  "High-probability request sequences"
                ],
                "explanation": "Punishment occurs when stimulus change immediately follows a response, and decreases the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary loses TV time when her mother is home and Mary doesn’t clean her room. Mary usually cleans her room when her mother is home. When her mother is not home, Mary never cleans her room. What effect appears to be occurring?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral Contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔP ",
                  "Punishment",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary loses TV time when her mother is home and Mary doesn’t clean her room. Mary usually cleans her room when her mother is home. When her mother is not home, but her father is home, Mary never cleans her room. Mary’s mother appears to be a(n)?",
                "correctAnswer": "SDP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔP ",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Behavioral Contrast"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary’s mother appears to be functioning as an SDP. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary loses TV time when her mother is home and Mary doesn’t clean her room. Mary usually cleans her room when her mother is home. When her mother is not home, and her father is home, Mary never cleans her room. Mary’s father appears to be a(n)?",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔP ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SDP",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Behavioral Contrast"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary’s father appears to be functioning as an SΔP. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Using the intervention in ALL applicable settings and conditions",
                  "Withhold reinforcement for all occurrences of problem behavior",
                  "Provide alternative desirable behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above can be used to minimize behavioral contrast effects. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide alternative desirable behaviors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ask the person to not engage in the problem behavior",
                  "Collect data",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by providing alternative desirable behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Don engages in frequent disruptive behaviors. His teacher implements a token economy where she removes one of Don’s tokens every time he is disruptive. This results in disruptive behaviors decreasing while the teacher is there. When a substitute teacher is present, engages in even more frequent disruptive behaviors. What phenomenon is occurring?  ",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral Contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔP ",
                  "Punishment",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Don engages in frequent disruptive behaviors. His teacher implements a token economy where she removes one of Don’s tokens every time he is disruptive. This results in disruptive behaviors decreasing while the teacher is there. When a substitute teacher is present, engages in even more frequent disruptive behaviors. The teacher appears to be functioning as a(n)?",
                "correctAnswer": " SDP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔP ",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Behavioral Contrast"
                ],
                "explanation": "Don’s teacher appears to be functioning as an SDP. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Don engages in frequent disruptive behaviors. His teacher implements a token economy where she removes one of Don’s tokens every time he is disruptive. This results in disruptive behaviors decreasing while the teacher is there. When a substitute teacher is present, engages in even more frequent disruptive behaviors. The substitute teacher appears to be functioning as a(n)?",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔP ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SDP",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Behavioral Contrast"
                ],
                "explanation": "Don’s substitute teacher appears to be functioning as an SΔP. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use the matching law and recognize factors influencing choice",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "According to this principle, behavior matches reinforcement distribution. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Matching law",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Concurrent schedule",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Premack Principle"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to the matching law, behavior matches reinforcement distribution. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The matching law explains “choice” within which schedule of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Concurrent schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules"
                ],
                "explanation": "The matching law explains choice within concurrent schedules of reinforcement. (Martin, Yu, Martin, & Fazzio, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the presence of multiple discriminative stimuli.",
                "correctAnswer": "Choice",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Choosing",
                  "Preference",
                  "Matching law"
                ],
                "explanation": "A choice is defined as the presence of multiple discriminative stimuli. (Martin, Yu, Martin, & Fazzio, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as performing a discriminated operant, when another is possible.",
                "correctAnswer": "Choosing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Choice",
                  "Preference",
                  "Matching Law"
                ],
                "explanation": "Choosing is defined as performing a discriminated operant, when another is possible. (Martin, Yu, Martin, & Fazzio, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when one discriminated operant is stronger than another, especially when a choice is present. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Preference",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Choice",
                  "Choosing",
                  "Matching Law"
                ],
                "explanation": "A preference is evident when one discriminated operant is stronger than another, especially when a choice is present. (Martin, Yu, Martin, & Fazzio, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound  schedule of reinforcement occurs when 2 contingencies are operating simultaneously and independently for two or more behaviors. This schedule provides choice for the individual, and occurs frequently in the natural environment.",
                "correctAnswer": "Concurrent schedule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules "
                ],
                "explanation": ""
              },
              {
                "question": "This Compound schedule of reinforcement occurs when two or more schedules of reinforcement occur in an alternating, usually random sequence. A discriminative stimulus is correlated with each schedule. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Chained schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules",
                  "Tandem schedules "
                ],
                "explanation": "Multiple schedules of reinforcement occur when two or more schedules of reinforcement occur in an alternating, usually random sequence. A discriminative stimulus is correlated with each schedule. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the matching law, what affects choosing?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcement rate",
                  "Quality of reinforcement",
                  "Response effort"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above affect choosing. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the matching law, what affects choosing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Free agency",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Genetics"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement rate affects choosing. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Measuring choice allocation during frequent response opportunities will help determine:",
                "correctAnswer": "Preferences",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Choices",
                  "Response effort",
                  "Matching law"
                ],
                "explanation": "Measuring choice allocation during frequent response opportunities will help determine preferences. (Martin, Yu, Martin, & Fazzio, 2006)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Arrange high-probability request sequences",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a metaphor to describe a rate of responding and its resistance to change following an alteration in reinforcement conditions. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral momentum",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High-probability behavior",
                  "Low-probability behavior",
                  "High-P request sequence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral momentum is defined as a metaphor to describe a rate of responding and its resistance to change following an alteration in reinforcement conditions. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is an antecedent intervention in which two to five easy tasks with a known history of compliance are presented in quick succession immediately before requesting the target task.",
                "correctAnswer": "High-P request sequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "High-probability behavior",
                  "Low-probability behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "High-probability request sequence is an antecedent intervention in which two to five easy tasks with a known history of compliance are presented in quick succession immediately before requesting the target task. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior that has a known history of compliance.",
                "correctAnswer": "High-probability behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Low-probability behavior",
                  "High-P request sequence",
                  "Behavioral momentum"
                ],
                "explanation": "A high probability behavior is one that has a known history of compliance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a target request in a high-p request sequence.",
                "correctAnswer": "Low-probability behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High-P request sequence",
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "High-probability behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The low-probability behavior is the target request in a high-p request sequence. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To implement a high-p request sequence, the instructor should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Give 2-5 high-p requests, then one low-p request",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Give one high-p request, then 2-5 low-p requests",
                  "Give 2-5 low-p requests, the one high-p request",
                  "Give one low-p request, then 2-5 high-p requests"
                ],
                "explanation": "To implement a high-p request sequence, the instructor should give 2-5 high-p requests, then one low-p request. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The tasks selected for the high-p request sequence should:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Be in the learner’s current repertoire",
                  "Occur with regularity of compliance",
                  "Have a short duration of occurrence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Tasks selected for the high-p request sequence should be in the learner’s current repertoire, have a short duration of occurrence, and occur with regular compliance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The tasks selected for the high-p request sequence should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Be in the learner’s current repertoire",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Not occur regularly with compliance",
                  "Have a long duration of occurrence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Tasks selected for the high-p request sequence should be in the learner’s current repertoire, have a short duration of occurrence, and occur with regular compliance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a high-p request sequence, after presenting a high-p request, when do you request another?",
                "correctAnswer": "Immediately following reinforcement for compliance to the first high-p request",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Immediately following the first high-p request",
                  "A while after the first high-p request",
                  "A while after reinforcement for compliance to the first high-p request"
                ],
                "explanation": "Another high-p request should be delivered immediately following reinforcement for compliance to the first high-p request. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a high-p request sequence, when do you give a low-p request?",
                "correctAnswer": "Immediately after the learner complied with 2-5 high-p requests",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A few minutes after the learner complied with 2-5 high-p requests",
                  "Immediately before presenting 2-5 high-p requests",
                  "Immediately before presenting one high-p request"
                ],
                "explanation": "The low-p request is to be delivered immediately after the learner complied with 2-5 high-p requests. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What should be done immediately after complying with a high-p request?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver an additional high-p request",
                  "Deliver a low-p request",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Immediately after compliance with a high-p request, reinforcement should be delivered, then an additional high-p request. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use the Premack principle",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is another name for the Premack principle?",
                "correctAnswer": "Grandma’s law",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Mommy’s principle",
                  "Response deprivation hypothesis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Grandma’s law is another name for the Premack principle. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Any response A will reinforce any response B if and only if the independent rate of A is greater than B. This is the definition of what?",
                "correctAnswer": "Premack principle",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response deprivation hypothesis",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "High probability request sequence"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Premack principle explains that any response A will reinforce any response B if and only if the independent rate of A is greater than B. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To implement the Premack principle, the instructor needs to select 2 behaviors. These should be:",
                "correctAnswer": "The target behavior to increase and a preferred behavior/activity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Two target behaviors to increase",
                  "Two preferred activities",
                  "The target behavior to increase and a preferred item"
                ],
                "explanation": "To implement the Premack principle, the instructor will select the target behavior to increase and a preferred behavior/activity. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph struggles to brush his teeth, but he loves to color. To implement the Premack principle:",
                "correctAnswer": "Joseph should be required to brush his teeth before he is allowed to color.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Joseph should be allowed to color as much as he wants, so he isn’t too upset to take a break to brush his teeth.",
                  "Joseph should be allowed to color for 10 minutes, and then he must take a break to brush his teeth.",
                  "Joseph may color as long as he promises to brush his teeth later."
                ],
                "explanation": "Joseph should be required to brush his teeth before he is allowed to color. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When preferred activities are restricted, this will function as an establishing operation to make them more powerful reinforcers. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "The response deprivation hypothesis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The Premack principle",
                  "High probability request sequence",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The response deprivavtion hypothesis explains that when preferred activities are restricted, this will function as an establishing operation to make them more powerful reinforcers. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the response deprivation hypothesis, the Premack principle will be more effective if which behavior is limited/restricted?",
                "correctAnswer": "The preferred behavior/activity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The less preferred behavior/activity",
                  "Both the less and more preferred behavior/activity",
                  "Neither the less nor the preferred behavior/activity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Restricting the preferred behavior/activity will increase the effectiveness of the Premack principle. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy loves playing basketball. She does not enjoy doing her homework. To implement the Premack principle, what contingency should be in place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Lucy must complete her homework before playing basketball. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Lucy should complete half of her homework, play basketball for 15 minutes, then finish her homework.",
                  "Lucy may play basketball first ONLY if she promises to do her homework after basketball.",
                  "Lucy should be allowed to play basketball until she is bored, then she will choose to do her homework on her own. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Lucy should be required to complete her homework before playing basketball. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The Premack principle reinforces non-preferred behaviors/activitities with:",
                "correctAnswer": "A highly preferred behavior/activity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A non-preferred behavior/activity",
                  "Any preferred item",
                  "Any item established as a reinforce"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Premack principle reinforces non-preferred behaviors/activities with a highly preferred behavior/activity. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy loves playing basketball. She does not enjoy doing her homework. To use response deprivation to increase the effectiveness of the Premack principle, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Restrict the amount of time Lucy may play basketball",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Restrict the amount of time Lucy may do homework",
                  "Not restrict the amount of time Lucy may play basketball",
                  "Not restrict the amount of time Lucy may do homework"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to the response deprivation hypothesis, restricting the amount of time Lucy plays basketball would help increase the effectiveness of the Premack principle. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph struggles to brush his teeth, but he loves to color. To use response deprivation to increase the effectiveness of the Premack  principle, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Restrict the amount of time Joseph may color",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Restrict the amount of time Joseph may brush his teeth",
                  "Not restrict the amount of time Joseph may color",
                  "Not restrict the amount of time Joseph may brush his teeth"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to the response deprivation hypothesis, restricting the amount of time Joseph may color would help increase the effectiveness of the Premack principle. (Klatt & Morris, 2001)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use pairing procedures to establish new conditioned reinforcers and punishers",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The contingent presentation of this stimulus increases a behavior due to the individual’s learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a conditioned reinforce. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The contingent presentation of this stimulus increases a behavior NOT due to the individual’s learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an unconditioned reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The contingent presentation of this stimulus decreases a behavior due to the individual’s learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a conditioned punisher. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The contingent presentation of this stimulus decreases a behavior NOT due to the individual’s learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an unconditioned punisher. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The contingent presentation of this stimulus does not increase nor decrease behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a neutral stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Small edible treats is reinforcing for James, however praise is not. What process should take place to help Praise become a conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer Assessment",
                  "Preference Assessment",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer training"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing (or just “pairing”) should take place. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Small edible treats is reinforcing for James, however praise is not. How can praise become a conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver praise as temporally close to delivering small edibles as possible. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver praise more frequently",
                  "Deliver edibles more frequently",
                  "Pair praise with a conditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Deliver praise as temporally close to delivering small edibles as possible. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This powerful stimulus has been paired with several different reinforcers to gain reinforcing properties.",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Conditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a generalized conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "For most people, money is a powerful reinforcer because it has been paired with many other reinforcers. This is an example of a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Conditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a generalized conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Praise was paired repeatedly with small edibles. However, when praise is delivered alone, it still does not increase the frequency of the behavior. Praise appears to be functioning as a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Praise appears to be functioning as a neutral stimulus in this example. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use errorless learning procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be used in an errorless learning procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response prompts",
                  "Time delay",
                  "Stimulus fading"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are errorless learning procedures."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be used in an errorless learning procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Response prompts",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Non-contingent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response prompts may be used in an errorless learning procedure."
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy is based on the understanding that trial and error is not a necessary part of learning. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Errorless learning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Differential reinforcement",
                  "Shaping",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Errorless learning is based on the understanding that trial and error is not a necessary part of learning."
              },
              {
                "question": "This errorless learning procedure gradually increases the amount of time from the SD to the response prompt.",
                "correctAnswer": "Time delay",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response prompt",
                  "Stimulus fading",
                  "Errorless learning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Time delay procedures gradually increase the amount of time from the SD to the response prompt."
              },
              {
                "question": "This errorless learning procedure may involve modeling, physical prompting, and verbal instructions.",
                "correctAnswer": "Response prompts",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Time delay",
                  "Stimulus fading",
                  "Errorless learning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response prompts involve modeling, physical prompting, and verbal instructions."
              },
              {
                "question": "This errorless learning procedure involves highlighting a physical dimension of a stimulus (color, size, position) to increase the likelihood of a correct response. This is then gradually faded.",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus fading",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Errorless learning",
                  "Time delay",
                  "Response prompts"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of stimulus fading."
              },              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” he places his hand on hers, moving her hand until she selects the correct card. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Full physical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model",
                  "Gestural"
                ],
                "explanation": "Full physical prompts include hand over hand manipulation to aid the learner to the correct answer."
              },              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” Alex touches the correct response, demonstrating the correct response. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Model",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Gestural",
                  "Full physical",
                  "Partial physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Modeling includes the instructor demonstrating the correct response for the learner."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and pink. After saying “Where is the red card?” Alex points in the direction of the correct card. This is an example of which kind of prompt?",
                "correctAnswer": "Gestural",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Full physical",
                  "Partial physical",
                  "Model"
                ],
                "explanation": "Gestural prompts include pointing or gesturing towards the next step of completing the task."
              },
              {
                "question": "Alex is a BCBA using errorless learning to teach a child to discriminate between red and ink. After saying “Where is the red card?” Alex immediately points in the direction of the correct card. During the next trial, Alex waits 1 second before giving another prompt. Alex appears to be using which errorless learning procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Time delay",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Gestural",
                  "Model",
                  "Full physical"
                ],
                "explanation": "Alex appears to be using a time delay. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use matching to sample procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Matching to sample procedures are used to help develop and test for:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus equivalence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Matching skills",
                  "Reinforcing stimuli",
                  "Behavior chains"
                ],
                "explanation": "Matching to sample procedures are used to help develop and test for stimulus equivalence."
              },
              {
                "question": "Matching to sample procedures usually take place in:",
                "correctAnswer": "Discrete trials",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The natural environment",
                  "New environments",
                  "The classroom"
                ],
                "explanation": "Matching to sample procedures usually take place in discrete trials."
              },
              {
                "question": "A boy is shown a picture of a dog and the boy selects another picture of a dog (A = A). This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity occurs when in the absence of training a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor presents a picture of a dog, and the boy selects a toy dog from an array of toys. The instructor then presents a toy dog, and the boy selects a picture of a dog. (If A = B, then B = A)This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry occurs with the reversibility of the sample stimulus and comparison stimulus. (if A = B, then B = A). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor demonstrates that the image of the dog and the toy dog are the same. He then teaches that the toy dog and the written word “DOG” are the same. Then, without direct training, the boy selects the written word “DOG” when shown an image of a dog. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a description of the emergence of accurate responding to untrained and nonreinforced relations following the reinforcement of other relations.",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus equivalence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus equivalence is a description of the emergence of accurate responding to untrained and nonreinforced relations following the reinforcement of other relations. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are procedures used to test for stimulus equivalence:",
                "correctAnswer": "Matching to sample",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus equivalence",
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Matching to sample procedures test for stimulus equivalence."
              },
              {
                "question": "The instructor demonstrates that the image of the dog and the toy dog are the same. He then teaches that the toy dog and the written word “DOG” are the same. Then, without direct training, the boy selects the written word “DOG” when shown an image of a dog. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A learner demonstrates that A = A without prior training. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity occurs when in the absence of training a response will select a stimulus that is matched to itself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If A = B and B = C, then A = C. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Stimulus Equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when a derived relation emerges as a product of training two other relations. If A = B and B = C, then A = C. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Behavior-Change Systems",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Use self-management strategies",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the personal application of behavior change tactics that produces a desired change in behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Self-Management",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Self-Control",
                  "Self-Monitoring",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Self-Management is the correct answer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is “Self-Control” a misleading term?",
                "correctAnswer": "It implies that the ultimate control of behavior lies within the person.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It implies that people can influence their own behavior.",
                  "It implies that behavior is able to be controlled.",
                  "It implies that behavior cannot be controlled."
                ],
                "explanation": "The term “self-control” is misleading because it implies that the ultimate control of behavior lies within the person. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using self-management strategies?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It can influence behaviors not accessible to external change agents",
                  "Can promote generalization and maintenance",
                  "People with diverse abilities can learn these skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of using self-management strategies?",
                "correctAnswer": "Self-Management is an ultimate goal of education",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Only higher functioning individuals are capable of learning these skills",
                  "It hinders generalization and maintenance"
                ],
                "explanation": "Self-Management is an ultimate goal of education. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an antecedent based self-management strategy?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Manipulating MOs",
                  "Removing materials required for an undesired behavior",
                  "Limiting an undesired behavior to restricted stimulus conditions"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an antecedent based self-management strategy?",
                "correctAnswer": "Providing environmental prompts/cues",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Self-monitoring",
                  "Self-evaluation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Providing environmental prompts/cues is an antecedent based self-management strategy. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To prevent yourself from purchasing too much food at the grocery store, you eat a big meal right before you go shopping. What type of self-management strategy are you using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Manipulating MOs",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Self-monitoring",
                  "Removing materials required for an undesired behavior",
                  "Limiting an undesired behavior to restricted stimulus conditions."
                ],
                "explanation": "By getting full before shopping, you are manipulating MOs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You discover you say the word “like” too often during conversation. Every time you say “like” you mark a tally on a little notebook you carry around. What type of self-management strategy are you using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Self-monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Manipulating MOs",
                  "Removing materials required for an undesired behavior",
                  "Performing the initial steps of a behavior chain"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of self-monitoring. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You struggle to go to the gym in the morning, and often sleep through the alarm. You pack your gym bag the night before and place it by the door in the morning to make it easier to go the next day. What type of self-management strategy are you using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Performing initial steps of a behavior chain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Self-monitoring",
                  "Manipulating MOs",
                  "Removing materials required for an undesired behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "You are performing initial steps of a behavior chain. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You typically forget to bring your lunch with you to work. The night before you place a sticky note on the front door as a reminder. What type of self-management strategy are you using?",
                "correctAnswer": "Providing environmental prompts/cues",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Manipulating MOs",
                  "Self-monitoring",
                  "Self-evaluation"
                ],
                "explanation": "You are providing environmental prompts/cues. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use token economies and other conditioned reinforcement systems",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as a behavior change system that utilizes points or other tokens which are exchanged for backup reinforcers.",
                "correctAnswer": "Token Economy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Backup reinforcer",
                  "Level system",
                  "Response cost"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a token economy. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as items that are exchanged for using tokens.",
                "correctAnswer": "Backup reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Token economy",
                  "Level system",
                  "Response cost"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a backup reinforcer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a program in which the learners are moved up and down a hierarchy of privileges with regards to earning tokens.",
                "correctAnswer": "Level system",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Backup reinforcer",
                  "Token economy",
                  "Response cost"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a level system. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a program during which the learner is earns tokens contingent on appropriate behavior, but also loses tokens contingent on poor behavior. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Response cost",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Level system",
                  "Backup reinforcer",
                  "Token economy"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a response cost. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of consequence is a token in a token economy?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Tokens should function as generalized conditioned reinforcers. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is necessary in developing a token economy?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Identify target behaviors",
                  "Identify backup reinforcers",
                  "Identify a ratio of exchange"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are necessary in developing a token economy. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT necessary in developing a token economy?",
                "correctAnswer": "Select maladaptive behaviors to decrease by removing tokens",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Identify target behaviors",
                  "Establish a ratio of exchange",
                  "Select tokens"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response cost programs are not necessary in token economies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Initially, when implementing a token economy, the ratio between the number of tokens and the price of backup reinforcers should be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Low",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High",
                  "Increased",
                  "Decreased"
                ],
                "explanation": "The ratio should be low, so the learner is easily able to come into contact with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a challenge with implementing a token economy:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior typically does not change significantly",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It utilizes large amounts of time, energy, and resources.",
                  "May be cumbersome for behavior analyst and staff to implement",
                  "May be difficult to fade or remove."
                ],
                "explanation": "Token economies are an effective procedure for changing behavior, even making significant changes. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A response cost program is set up to function as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response cost programs are set up to function as negative punishment, by removing tokens contingent on maladaptive behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use Direct Instruction",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Choral responding, in relation to direct instruction, involves:",
                "correctAnswer": "All students reciting the correct answer in unison",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All students will sing the correct answer",
                  "One student will be asked to say the correct answer",
                  "Students will ask each other questions about the learning material."
                ],
                "explanation": "Choral responding involves all students reciting the correct answer in unison. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What should the class size typically be while using direct instruction? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Small groups",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Large groups",
                  "Individualized ",
                  "It doesn’t matter. Direct instruction works for all class sizes!"
                ],
                "explanation": "Small groups are best for direct instruction. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How should the learning material be presented during direct instruction?",
                "correctAnswer": "A written script is followed nearly exactly",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A written script is used as a guide",
                  "The teacher is able to customize the content and script for the needs of the students",
                  "As long as the teacher covers the content, it doesn’t matter how exactly the content is taught"
                ],
                "explanation": "A written script is followed nearly exactly. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When errors are made by students during direct instruction, what does the teacher do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Give immediate feedback as written in the script.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Give immediate feedback individualized to the need of the child.",
                  "The instructor moves on. This script doesn’t usually cover errors.",
                  "The teacher starts back at the beginning of the section to ensure all students achieve mastery. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Teachers are to give immediate feedback as written in the script. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use precision teaching",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which graphing tool is regularly used during precision teaching?",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Histogram",
                  "Equal-interval graph",
                  "Pie chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Standard celeration charts are usually used during precision teaching. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the learner performs accurately and at a high rate of occurrence. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Fluency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Improvement",
                  "Accuracy ",
                  "Precision teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Fluency occurs when the learner performs accurately and at a high rate of occurrence. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT an essential component of precision teaching",
                "correctAnswer": "The learner moves through the curriculum at their own pace",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Focus on fluency",
                  "Measure frequency",
                  "Focus on clearly defined and observable behavior "
                ],
                "explanation": "The learner does not move through the curriculum at their own pace.  That is true for personalized system of instruction. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To measure fluency, what two measurements are used?",
                "correctAnswer": "Accuracy and frequency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Accuracy and Percent correct",
                  "Frequency and inter-response time",
                  "Inter-response time and percent correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Accuracy and frequency are used to measure fluency. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an essential component of PSI?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Focus on mastery",
                  "Repeated testing",
                  "Move at your own pace"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are correct. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an essential component of PSI?",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequent testing and immediate feedback",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The teacher follows a written script",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Focus on fluency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequent testing and immediate feedback are essential components of PSI. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Steven is using PSI to learn biology in an online class. He goes through the first short unit, but didn’t score the level needed on the first test for mastery. If this is truly a PSI program, what should occur next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Steven is given immediate feedback on the questions he missed. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Steven may move on to the next unit",
                  "Steven will receive a penalty for errors on the test",
                  "Steven may retake the test once"
                ],
                "explanation": "Immediate feedback should be given, and Steven must remain on the same unit until mastery is achieved. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Steven is using PSI to learn biology in an online class. He goes through the first short unit and scored the level needed on the first test for mastery. If this is truly a PSI program, what should occur next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Steven may move on to the next unit.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Steven will receive a penalty for errors on the test.",
                  "Steven may retake the test once.",
                  "Steven is given immediate feedback on the questions he missed. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Steven may move on to the next unit as soon as mastery is demonstrated for that unit. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use incidental teaching",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Who can implement incidental teaching effectively?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "BCBA’s",
                  "RBT’s",
                  "Parents"
                ],
                "explanation": "One of the advantages of incidental teaching is that most people can be trained to conduct this effectively. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you prepare the environment for incidental teaching with your child? You are hoping to begin to teach him how to ask for cookies appropriately.",
                "correctAnswer": "Place the cookies in sight but out of reach",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Place the cookies out of sight and out of reach",
                  "Give the cookie to the child",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "When starting out, it would be best for the cookies to be in sight but out of reach. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you prepare the environment for incidental teaching with your child? You are going to teach him how to ask for cookies appropriately.",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Place the cookies in sight but out of reach",
                  "Put the cookie in sight when the child hasn’t eaten in a while",
                  "Bake cookies so the house smells like freshly baked cookies"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above would be good to prepare for incidental teaching. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an essential component of incidental teaching?",
                "correctAnswer": "Occurs in the natural environment where the behavior is likely to occur",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "The learner moves through the curriculum at their own pace",
                  "The teacher must follow a script"
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching occurs in the natural environment where the behavior is likely to occur. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use functional communication training",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is the purpose of functional communication training",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach an appropriate replacement behavior & reduce problem behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach an appropriate replacement behavior",
                  "Reduce problem behavior",
                  "Provide non-contingent reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is intended to teach an appropriate replacement behavior & reduce problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What differential reinforcement procedure is used during functional communication training?",
                "correctAnswer": "DRA",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRO",
                  "DRL",
                  "DRI"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential Reinforcement of Alternative behaviors is used as reinforcement is provided for appropriate responses and withheld for problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Before using functional communication training to decrease a problem behavior, what must occur?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "You must conduct a functional assessment on the problem behavior",
                  "You must select a functionally equivalent communicative response ",
                  "You must have the specific reinforcement ready to be delivered "
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above must occur before using FCT to decrease problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Should prompts be used during functional communication training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Yes, but they should be faded as soon as possible",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Yes, prompts are naturally occurring in most environments",
                  "No, pure shaping is sufficient to teach an appropriate replacement behavior",
                  "No, prompting will lead to the learner becoming prompt dependent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prompts may be used during functional communication training, but they should be faded as soon as possible. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Use augmentative communication systems",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "These are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech.",
                "correctAnswer": "Augmentative communication systems",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct Instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Augmentative communication systems are devices used for individuals with severe speech deficits allowing them to communicate in other forms rather than vocal speech. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an example of an augmentative communication system?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "PECS",
                  "Tablet",
                  "Progressive communicators"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are examples of augmentative communication systems. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an example of an augmentative communication system?",
                "correctAnswer": "Tablet",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Microphone",
                  "Speakers",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tablet is an example of an augmentative communication system. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is vocal speech preferred to the use of augmentative communication systems?",
                "correctAnswer": "Vocal speech is more widely understood by more audiences and is more transportable.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Vocal speech is NOT more preferred to the use of augmentative communication systems",
                  "Vocal speech is required to access most reinforcement",
                  "Vocal speech is easier to learn"
                ],
                "explanation": "Vocal speech is more widely understood by more audiences and is more easily transportable. Many augmentative communication systems can be heavy and difficult to carry with the speaker. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Communicating with an augmentative communication system is considered:",
                "correctAnswer": "Verbal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Vocal behavior",
                  "Augmentative communicative behavior",
                  "All of the above are accepted terms"
                ],
                "explanation": "Verbal behavior includes all forms of communication including speech, sign and the use of augmentative communication systems. (Dattilo & Camarata, 1991)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What behavior-change system is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional communication training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Augmentative communication systems",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional communication training is used by establishing an appropriate communicative replacement behavior for a functionally equivalent problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Incidental teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Functional communication training (FCT) "
                ],
                "explanation": "Incidental teaching uses naturally occurring interactions to teach skills in the natural environment. (Hart & Risley, 1975)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which teaching strategy is centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content?",
                "correctAnswer": "Personalized Systems of instruction (PSI)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct instruction",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Personalized systems of instruction are centered on the learner moving on in the curriculum at their own pace, as soon as they master the current content. (Sherman, 1992)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This teaching strategy focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form.",
                "correctAnswer": "Precision teaching",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Incidental teaching",
                  "Direct instruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Precision teaching focuses on increasing fluency by using frequency as the primary measurement form. (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of teaching strategy uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR).",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct Instruction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Personalized systems of instruction (PSI)",
                  "Precision teaching",
                  "Incidental teaching"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct instruction uses scripted presentations in small groups. The instructor typically moves at a fast pace and relies heavily on active student responding (ASR). (Binder & Watkins, 2013)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Identification of the Problem",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Review records and available data at the outset of the case",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "According to the BACB’s ethical code, how long are behavior analysts to keep records?",
                "correctAnswer": "7 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                  "Until termination of services",
                  "5 years (and as otherwise required by law)"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB requires that records be stored for at least 7 years and as otherwise required by law. This is according to the BACB “Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analyst” section 2.11."
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to taking on new clients, what factor(s) must be considered?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Available resources",
                  "Education",
                  "Experience"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above must be considered, according to the BACB “Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analyst” section 2.01."
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to taking on new clients, what factor(s) must be considered?",
                "correctAnswer": "Organizational Policies",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Age of the client",
                  "Diversity considerations",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to the BACB “Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analyst” section 2.01, organizational policies is consideration that needs to be made prior to accepting a client."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have accepted to work with a new client. When considering which behaviors to address, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Review records and available data",
                  "Consider biological/medical variables",
                  "Conduct preliminary assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB task list identifies all of the above as things necessary in selecting problem behaviors."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have accepted to work with a new client. When considering which behaviors to address, you should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Review records and available data",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Receive an initial down payment for services",
                  "Conduct a functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB task list identifies that you should review records and available data."
              },
              {
                "question": "When a case is transferred to a new behavior analyst, what is required to share confidential information such as past records and data?",
                "correctAnswer": "Consent of the client",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Transferring a case is justification alone to release confidential records. ",
                  "All of the above",
                  "The behavior analyst needs to inform the client that they shared confidential information."
                ],
                "explanation": "Consent of the client is needed to share confidential information, unless there is other legal reasons to do so as outlined in the BACB ethics code 2.08."
              },
              {
                "question": "At what point should client’s data and records initially be reviewed?",
                "correctAnswer": "At the outset of the case",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Before accepting the case",
                  "After the problem behavior has been accepted",
                  "It differs for each situation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Data and records are to be reviewed initially at the outset of the case according to the BACB task list G-01."
              },
              {
                "question": "Who is defined as a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The individual with disabilities",
                  "Whoever funds the services",
                  "The behavior analyst"
                ],
                "explanation": "The client is whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be identified as a “client”?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The service recipient",
                  "The parent",
                  "An organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above may be identified as a client according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "You just accepted Peter as a new client. He received services with another provider before coming on to your caseload. What should you request from the past provider?",
                "correctAnswer": "Past data and records",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A referral fee",
                  "8 hours of in person training on the previous behavior plan ",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Past data and records should be requested. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Consider biological/medical variables that may be affecting the client",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "For the past two days your client spits out his food. He doesn’t even eat typically preferred foods. What should be your course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conduct a functional assessment",
                  "Reinforce eating compliance",
                  "Reprimand every occurrence of spitting out food"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "For the past two days your client spits out his food. He doesn’t even eat typically preferred foods. He was taken in to several physicians who all say that the behavior doesn’t appear to be medically related. What might be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conduct a functional assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Recommend seeking additional medical consultations",
                  "Reinforce eating compliance",
                  "Reprimand every occurrence of spitting out food"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related. "
              },
              {
                "question": "You notice a drastic spike in the frequency of your client engaging in head hitting. There appears to be no recent major changes to his environment or supports. What should be your initial course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Consider redoing the functional assessment",
                  "Implement a DRA procedure",
                  "Reprimand every occurrence of hitting his head-"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "You notice a drastic spike in the frequency of your client engaging in head hitting. There appears to be no recent major changes to his environment or supports. After seeking a medical consult, there appears to be no medical or biological factors. What should be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Consider redoing the functional assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                  "Implement a DRA procedure",
                  "Reprimand every occurrence of hitting his head-"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "You notice a drastic spike in the frequency of your client engaging in head hitting. His physician states that this behavior appears to be headache related and prescribes pain killers. What should be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Wait for the behavior to be medically addressed, and seek out further medical consult if the behavior continues.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Consider redoing the functional assessment",
                  "Implement a DRA procedure",
                  "Reprimand every occurrence of hitting his head-"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "Your client engages in frequent urinary incontinence. You have been working with her for 2 years, and this has never been an issue before. What may be your course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conduct a functional assessment",
                  "Ignore the behavior and teach her how to appropriately seek attention",
                  "Continue prompting task completion and teach how to appropriately get out of a task"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "Your client engages in frequent urinary incontinence. You have been working with her for 2 years, and this has never been an issue before. Her medical doctors state that there is no apparent medical component to this behavior. What may be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conduct a functional assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                  "Ignore the behavior and teach her how to appropriately seek attention",
                  "Continue prompting task completion and teach how to appropriately get out of a task"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "Your client engages in frequent urinary incontinence. You have been working with her for 2 years, and this has never been an issue before. Her medical doctors state that there is no apparent medical component to this behavior. You complete a functional assessment and the behavior appears to be escape maintained. What may be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continue prompting task completion and teach how to appropriately get out of a task",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conduct a functional assessment",
                  "Recommend seeking a medical consultation",
                  "Ignore the behavior and teach her how to appropriately seek attention"
                ],
                "explanation": "Escape extinction and teaching a functionally equivalent replacement behavior are functionally based interventions."
              },
              {
                "question": "Your client engages in frequent urinary incontinence. You have been working with her for 2 years, and this has never been an issue before. Her medical doctors state that there appears to be a medical component and prescribes a medication to address a urinary tract infection. What may be your next course of action?",
                "correctAnswer": "Wait for this to be medically addressed and recommend further medical consultation if the behavior continues.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conduct a functional assessment",
                  "Ignore the behavior and teach her how to appropriately seek attention",
                  "Continue prompting task completion and teach how to appropriately get out of a task"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts recommend a medical consultation when the behavior has potential of being medically related."
              },
              {
                "question": "Who is defined as a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The individual with disabilities",
                  "Whoever funds the services",
                  "The behavior analyst"
                ],
                "explanation": "The client is whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conduct a preliminary assessment of the client in order to identify the referral problem.",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What involves a variety of methods including direct observations and other indirect measures to inform behavior change programs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct assessment",
                  "Indirect assessment",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral assessments involve a variety of methods including direct observations and other indirect measures to inform behavior change programs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are opening your own company and are looking for appropriate ways to gain clients. Which of the following is an appropriate method?",
                "correctAnswer": "Create a website with explanations of ABA strategies you use.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide a small financial incentive for referrals",
                  "Ask past clients to supply testimonials to post on your website",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts may not use incentives for referrals or use testimonials. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of indirect assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists",
                  "Standardized tests"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of indirect assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "Interviewing the client",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of direct assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis",
                  "Direct observation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of direct assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "ABC recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which assessments use information about the individual by observing the individual as the behavior occurs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct assessments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Indirect assessments",
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which assessments use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events?",
                "correctAnswer": "Indirect assessments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct assessments",
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a purpose of conducting a preliminary assessment?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Define potential target behaviors",
                  "Conduct initial functional assessment",
                  "Consider potential interventions to be used"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are purposes of conducting preliminary assessment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an assessment/test that a BCBA may conduct?",
                "correctAnswer": "Trial Based Functional Analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "IQ Test",
                  "Competency evaluation",
                  "Autism diagnosis evaluation"
                ],
                "explanation": "BCBA’s are not trained to conduct IQ tests, competency evaluations, or diagnose Autism. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Explain behavioral concepts using nontechnical language",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "When speaking to clients, parents, and other individuals in the community about behavior analysis, how should we explain behavioral principles?",
                "correctAnswer": "Using easy to understand language",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Using mentalistic explanations",
                  "Using technical language",
                  "Use technical language first, then explain it using easy to understand language, in an effort to teach them the technical language"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. "
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain “consequences” to somebody who does not understand ABA jargon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable",
                  "A stimulus change that follows a behavior of interest",
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. "
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain “consequences” to somebody who understands ABA jargon well?",
                "correctAnswer": "A stimulus change that follows a behavior of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable",
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. "
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain positive reinforcement to somebody who does not understand ABA jargon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that decreases the future frequency of the behavior.",
                  "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. "
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain positive reinforcement to somebody who understands ABA jargon well?",
                "correctAnswer": "Occurs when a behavior is followed immediately by the presentation of a stimulus that decreases the future frequency of the behavior.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior",
                  "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain the term “stimulus generalization” to somebody who does not understand ABA jargon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Being able to apply something learned in class in a different setting",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "When an antecedent stimulus has a history of evoking a response that has been reinforced in its presence, the same type of behavior tends to be evoked by stimuli that share similar physical properties with the controlling antecedent stimulus",
                  "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain the term “stimulus generalization” to somebody who understands ABA jargon well?",
                "correctAnswer": "When an antecedent stimulus has a history of evoking a response that has been reinforced in its presence, the same type of behavior tends to be evoked by stimuli that share similar physical properties with the controlling antecedent stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Something good or bad that happens after a person does something",
                  "Imposing a fine for doing something unacceptable",
                  "Being able to apply something learned in class in a different setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain the term “negative reinforcement” to somebody who does not understand ABA jargon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behaving in a way to avoid something unpleasant, like a reprimand. ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior",
                  "Being able to apply something learned in class in a different setting",
                  "The removal of a stimulus following a response, which increases the future frequency of that response"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain the term “negative reinforcement” to somebody who understands ABA jargon well?",
                "correctAnswer": "The removal of a stimulus following a response, which increases the future frequency of that response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behaving in a way to avoid something unpleasant, like a reprimand. ",
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior",
                  "Being able to apply something learned in class in a different setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How might you explain the term “extinction” to somebody who does not understand ABA jargon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reducing behavior by withholding the item or attention the person wants",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Providing rewards, attention, praise, etc. to get more of the behavior",
                  "Being able to apply something learned in class in a different setting",
                  "The discontinuing of a reinforcement of a previously reinforced behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is not our job to teach the difficult vocabulary behavior analysts use. Using every day language will be best practice to explain interventions to other people. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Describe and explain behavior, including private events, in behavior-analytic (non-mentalistic) terms",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is defined as “A fictitious or hypothetical variable that often takes the form of another name for the observed phenomenon it claims to explain and contributes nothing to a functional account of the phenomenon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Explanatory fiction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalism",
                  "Circular reasoning",
                  "Private events"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the definition of an explanatory fiction. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is an approach to explaining behavior that assumes a mental (or inner) dimension exists that differs from a behavioral dimension.",
                "correctAnswer": "Mentalism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Explanatory fiction",
                  "Circular reasoning",
                  "Private events"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the definition of mentalism. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when explaining behavior, when the description of the behavior is the same as the cause of the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Circular reasoning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Private events",
                  "Explanatory fiction",
                  "Mentalism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Circular reasoning occurs when the description of the behavior is the same as the cause of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Private event",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Circular reasoning",
                  "Explanatory fiction",
                  "Mentalism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jordan closes his eyes and “thinks” about a blue ball. Thinking about the blue ball is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Private event",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Public behavior",
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jordan closes his eyes and “thinks” about a blue ball. Closing his eyes is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Public behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Private event"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally goes into the bathroom by herself and urinates. Nobody is in the bathroom with her, and nobody can see Sally. Urinating in the bathroom is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Public behavior ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Private event"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. Although Sally was alone in the bathroom, had somebody been present, urinating would be measurable. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally’s heart is beating. Nobody is feeling her heartbeat. Sally’s heart beating is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Public behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Private event"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. Although nobody is listening to her heart beating, somebody COULD listen to her heart beat. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jordan recites the alphabet in his head. This thinking behavior is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Private event",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Public behavior",
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Molly goes in to her room all by herself and hits her head. Hitting her head is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Public behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Private event"
                ],
                "explanation": "Private events occur when the behavior is accessible only to the person engaging in the behavior. Although Molly was alone in her room, had somebody been present the COULD have seen the behavior. (Tourinho, 2006)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Provide behavior-analytic services in collaboration with others who support and/or provide services to one’s clients. ",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Who is defined as a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The individual with disabilities",
                  "Whoever funds the services",
                  "The behavior analyst"
                ],
                "explanation": "The client is whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be identified as a “client”?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The service recipient",
                  "The parent",
                  "An organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above may be identified as a client according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a principal party has a vested interest in the outcome of the interaction.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conflict of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Dual relationship",
                  "Exploitative relationships",
                  "Integrity"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a conflict of interest"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a team meeting for your client, one team member is adamant about starting a treatment that is not evidence based. What is should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated.",
                  "As the BCBA, you should not implement the treatment",
                  "Ask the team member if they have any research they could provide on the effects of the treatment."
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above would be appropriate."
              },
              {
                "question": "During a team meeting for your client, one team member is adamant about starting a treatment that is not evidence based. What is should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Tell the team that you will not be part of a team that uses non-evidence based treatments",
                  "Implement your own treatment to counteract anything that the rest of the team does."
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated."
              },
              {
                "question": "Lou is a BCBA who frequently demeans those working under him. What ethical concern is this an example of?",
                "correctAnswer": "Professional relationships",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple relationships",
                  "Conflicts of interest ",
                  "Exploitative relationships"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a concern with his professional relationships."
              },
              {
                "question": "Lou is a BCBA and his client recently gave him a gift card as a thank you for his hard work. What ethical concern is this an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Conflicts  of interest",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Professional relationships",
                  "Multiple relationships",
                  "Exploitative relationships"
                ],
                "explanation": "BCBA’s should not receive gifts. This creates a potential conflict of interest. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Lou is an ABA professor. He requires his students to promote his twitter account as part of their grade. This is an example of what ethical concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Exploitative relationships",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conflicts  of interest",
                  "Professional relationships",
                  "Multiple relationships"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of an exploitative relationship."
              },
              {
                "question": "Lou serves in his local church teaching religion classes. He is also a BCBA. He recently started providing ABA therapy with one of his students at church. This is an example of what ethical concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple relationships",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Exploitative relationships",
                  "Conflicts  of interest",
                  "Professional relationships"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of multiple relationships."
              },
              {
                "question": "While providing ABA services to a young lady, Lou has begun dating her. This is an example of what ethical concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple relationships",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Exploitative relationships",
                  "Conflicts  of interest",
                  "Professional relationships"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of multiple relationships."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Practice within one’s limits of professional competence in applied behavior analysis, and obtain consultation, supervision, and training, or make referrals as necessary",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are opening your own company and are looking for appropriate ways to gain clients. Which of the following is an appropriate method?",
                "correctAnswer": "Create a website with explanations of ABA strategies you use.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide a small financial incentive for referrals",
                  "Ask past clients to supply testimonials to post on your website",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts may not use incentives for referrals or use testimonials. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is given by the BACB stating you are competent to practice as a behavior analyst.",
                "correctAnswer": "Certification",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Licensure",
                  "BCBA",
                  "Master’s degree"
                ],
                "explanation": "Certification is given by the BACB stating you are competent to practice as a behavior analyst. This process does not involve the law from where you reside. "
              },
              {
                "question": "This is given by the local government usually involving the BACB as well. This restricts who can call themselves different titles and places legal parameters on how you can practice.",
                "correctAnswer": "Licensure",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Certification",
                  "BCBA",
                  "Master’s degree"
                ],
                "explanation": "Licensure is given by the local government usually involving the BACB as well. This restricts who can call themselves different titles and places legal parameters on how you can practice."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following can the BACB do if the ethical standards are violated, or the individual is deemed not competent to practice as a behavior analyst?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deny initial certification",
                  "Revoke certification",
                  "Suspend certification"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB may deny initial certification, revoke certification, or suspend certification"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following can the BACB do if the ethical standards are violated, or the individual is deemed not competent to practice as a behavior analyst?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deny initial certification",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Revoke License",
                  "imprisonment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB may deny initial certification, revoke certification, or suspend certification"
              },
              {
                "question": "What determines if a behavior analyst is competent to work with a specific client?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Education",
                  "Training",
                  "Supervised experience"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to the ethical code 1.02 behavior analysts only practice within the boundaries of the competence defined as being commensurate with their education, training, and supervised experience. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph wants to start practicing Organizational Behavior Management by consulting with companies in the private sector. He has read several books on the matter, but is lacking experience and training in OBM. What should Joseph do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Seek out a mentor with more experience that may be able to supervise his work.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Learn as he goes. He may begin practicing and learn from his mistakes.",
                  "Do not practice OBM without experience.",
                  "Reading several books is sufficient to practice OBM effectively and ethically. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Seek out a mentor with more experience that may be able to supervise his work."
              },
              {
                "question": "Phillip is recommended to implement a treatment that is lacking research. There is one article he found that has promising results. The strategy does not have a high risk of being harmful to his client. What should Phillip do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Consider a more established treatment. If the situation is unique, and other treatments do not apply, it would be appropriate to conduct research and further the literature on the treatment.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Do not implement the treatment",
                  "Refer the client to another person with more experience",
                  "Use a more established treatment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts rely on scientific knowledge and conduct research to further that knowledge."
              },
              {
                "question": "How do behavior analysts maintain knowledge of current scientific information?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reading appropriate literature",
                  "Attending conferences",
                  "Participating in workshops"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts do all of the above to maintain knowledge of current scientific information."
              },
              {
                "question": "How do behavior analysts maintain knowledge of current scientific information?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reading journal articles",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Reading mainstream news articles",
                  "Reading fiction novels"
                ],
                "explanation": "Journal articles should be a source of knowledge for behavior analysts."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Identify and make environmental changes that reduce the need for behavior analysis services",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Mary is a BCBA serving several clients in her area. Due to a family emergency she needs to relocate to another state for several months. Mary should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not abandon the clients without ensuring the cases are transferred",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Do what she needs to do in emergency situations",
                  "Inform the clients that she may be able to continue services in a few months when she returns.",
                  "Resolve the family situation first, and then decide later on what to do with the caseload."
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary should do everything possible to ensure the cases are transferred to a qualified replacement."
              },
              {
                "question": "When would be an appropriate time to discontinue services with a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The client requests discontinuation of services",
                  "Is not benefitting from the service",
                  "Is being harmed by the service"
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to discontinue services for all of the reasons listed above. "
              },
              {
                "question": "When would be an appropriate time to discontinue services with a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "The client has met the measurable objectives laid out at the onset of services",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior analyst is sick, and will be unable to work for several days",
                  "All of the above",
                  "The client has met one of the two measureable objectives laid out at the onset of services."
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to discontinue services if the client has met the measurable objectives laid out at the onset of services"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hired to consult with a young boy who engages in frequent hitting. His mother wants you to help the boy learn not to hit. What might be the criterion you set to discontinue services?",
                "correctAnswer": "When the boy has gone 2 weeks without engaging in any hitting",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "When the boy has gone 12 months without engaging in any hitting",
                  "When the boy is no longer aggressive",
                  "With the boy has progressed to the point to where services are no longer needed."
                ],
                "explanation": "There needs to be set criteria that includes a reasonable amount of time."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with Ella who engages in frequent tantrums. You have worked with her for 12 months and have not seen any progress. You have changed the behavior intervention plan multiple times, but they haven’t seemed to help the behavior. What could you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Refer the client to another behavior analyst who may have more experience",
                  "Recommend seeking a medical consultation.",
                  "Attend a conference or workshop addressing Ella’s specific needs"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above would be appropriate."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with Ella who engages in frequent tantrums. You have worked with her for 12 months and have not seen any progress. You have changed the behavior intervention plan multiple times, but they haven’t seemed to help the behavior. What could you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Refer the client to another behavior analyst who may have more experience",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Seek out a mental health diagnosis",
                  "Immediately terminate services"
                ],
                "explanation": "Refer the client to someone who may have more experience with similar situations."
              },
              {
                "question": "Joey is sleeping well and no longer engaging in angry outbursts. He has met the criteria established at the onset of services to discontinue services. As the behavior analyst, what do you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Terminate services by slowly fading all behavioral interventions you are providing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Immediately terminate services once the criteria are met",
                  " Look for more behaviors that would benefit from your services",
                  "Ask Joey if he wants you to leave or stay working with him"
                ],
                "explanation": "Terminate services once he has met the established criteria by slowly fading all behavioral interventions."
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "State the nature of the services provided",
                  "State the fees or charges",
                  "State the identity of the provider"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above should be included."
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the nature of the services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "A record of billing from the past 12 months",
                  "An increase in you fees each year"
                ],
                "explanation": "The billing report should state the nature of the services provided."
              },
              {
                "question": "Adam is receiving behavior analysis services, but is unhappy with the service you provide. He asks for termination of services. What do you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Terminate services",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide data to show the positive effect of your services",
                  "Provide a termination of services fee to deter him from terminating services",
                  "Provide a list of testimonials of satisfied consumers"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is appropriate to terminate services as requested by the client. "
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Measurement",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Select a measurement system to obtain representative data given the dimensions of the behavior and the logistics of observing and recording",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Frequency is:",
                "correctAnswer": "A simple count of the total occurrences of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The number of occurrences of the behavior across time",
                  "The amount of time from the discriminative stimulus to the occurrence of the behavior",
                  "The amount of time between occurrences of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Many refer to “Rate” as synonymous to Frequency, but according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List, Frequency and Rate are separate measures. “Frequency” is synonymous with “Count”."
              },
              {
                "question": "Select the word the means the same as “Count”",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "Latency",
                  "Inter-response time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Frequency is defined as a simple count of the total occurrences of behavior, which is different from Rate, according to the BACB Fourth Edition Task List. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Frequency across time is referred to as",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Frequency",
                  "Inter-response time"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is defined as the number of responses per unit of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },              {
                "question": "John is a BCBA wanting to measure how often George engages in tongue clicking. What would be an appropriate measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trials to Criterion",
                  "Frequency (Count)",
                  "Latency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is usually the best measure for free operant behaviors. .(Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Duration is based on which measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal Extent",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Locus",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Repeatability AND Temporal Locus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is based on the measureable dimension of behavior “Temporal Extent”. Temporal extent explains that every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeremy engages in on task behavior for extended periods of time. Which measure would be most beneficial to use to measure this behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "IRT",
                  "Frequency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is usually the best measure for continuous behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Latency is defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "The amount of time between the stimulus and the response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Count per unit of time",
                  "Amount of time in which a behavior occurs",
                  "The amount of time between two responses"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After 3.5 seconds of prompting Mary, she finally got up and placed her dishes in the dishwasher, which took her 6 seconds to complete. In this scenario 3.5 seconds refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Latency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Duration",
                  "Inter-Response Time",
                  "Percent of compliance"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is defined as the amount of time between the stimulus and the response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response?",
                "correctAnswer": "IRT",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Rate",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is defined as the amount of time that occurs between two consecutive instances of a response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Calculate the percent of occurrence of completed tasks for John. He was prompted to complete 20 different tasks and refused only 3 times. He complied following all other prompts. ",
                "correctAnswer": "85%",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "15%",
                  "17",
                  "3"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percent of occurrence is defined as a ratio formed by combining the same dimensional quantities (i.e., Duration ÷ Duration). (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select a schedule of observation and recording periods",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a continuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Time Sampling",
                  "Planned Activity Check"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording and Timing are common procedures used when collecting continuous measurement data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a continuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Timing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time sampling",
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "PLACHECK"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording and Timing are common procedures used when collecting continuous measurement data. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Wrist counters, hand-tally digital counters, tally marks, are all devices that can be used with which measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Timing",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "Whole-Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Wrist counters, digital counters, or simple tally marks on paper can all be used with event recording procedures. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stopwatches/timers are necessary for which measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Timing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "Whole-Interval Recording",
                  "Event Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Timing measurement procedures require a device to track time for accurate time measures. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “no” if the behavior does not occur throughout the entire session.",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole Interval Recording is when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this discontinuous measurement procedure, the observer marks “no” if the behavior did not occur at all during the session. If there were any occurrences they mark “yes”.",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial Interval Recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Momentary Time Sampling",
                  "PLACHECK",
                  "Whole Interval Recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording occurs when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a 10 second interval, Ruby engages in disruptive behavior twice for 5 seconds total duration. Using a whole interval recording procedure, what would be marked on the data sheet?",
                "correctAnswer": "“no”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "“yes”",
                  "5 seconds",
                  "2"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole Interval Recording is when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs during the entire session observed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a 10 second interval, Ruby engages in disruptive behavior twice for 5 seconds total duration. Using a partial interval recording procedure, what would be marked on the data sheet?",
                "correctAnswer": " “yes”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "“no”",
                  "5 seconds",
                  "2"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording occurs when the observer marks “yes” when the behavior occurs at all during the entire session. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the physical shape or form of a behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Topography",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Magnitude",
                  "Response class",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Topography is defined as the physical shape or form of a behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the force or intensity with which a response is emitted.",
                "correctAnswer": "Magnitude",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Topography",
                  "Response class",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Magnitude is defined as the force or intensity with which a response is emitted. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select a data display that effectively communicates relevant quantitative relations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is the most commonly used graphic display used by behavior analysts?",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Line graphs are most commonly used. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line.",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Line graphs allow for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This graph is also referred to as a histogram",
                "correctAnswer": "Bar graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The bar graph is also called a histogram. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled.",
                "correctAnswer": "Bar graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The bar graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph was developed by Skinner to collect data in the experimental analysis of behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Cumulative record",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The cumulative record was developed by Skinner. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation.",
                "correctAnswer": "Cumulative record",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The cumulative record displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a semilogarithmic chart?",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph"
                ],
                "explanation": "The standard celeration chart is a semilogarithmic chart. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments.",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph"
                ],
                "explanation": "The standard celeration chart is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to discover the temporal distribution of a target behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Evaluate changes in level, trend, and variability",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the extent to which multiple measures of behavior yield different outcomes.",
                "correctAnswer": "Variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trend",
                  "Level",
                  "Number of data Points"
                ],
                "explanation": "Variability is defined as the extent to which multiple measures of behavior yield different outcomes."
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the value on the vertical axis scale around which a set of behavioral measures converge.",
                "correctAnswer": "Level",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Trend",
                  "Variability",
                  "Number of data points"
                ],
                "explanation": "Level is defined as the value on the vertical axis scale around which a set of behavioral measures converge."
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the overall direction taken by a data path.",
                "correctAnswer": "Trend",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Level",
                  "Variability",
                  "Number of data points"
                ],
                "explanation": "Trend is defined as the overall direction taken by a data path. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the Trend of the following line graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Decreasing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High variability",
                  "Zero Trend",
                  "Low variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be decreasing."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the variability of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "High variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Not determinable",
                  "Low variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to highly variable"
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the trend of the following graph: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Zero trend",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing",
                  "High variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to have zero trend."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the variability of the following graph: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Low variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High variability",
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to have low variability."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the level of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not determinable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Zero trend"
                ],
                "explanation": "Level is only determinable if given the value of the data points, or in comparison to another line."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the trend of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Increasing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Low variability",
                  "Zero trend"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be increasing."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is the most accurate visual analysis of this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Increasing/low variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing/low variability",
                  "Increasing/high variability",
                  "Decreasing/high variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be increasing and low variability."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Evaluate temporal relations between observed variables",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Rate is measured using which measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Repeatability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Temporal locus",
                  "Temporal locus AND temporal extent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is based on the measurable dimension of behavior “Repeatability”. Repeatability states that instance of a response class can occur repeatedly through time. You can count behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The measurable dimension of behavior “repeatability” can be defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Instances of behavior can occur repeatedly through time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior occurs during time",
                  "Every instance of behavior occurs at a certain point in time",
                  "Behavior always repeats if it has happened before"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is based on the measurable dimension of behavior “Repeatability”. Repeatability states that instance of a response class can occur repeatedly through time. You can count behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Duration is based on which measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal Extent",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Locus",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Repeatability AND Temporal Locus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is based on the measureable dimension of behavior “Temporal Extent”. Temporal extent explains that every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Temporal Extent is defined as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Instances of behavior can occur repeatedly through time",
                  "Every instance of behavior occurs at a certain point in time",
                  "Behavior is temporary"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration is based on the measureable dimension of behavior “Temporal Extent”. Temporal extent explains that every instance of behavior occurs during some amount of time. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Define Temporal Locus",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior occurs during some amount of time",
                  "Behavior can occur repeatedly.",
                  "Behavior always occurs after an antecedent."
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is based on the dimension “Temporal Locus” Temporal locus refers to that behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Latency is based on which dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal Locus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Extent",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Temporal Extent AND Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is based on the dimension “Temporal Locus” Temporal locus refers to that behavior occurs at a certain point in time with respect to other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "IRT is based on which dimension of behavior? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal locus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Temporal extent AND Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "IRT is based on the dimension ”temporal locus”. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of behavior is used when reporting a percentage?",
                "correctAnswer": "None",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal Extent",
                  "Temporal Locus",
                  "Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Percentages use ratios of the same dimensional quantity. The dimensional quantity is canceled out in the ratio equation and no longer contains those dimensional quantities. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to discover the temporal distribution of a target behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Assessment",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Define Behavior in observable and measurable terms",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This type of behavioral definition identifies responses as members of the targeted response class solely by their common effect on the environment.",
                "correctAnswer": "Function-based definition",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Topography-based definition",
                  "Target behavior definition",
                  "Social validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Function-based definitions identify responses as members of the targeted response class solely by their common effect on the environment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of behavioral definition identifies responses by the shape or form of the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Topography-based definition",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Function-based definition",
                  "Target behavior definition",
                  "Social validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Topography based definitions identify responses by the shape or form of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is the best example of an observable and measurable behavioral definition?",
                "correctAnswer": "Hitting any person with an open hand or closed fist",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Getting upset",
                  "Hitting ",
                  "Engaging in an angry outburst"
                ],
                "explanation": "“hitting any person with an open hand or closed fist” is the best example of an observable and measurable behavioral definition. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is the best example of an observable and measurable behavioral definition?",
                "correctAnswer": "Any occurrence of making self-disparaging remarks or threats of harming himself.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Being depressed",
                  "Showing depressive symptoms congruent with a diagnosis of major depressive disorder",
                  "Showing signs of depression or other emotional instability"
                ],
                "explanation": "“Any occurrence of making self-disparaging remarks or threats of harming himself” is the best answer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following will strengthen a behavioral definition?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Examples ",
                  "Non-examples",
                  "Data collection guidelines such as an onset and offset of the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above would be correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a client, trying to increase the occurrences of appropriate requests when they ask for an item. What might be the behavioral definition for this behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Defined as Mary naming the item she wants as well as saying “please”.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Defined as Mary having proper manners when requesting an item.",
                  "Defined as Mary being polite when wanting an item.",
                  "Defined as Mary showing manners by asking nicely for items with which she wants."
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary naming the item she wants as well as saying “please” is the most observable and measurable definition provided. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a purpose of writing observable and measurable behavioral definitions?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To ensure inter-observer agreement is high with data collection",
                  "To encompass the entire behavior of concern",
                  "To ensure that contingencies are delivered at appropriate times (when contingent on said behavior)"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a purpose of writing observable and measurable behavioral definitions?",
                "correctAnswer": "To ensure inter-observer agreement is high with data collection",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "To help create standardized behavioral definitions across the field of ABA.",
                  "To prevent reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "One purpose of writing observable and measureable behavioral definitions is that it helps to ensure inter-observer agreement is high with data collection. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavioral definitions should be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Individualized so the definition encompasses all relevant behaviors of concern",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Standardized to increase the likelihood of exact replications in research",
                  "Fluid, meaning open to interpretation for data collectors.",
                  "Concise, even if that means leaving out relevant responses often of concern."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral definitions should be individualized so the definition encompasses all relevant behaviors of concern. Although concise definitions are easier to understand, it is best for them to be concise, yet contain all relevant responses often of concern. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tray engages in encopresis, where he will defecate all around his house. What is missing from the following behavioral definition?\n“Defined as Tray defecating anywhere other than the toilet. Frequency of this behavior will be tracked by marking a tally after every occurrence of Tray engaging in the behavior.”",
                "correctAnswer": "Add examples and non-examples",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Nothing",
                  "There needs to be a more observable definition",
                  "The definition needs to be more individualized to Tray’s circumstances."
                ],
                "explanation": "Examples and non-examples may improve this behavioral definition. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Define environmental variables in observable and measurable terms",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which conditioned motivating operation is created by being paired with an unconditioned motivating operation, gaining the same behavior-altering effects as that UMO?",
                "correctAnswer": "Surrogate CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexive CMO",
                  "Transitive CMO",
                  "None of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Surrogate CMO’s are created by being paired with an unconditioned motivating operation, gaining the same behavior-altering effects as that UMO. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How can you weaken the effects of surrogate CMOs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Unpairing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction & Unpairing",
                  "Weaken the MO related to the end of the behavior sequence",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unpairing will weaken the effects of a surrogate CMO. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which conditioned motivating operation precedes the onset of painful stimulation and functions as a warning stimulus?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexive CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Surrogate CMO",
                  "Transitive CMO",
                  "None of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexive CMOs precede the onset of painful stimulation and functions as a warning stimulus. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How can you weaken the effects of a Reflexive CMO?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction & unpairing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unpairing",
                  "Weaken the MO related to the end of the behavior sequence",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction and unpairing will weaken the effects of a CMO-R. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which conditioned motivating operation involves UMOs functioning as both a UMO and a CMO for consecutive contingencies?",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitive CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Surrogate CMO",
                  "Reflexive CMO",
                  "None of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitive CMOs involve UMOs functioning as both a UMO and a CMO for consecutive contingencies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "How can you weaken the effects of a transitive CMO?",
                "correctAnswer": "Weaken the MO related to the end of the behavior sequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction & unpairing",
                  "Unpairing",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "CMO-Ts are weakened by weakening the MO related to the end of the behavior sequence. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Philip was diagnosed with anxiety. He frequently engages in finger rubbing to the point for causing blisters on his thumb and index finger. After conducting a functional assessment, it was determined that finger rubbing typically results in Phillip receiving hugs from his family in an effort to calm him down. It has been established by a functional analysis that this is reinforcing finger rubbing. Why is Philip engaging in finger rubbing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Philip’s finger rubbing appears to be reinforced by receiving attention from his family such as them giving him hugs. Although, there may be other contingencies at play.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Philip’s finger rubbing appears to be a product of high anxiety, mixed with his family reinforcing the behavior by giving him hugs.",
                  "Anxiety is likely causing the behavior.",
                  "Being in stressful situations appear to be causing the behavior. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Although diagnoses may give a description of some behaviors, behavior analysts do not use diagnoses to explain why behavior occurs."
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when explaining behavior, when the description of the behavior is the same as the cause of the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Circular reasoning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Private events",
                  "Explanatory fiction",
                  "Mentalism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Circular reasoning occurs when the description of the behavior is the same as the cause of the behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is defined as “A fictitious or hypothetical variable that often takes the form of another name for the observed phenomenon it claims to explain and contributes nothing to a functional account of the phenomenon?",
                "correctAnswer": "Explanatory fiction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalism",
                  "Circular reasoning",
                  "Private events"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the definition of an explanatory fiction. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank engages in self-injurious behavior. He was recently diagnosed with depression. You conducted a functional assessment and have found that the behavior typically occurs when there is a lack of social interaction, and usually results in receiving high quality attention. You verify this with a functional analysis. What is “causing” Frank’s self-injurious behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "A lack of attention appears to evoke this behavior, and it typically results in receiving high quality attention.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Attention",
                  "Frank’s recent diagnosis of depression is probably a contributing factor to why this behavior is going on.",
                  "Automatic reinforcement."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts do not use diagnoses as explanations of behavior. The answer “attention” is too simple in that it does not explain the stimuli changes surrounding the behavior."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and implement individualized behavioral assessment procedures. Conduct a preliminary assessment of the client in order to identify the referral problem.",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What involves a variety of methods including direct observations and other indirect measures to inform behavior change programs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct assessment",
                  "Indirect assessment",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral assessments involve a variety of methods including direct observations and other indirect measures to inform behavior change programs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of indirect assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists",
                  "Standardized tests"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of indirect assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "Interviewing the client",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of direct assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis",
                  "Direct observation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a form of direct assessments?",
                "correctAnswer": "ABC recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which assessments use information about the individual by observing the individual as the behavior occurs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Direct assessments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Indirect assessments",
                  "Interviews",
                  "Checklists"
                ],
                "explanation": "Direct assessments are those which use information about the individual as it occurs. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which assessments use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events?",
                "correctAnswer": "Indirect assessments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Direct assessments",
                  "ABC recording",
                  "Functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Indirect assessments are those which use data derived from recollections, or subjective ratings of events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an assessment/test that a BCBA may conduct?",
                "correctAnswer": "Trial Based Functional Analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "IQ Test",
                  "Competency evaluation",
                  "Autism diagnosis evaluation"
                ],
                "explanation": "BCBA’s are not trained to conduct IQ tests, competency evaluations, or diagnose Autism. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This behavioral assessment is a systematic method of assessment for obtaining information about the purposes a problem behavior serves for a person.",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional behavior assessment ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional analysis",
                  "Direct assessment",
                  "Indirect assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "A functional behavior assessment is a systematic method of assessment for obtaining information about the purposes a problem behavior serves for a person. A functional analysis is a type of functional behavior assessment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During this behavioral assessment antecedents and consequences representing those in the individual’s natural environment are experimentally arranged as to determine behavioral function.",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional behavior assessment",
                  "Direct assessment",
                  "Indirect assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "A functional analysis is a behavior assessment in which antecedents and consequences representing those in the individual’s natural environment are experimentally arranged as to determine behavioral function. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and implement the full range of functional assessment procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What are the four functions of behavior that are widely accepted as behavioral functions in applied behavior analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Escape, Access, Automatic, Attention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Attention, Tangible, Escape, Access",
                  "Automatic, Tangible, Escape, Access",
                  "Attention, Automatic, Access, Tangible"
                ],
                "explanation": "Escape, Access (tangible), automatic, attention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You received a new client and are conducting a functional behavior assessment. You just gathered information through indirect and descriptive assessment. What should you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Interpret information for indirect and descriptive assessment and create a hypothesis regarding behavior function.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Gather information through indirect and descriptive assessment",
                  "Test hypothesis using a functional analysis",
                  "Develop intervention options based on the function of problem behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "You should interpret the findings of the indirect and descriptive assessment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You just received a new client, and are conducting a functional behavior assessment. What should you do first?",
                "correctAnswer": "Gather information through indirect and descriptive assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Interpret information for indirect and descriptive assessment and create a hypothesis regarding behavior function.",
                  "Test hypothesis using a functional analysis",
                  "Develop intervention options based on the function of problem behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "You should gather information through indirect and descriptive assessment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You just received a new client and are conducting a functional behavior assessment. You just gathered and interpreted data using indirect and descriptive assessment. You have a hypothesis of the function of the behavior. What should you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Test hypothesis using a functional analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Gather information through indirect and descriptive assessment",
                  "Interpret information for indirect and descriptive assessment and create a hypothesis regarding behavior function.",
                  "Develop intervention options based on the function of problem behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "You should test the hypothesis using a functional analysis. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You just received a new client and are conducting a functional behavior assessment. You tested your hypothesized function of the behavior, and received strong results. What should you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Develop intervention options based on the function of problem behavior.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Test hypothesis using a functional analysis",
                  "Gather information through indirect and descriptive assessment",
                  "Interpret information for indirect and descriptive assessment and create a hypothesis regarding behavior function."
                ],
                "explanation": "You should develop and select and intervention option based on the function of problem behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },              {
                "question": "During a standard functional analysis, which condition is used as a baseline to compare to the test conditions?",
                "correctAnswer": "Control condition",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingent attention",
                  "Contingent escape",
                  "Alone"
                ],
                "explanation": "You should always use a control condition in a functional analysis to compare to the other test trials. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which term is synonymous with the term “Analog assessment”",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional behavior assessment",
                  "Descriptive assessment",
                  "Indirect assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "An analog assessment (or analogue) is synonymous with the term “functional analysis”. (Cipani & Schock, 2011)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is an advantage of functional analyses?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provides a clear demonstration of variables that relate to problem behavior",
                  "Widely researched and reported in journal articles",
                  "reduces the need for and use of punishment procedures"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are advantages. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which is NOT a disadvantage of functional analyses?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reduces the need for and use of punishment procedures",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "May strengthen problem behavior",
                  "May evoke dangerous behavior",
                  "Requires large amounts of time and effort"
                ],
                "explanation": "Functional analyses may reduce the need for and use of punishment procedures. This is an advantage of functional analyses. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not an advantage of functional analyses?",
                "correctAnswer": "Requires professional expertise and training to conduct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provides a clear demonstration of variables that relate to problem behavior",
                  "Widely researched and reported in journal articles",
                  "reduces the need for and use of punishment procedures"
                ],
                "explanation": "Requiring professional expertise and training to conduct a functional analysis is a weakness. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Organize, analyze, and interpret observed data",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You recently began implementing a new reinforcement program for teaching your client appropriate responses. You conducted a reversal to test the effectiveness. According to this graph, what should you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Implement the treatment again",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continue with baseline",
                  "Try a different treatment",
                  "Conduct a new functional behavior assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Implement the treatment again"
              },
              {
                "question": "You recently began implementing a new reinforcement program for teaching your client appropriate responses. You conducted a reversal to test the effectiveness. According to this graph, what should you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continue implementing the treatment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Return to baseline",
                  "Try a different treatment",
                  "Conduct a new functional behavior assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Continue implementing the treatment."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the Trend of the following line graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Decreasing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High variability",
                  "Zero Trend",
                  "Low variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be decreasing."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the variability of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "High variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Not determinable",
                  "Low variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to highly variable"
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the trend of the following graph: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Zero trend",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing",
                  "High variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to have zero trend."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the variability of the following graph: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Low variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High variability",
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to have low variability."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the level of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not determinable",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Increasing",
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Zero trend"
                ],
                "explanation": "Level is only determinable if given the value of the data points, or in comparison to another line."
              },
              {
                "question": "Describe the trend of the following graph:",
                "correctAnswer": "Increasing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing",
                  "Low variability",
                  "Zero trend"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be increasing."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is the most accurate visual analysis of this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Increasing/low variability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Decreasing/low variability",
                  "Increasing/high variability",
                  "Decreasing/high variability"
                ],
                "explanation": "This graph appears to be increasing and low variability."
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the BACB’s ethical code, how long are behavior analysts to keep records?",
                "correctAnswer": "7 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                  "Until termination of services",
                  "5 years (and as otherwise required by law)"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB requires that records be stored for at least 7 years and as otherwise required by law. This is according to the BACB “Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analyst” section 2.11."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Make recommendations regarding behaviors that must be established, maintained, increased, or decreased",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are working with a client who wants to lose weight. Why might you not select “weight” as the behavior of interest?",
                "correctAnswer": "Weight is not a behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Weight loss is ineffective when the person focusses on weight",
                  "Weight loss is out of the competency of practice for behavior analysts",
                  "Focusing on weight will only make the person hungrier."
                ],
                "explanation": "Weight is not a behavior. Focusing on other behaviors such as exercise and eating healthy will be more beneficial, however measuring weight may be used to show the positive effects of improved healthy behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior that when changed, exposes the individual to new environments and contingencies.",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pivotal behavior",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a behavioral cusp. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior, that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Pivotal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral cusp",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A pivotal behavior is on that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Teaching an individual self-management skills which results in the learner engaging in untrained behaviors, is an example of what kind of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Pivotal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral cusp",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A pivotal behavior is on that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A child learns how to walk, and now is able to come into contact with new contingencies that were unavailable until they could walk. This is an example of what kind of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pivotal behavior",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A behavioral cusp is a behavior that when changed, exposes the individual to new environments and contingencies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a question to ask yourself when selecting a target behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Does this behavior match my research interests?",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Is this behavior likely to produce reinforcement in the client’s natural environment after treatment ends?",
                  "Is this behavior a behavioral cusp?",
                  "Is this an age appropriate behavior?"
                ],
                "explanation": "When working with a client, it would not be appropriate to select a behavior simply because of a research interest. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a question to ask yourself when selecting a target behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Which behavior, if addressed, will make your job easiest?",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "What adaptive behavior will replace the problem behavior?",
                  "Does this behavior represent the actual problem or goal?",
                  "Does this behavior cause any danger to the client or others?"
                ],
                "explanation": "The questions should revolve around the client’s needs, not the behavior analyst’s preferences. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Suzy’s support team set a goal for her to be able to read. However, recently she has been engaging in cursing as well as suicidal behavior. Which behavior should be the targeted first?",
                "correctAnswer": "Suicidal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reading",
                  "Cursing",
                  "All three behaviors at once"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behaviors that may cause harm to the client or others need to be addressed first. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Suzy has struggled for years with bullying other people. Just yesterday a new behavior arose. Suzy called somebody 6 times in a row on the telephone. Which target behavior should be of priority?",
                "correctAnswer": "Bullying",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Excessive phone calling",
                  "Both",
                  "Neither"
                ],
                "explanation": "behaviors of concern that have been a problem longer take precedence over randomly occurring behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This effect on behavior occurs when an assessment procedure affects the behavior being assessed. Suzy knows a BCBA is doing an assessment, so her behavior changes.",
                "correctAnswer": "Reactivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Type I error",
                  "Type II error",
                  "Extinction burst"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reactivity occurs when  an assessment procedure affects the behavior being assessed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and conduct preference assessments to identify putative reinforcers",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Stimulus Preference Assessments are used to identify:",
                "correctAnswer": "Appetitive Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Aversive Stimuli",
                  "Reinforcers",
                  "Punishers"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus preference assessments are used to identify preferred (appetitive) stimuli. Appetitive stimuli are not always reinforcers."
              },
              {
                "question": "All of the following are trial based methods for determining preferred stimuli EXCEPT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free Operant Observation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free operant observation can be used to determine preferred stimuli, but it is not trial based. Single stimulus, paired stimuli, and multiple stimuli are all trial based methods."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, stimuli are measure consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents a stuffed toy and measures how long the individual interacts with the toy. The BCBA removes the stuffed toy and presents a backpack and measures the interaction with the item. The BCBA removes the backpack and presents a spinner toy. What type of preference is the BCBA conducting?",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, 2 stimuli are presented to the individual, creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents the child with a stuffed toy and a fidget spinner, and the child selects the fidget spinner. The BCBA then presents a fidget spinner and a backpack, and the child selects the fidget spinner. This is done repeatedly, varying the pairing of items. What type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": " Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA places the item back into the array of items. The BCBA says “choose one” again. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA removes that item from sight. The BCBA says “choose one” again with only the remaining 5 items displayed. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Intervention",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "State intervention goals in observable and measurable terms",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are teaching a class and creating objectives for your students. Which of the following is the best example of class objectives using observable and measurable terms?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the definitions of positive and negative reinforcement and use these principles in behavioral interventions",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Learn principles of applied behavior analysis",
                  "Understand definitions of positive and negative reinforcement and know how to use them in behavioral interventions",
                  "Understand principles of applied behavior analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intervention goals should be observable and measurable. Using the words “understand” or “learn” makes the behavior difficult to measure and observe. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with Jim who frequently engages in angry outbursts. What would be the best example of an intervention goal to address this concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Decrease the frequency of angry outbursts (as defined in the behavior definition) to three or fewer angry outbursts per session for 3 consecutive sessions.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Defined as not yelling, not shouting, not swearing, and not engaging in any property destruction.",
                  "Remaining calm during 3 consecutive sessions",
                  "To no longer engage in angry outbursts "
                ],
                "explanation": "”Decrease the frequency of angry outbursts (as defined in the behavior definition) to three or fewer angry outbursts per session for 3 consecutive session” is the most appropriate intervention goal. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Intervention goals need to be established:",
                "correctAnswer": "Before the intervention begins",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Once the intervention is in place",
                  "Once the intervention is effective",
                  "When determining the termination of services"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intervention goals need to be established before the intervention begins. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is extremely disruptive in class, and does not accomplish essential tasks during the school day. Which would be the best intervention goal for Mary?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mary will engage in fewer than 3 disruptive behaviors each day (as defined in the behavioral definition), and will complete 80% of assigned tasks each day for five consecutive school days.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mary will learn to no longer disrupt the class and will accomplish all necessary tasks every day.",
                  "Mary will receive rewards for task completion. A DRO will be used to reinforce the nonoccurrence of disruptive behaviors.",
                  "Mary will engage in essential tasks during the school day and will no longer be disruptive during class. "
                ],
                "explanation": "“Mary will engage in fewer than 3 disruptive behaviors each day (as defined in the behavioral definition), and will complete 80% of assigned tasks each day for five consecutive school days”, is the best goal out of those options. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Prior to starting an intervention, what needs to take place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Intervention goals need to be established",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The client must decide which interventions would be best suited for themselves",
                  "The client will be quizzed on the intervention to ensure they understand the concepts",
                  "Intervention data will be graphed and analyzed"
                ],
                "explanation": "Before starting an intervention, intervention goals need to be established. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Before implementing a behavior change program, what must the behavior analyst do?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Establish intervention goals",
                  "Describe the objectives of the interventions to the client",
                  "A risk-benefit analysis should be conducted on the procedures to be implemented to reach the objective."
                ],
                "explanation": "All of these are discussed in the Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts. Section 4.05"
              },
              {
                "question": "Anytime new interventions are used, or new goals are established, what should take place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Must obtain written approval from the client",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Must submit the documents to be reviewed in a peer review",
                  "Must bill the client for each separate intervention to ensure the BCBA is not wasting their time",
                  "The client must submit a written review of their progress to the BACB."
                ],
                "explanation": "Anytime new interventions are used, or new goals are established, you must obtain written approval from the client. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts. Section 4.04"
              },
              {
                "question": "You consult with a family about their young child, and determine that their current living situation would not permit the effective implementation of a behavior support plan. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Recommend that other professional assistance be sought (Therapeutic interventions, consultation, or further assessment)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "If anyone can make a change, it would be a behavior analyst. You should do your best given their current environment.",
                  "Recommend a medical consultation",
                  "You should assist them, however, using this as a research opportunity could improve the situation."
                ],
                "explanation": "“Recommend that other professional assistance be sought (Therapeutic interventions, consultation, or further assessment)” is described in the Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts. Section 4.07. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This refers to the extent to which the behavior goal(s) and targeted behavior(s) will make a positive influence on the individual’s life.",
                "correctAnswer": "Social validity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Internal validity",
                  "External validity",
                  "Reactivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Social validity refers to the extent to which the behavior goal(s) and targeted behavior(s) will make a positive influence on the individual’s life. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are teaching a class and creating objectives for your students. Which of the following is the best example of class objectives using observable and measurable terms?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the definitions of extinction and differential reinforcement and use these principles in behavioral interventions",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Learn principles of applied behavior analysis",
                  "Understand definitions of extinction and differential reinforcement and know how to use them in behavioral interventions",
                  "Understand principles of applied behavior analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intervention goals should be observable and measurable. Using the words “understand” or “learn” makes the behavior difficult to measure and observe. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Identify potential interventions based on assessment results and the best available scientific evidence",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with attention as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Planned ignore",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continue to prompt the client to complete their assignment even when problem behavior occurs.",
                  "Differentially reinforce the absence of the target behavior",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Planned ignore is the only intervention listed above that is based on the function of the behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with attention as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Conduct social skills training to teach the client a more appropriate way to gain attention",
                  "Reinforce every occurrence of the client engaging in appropriate attention seeking"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are function based interventions that appear to be appropriate to implement."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with escape from schoolwork as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continue to prompt the client to complete their schoolwork even when problem behavior occurs",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Reinforce every occurrence of the client engaging in appropriate attention seeking"
                ],
                "explanation": "Escape extinction would be the most appropriate intervention out of the provided options."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with escape from schoolwork as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continue to prompt the client to complete their schoolwork even when problem behavior occurs",
                  "Allow the client to take breaks from the task whenever they ask appropriately",
                  "Reduce demands placed on the client"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are function based interventions that would be appropriate to implement."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional behavior assessment and identify that your client engages in property destruction with access to a preferred item as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Frequent and time-based access to the preferred item",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Restrict the preferred item to only being given to the client for 2 minutes each day",
                  "Provide frequent attention throughout the day on a time-based schedule",
                  "Planned ignore"
                ],
                "explanation": "An NCR is an appropriate function based antecedent intervention. In this scenario, delivering the item frequently and non-contingently would be an appropriate intervention."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional behavior assessment and identify that your client engages in property destruction with access to a preferred item as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequent and time-based access to the preferred item",
                  "Functional communication training",
                  "Ensure the client does not gain access to the item immediately following the inappropriate behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are function based interventions that would be appropriate to implement for this scenario."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and the results indicated that the thumb sucking occurred during all trials including alone, play, escape, and attention at similar rates. What might you conclude from this functional analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "The behavior is likely maintained by automatic reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior is likely controlled by multiple stimuli",
                  "There was likely data collection error",
                  "There was likely an implementation error of the functional analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Automatic reinforcement appears to be the function because the behavior occurred during all tests including the “alone” condition where behavior is not reinforced by the behavior analyst."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and the results indicated that engaging in head slapping occurred during all trials including alone, play, escape, and attention at similar rates. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach him to clap his hands to mimic the same sensation as head hitting, without the same level of danger.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Continue to prompt task completion, even when they engage in head slapping"
                ],
                "explanation": "This behavior appears to be automatically reinforced. DRA procedure would be an appropriate function based intervention."
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the functional behavior assessment timothy engages in kicking when he is asked to complete tasks as well as when he is ignored. What function based intervention could be implemented?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide frequent time-based attention ",
                  "Continue prompting task completion regardless of problem behavior",
                  "Provide attention when appropriately requested"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above would be appropriate interventions to implement"
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the functional behavior assessment timothy engages in kicking when he is asked to complete tasks as well as when he is ignored. What function based intervention could be implemented?",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide breaks during tasks when he requests appropriately",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Non-contingently deliver access to preferred items",
                  "A response cost program for kicking",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Providing breaks during tasks when he requests appropriately is a function based intervention that could be part of the intervention package. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select interventions based on task analysis",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses involve breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a behavior chain?",
                "correctAnswer": "A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Various methods used for linking specific sequences together",
                  "Behaviors that may look different, but all result in the same reinforcement",
                  "Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior chains are a specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following tasks would be most important to break up into smaller steps using a task analysis if it were to be taught to novice learner?",
                "correctAnswer": "Brushing teeth",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Open Container",
                  "Place clothes in the washer"
                ],
                "explanation": "task analyses are used to break up behaviors composed of multiple steps. Single step tasks would not usually need to be broken up further. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following tasks would be most important to break up into smaller steps using a task analysis if it were to be taught to novice learner?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Using dinner utensils",
                  "Doing a cartwheel",
                  "Asking someone on a date"
                ],
                "explanation": "task analyses are used to break up behaviors composed of multiple steps. Single step tasks would not usually need to be broken up further. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which is a research based method of developing a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Observing a competent performer",
                  "Consulting with an expert on the skill",
                  "Perform the behaviors oneself "
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses can be developed by observing a competent performer, consulting with an expert on the skill, or by performing the behaviors oneself. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If you were to conduct a task analysis on putting on pants, which might be the first step outlined in the task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Select one pair of pants from the bottom drawer the dresser",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver one reinforcer as soon as the individual correctly puts their pants on",
                  "Select one pair of pants from the dresser and step in to the pants",
                  "Prompt the individual to put pants on. "
                ],
                "explanation": "The first step of a task analysis should be the first basic task necessary for the individual to complete. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“Breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units” is the definition of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Task Analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior Chain",
                  "Chaining",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Task analyses involve breaking up a complex skill into smaller, teachable units. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“A specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement” is the definition of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior Chain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Chaining",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior chains are a specific sequence of discrete responses ending with reinforcement. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When teaching a new skill to an individual, what can be done only after completing a task analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Chaining",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior Chain",
                  "Task Analysis",
                  "Prompting"
                ],
                "explanation": "Chaining can be completed only after a task analysis. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a behavior chain, conditioned reinforcement for the first step, should also be the ______ for the next step.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "MO",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "In a behavior chain, condition reinforcement for the first step, should also be the SD for the next step. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select interventions based on client preferences",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Stimulus Preference Assessments are used to identify:",
                "correctAnswer": "Appetitive Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Aversive Stimuli",
                  "Reinforcers",
                  "Punishers"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus preference assessments are used to identify preferred (appetitive) stimuli. Appetitive stimuli are not always reinforcers."
              },
              {
                "question": "All of the following are trial based methods for determining preferred stimuli EXCEPT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Free Operant Observation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "Free operant observation can be used to determine preferred stimuli, but it is not trial based. Single stimulus, paired stimuli, and multiple stimuli are all trial based methods."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, stimuli are measure consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents a stuffed toy and measures how long the individual interacts with the toy. The BCBA removes the stuffed toy and presents a backpack and measures the interaction with the item. The BCBA removes the backpack and presents a spinner toy. What type of preference is the BCBA conducting?",
                "correctAnswer": "Single Stimulus ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement"
                ],
                "explanation": "A single stimulus preference assessment is used by presenting stimuli consecutively, one at a time, and the interaction with the stimulus is recorded by the observer. Each stimulus is presented more than once, but the order is varied."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, 2 stimuli are presented to the individual, creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents the child with a stuffed toy and a fidget spinner, and the child selects the fidget spinner. The BCBA then presents a fidget spinner and a backpack, and the child selects the fidget spinner. This is done repeatedly, varying the pairing of items. What type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": " Paired Stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus "
                ],
                "explanation": "A paired stimuli preference assessment is conducted by presenting 2 stimuli to the individual creating a forced choice of one of the stimuli. This is done repeatedly with multiple items, ending with every stimulus being paired with each of the other stimuli."
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA places the item back into the array of items. The BCBA says “choose one” again. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then placed back into the array and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is usually done repeatedly until all items have been selected. "
              },
              {
                "question": "During this preference assessment, an array of items (3 or more) is presented to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA presents 6 items to the child and says “Choose one”. The child selects an item, and then shortly after, the BCBA removes that item from sight. The BCBA says “choose one” again with only the remaining 5 items displayed. Which type of preference assessment is being conducted?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple Stimuli without Replacement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Single Stimulus ",
                  "Paired Stimuli",
                  "Multiple Stimuli with Replacement"
                ],

                "explanation": "A multiple stimuli with replacement preference assessment is conducted by presenting an array of items (3 or more) to the individual. The individual selects an item. The item is then removed from sight, and the individual is again prompted to select an item. This is done repeatedly until all items from the array have been selected."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select interventions based on the client’s current repertoires",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is defined as all of the behaviors that a person is able to do.",
                "correctAnswer": "Repertoire",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Skill set",
                  "Behavior altering effect",
                  "Celeration"
                ],
                "explanation": "The repertoire is all of the behaviors that person is able to do."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have a client who engages in property destruction when prompted to get out of a task. The client has a limited verbal repertoire, and you have never heard her say the words needed to get out of a task appropriately. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Use a simple action or a behavior she is able to do, to request breaks. Allow her to break from the task contingent on appropriate requests",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Require her to say the appropriate words in order to get a break",
                  "Provide reinforcement every 5 minutes that she doesn’t engage in property destruction"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is important that the client is able to perform the expected behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have a client that never brushes his teeth. You have never seen him complete the task. You are trying to increase teeth brushing, what might you do first?",
                "correctAnswer": "Implement a chaining procedure to teach how to brush teeth",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Explain to the client how to brush his teeth to ensure he really knows",
                  "Require that the client brushes his teeth in order to earn access to 10 minutes of tablet use.",
                  "Require that the client brushes his teeth. If he is non-compliant he will be required to return a token from his token economy."
                ],
                "explanation": "Implementing a chaining procedure to train the client on the skill will be a necessary component of the intervention."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have a client that never brushes his teeth. You have seen him perform the behavior before, but during the last few weeks, they have been completely non-compliant. What might you do first?",
                "correctAnswer": "Require that the client brushes his teeth in order to earn access to 10 minutes of tablet use.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Require that the client brushes his teeth. If he is non-compliant he will be required to return a token from his token economy.",
                  "Implement a chaining procedure to teach how to brush teeth",
                  "Explain to the client how to brush his teeth to ensure he really knows"
                ],
                "explanation": "There does not appear to be a skill deficit, rather non-compliance. A reinforcement program is preferred to a punishment program starting out."
              },
              {
                "question": "You have a client who engages in frequent self-injurious behavior. The function appears to be attention from others. You have selected appropriate attention seeking as a replacement behavior. However you have never seen your client engage in any sort of appropriate attention seeking. What might you do first?",
                "correctAnswer": "Use prompting procedures and behavior skills training to teach the replacement behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide frequent attention seeking training",
                  "Deliver preferred items on a frequent time-based schedule.",
                  "Continue prompting task completion whenever the behavior occurs."
                ],
                "explanation": "Use prompting procedures and behavior skills training to teach the replacement behavior. "
              },
              {
                "question": "You have a client who engages in physical aggression frequently. You have been hired to reduce this problem behavior. What appears to be the behavioral concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral excess",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral deficit",
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Behavior modification"
                ],
                "explanation": "This appears to be a behavioral excess."
              },
              {
                "question": "Scientists presume that the universe is a lawful place where things happen as the result of other events. This is which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Determinism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Replication"
                ],
                "explanation": "Determinism is the attitude of science which explains that scientists presume that the universe is a lawful place where things happen as the result of other events. "
              },
              {
                "question": "Scientists continually question the truthfulness of what is regarded as fact. This is which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Philosophical doubt",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Experimentation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Philosophical doubt is the attitude of science which explains that scientists continually question the truthfulness of what is regarded as fact."
              },
              {
                "question": "You hear about a new study that contains results contrary to what you have previously read. You demand to see the objective data because data are unbiased and open to anyone’s observation rather than the subjective belief of one single scientist. This refers to which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Empiricism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Replication"
                ],
                "explanation": "Empiricism is the attitude of science which explains that scientific observations are unbiased, and scientific findings do not depend on the subjective belief of the individual scientist."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which attitude of science states that scientists have a basic strategy for finding knowledge? Events are observed with independent and dependent variables.",
                "correctAnswer": "Experimentation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Replication",
                  "Determinism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Experimentation states that scientists have a basic strategy for finding knowledge. Events are observed with independent and dependent variables."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select interventions based on supporting environments, environmental and resource constraints, and the social validity of the intervention",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are working with a child whose parents are going against the behavior plan between your sessions. This is having a negative impact on the child’s progression. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Retrain the parents on the child’s behavior plan",
                  "Ensure the behavior plan is simple enough to be run by the parents",
                  "Identify in writing the obstacles you are facing for documentation purposes"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are appropriate solutions to parents not running behavior plans. (Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 4.07)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is defined as the extent to which target behaviors are appropriate, intervention procedures are acceptable, and significant changes in behaviors are produced:",
                "correctAnswer": "Social validity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Internal validity",
                  "External validity",
                  "Environmental constraints"
                ],
                "explanation": "Social validity is the extent to which target behaviors are appropriate, intervention procedures are acceptable, and significant changes in behaviors are produced. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a child whose parents are going against the behavior plan between sessions. This is having a negative impact on the child’s progression. This is a concern due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Environmental constraint",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Resource constraint",
                  "Social validity",
                  "Behavioral deficit"
                ],
                "explanation": "This appears to be an environmental constraint. The child’s parents are part of the child’s environment. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with an adolescent, and teaching him appropriate dating skills. The parents ask you to stop focusing on dating because they don’t think the child should date until he is at least 16 years old. Focusing on dating appears to be a concern due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Social validity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Resource constraint",
                  "Environmental constraint",
                  "Behavioral deficit"
                ],
                "explanation": "This appears to be a concern due to the social validity of dating as a target behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with an adolescent, and teaching him appropriate dating skills. The parents ask you to stop focusing on dating because they don’t think the child should date until he is at least 16 years old. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Move the focus of your services away from dating for now",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Talk to the importance of learning these skills to the parents",
                  "Focus on dating anyways. You are the behavior analyst and able to decide which target behaviors to focus on.",
                  "Bring in a neutral third party to select the target behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is important that the target behaviors and interventions have social validity. You should move the focus of your services away from dating for now. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After conducting a preference assessment with your client, you determine that the most preferred item which should be used in intervention is more expensive than you or the parents could provide for the intervention. This appears to be a concern due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Resource constraint",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Environmental constraint",
                  "Social validity",
                  "Behavioral deficit"
                ],
                "explanation": "This appears to be a concern due to resource constraints. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After conducting a preference assessment with your client, you determine that the most preferred item which should be used in intervention is more expensive than you or the parents could provide for the intervention. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Use the next highest preferred item",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Convince the parents to purchase outside their means because their child’s improved behavior is worth the cost",
                  "Use an intervention that does not require a preferred item",
                  "Explain to your friends the situation that your client is in, and ask for financial assistance."
                ],
                "explanation": "You should use the next highest preferred item. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Scientists believe that all simple, logical explanations of the phenomenon of interest be ruled out before more complex explanations are considered. Which attitude of science is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parsimony",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Philosophic doubt",
                  "Replication",
                  "Determinism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Parsimony is the scientific attitude that all simple, logical explanations of the phenomenon of interest be ruled out before more complex explanations are considered. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },              {
                "question": "When selecting an intervention for your client, your coworker shows you an interesting study of a new intervention. This appears to be the only study on this particular intervention at this time. You are not interested in conducting research, so you tell your coworker that experiments need to happen more than once to convincingly establish a new intervention. Which attitude of science are you practicing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Replication",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Parsimony",
                  "Philosophic doubt"
                ],
                "explanation": "Replication is an attitude of science that states that studies must be replicated to demonstrate convincing effectiveness. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Scientists continually question the truthfulness of what is regarded as fact. This is which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Philosophical doubt",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Experimentation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Philosophical doubt is the attitude of science which explains that scientists continually question the truthfulness of what is regarded as fact. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Identify and address practical and ethical considerations when using experimental designs to demonstrate treatment effectiveness",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which attitude of science states that scientists have a basic strategy for finding knowledge? Events are observed with independent and dependent variables.",
                "correctAnswer": "Experimentation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Replication",
                  "Determinism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Experimentation states that scientists have a basic strategy for finding knowledge. Events are observed with independent and dependent variables."
              },
              {
                "question": "When selecting an intervention for your client, your coworker shows you an interesting study of a new intervention. This appears to be the only study on this particular intervention at this time. You are not interested in conducting research, so you tell your coworker that experiments need to happen more than once to convincingly establish a new intervention. Which attitude of science are you practicing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Replication",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Parsimony",
                  "Philosophic doubt"
                ],
                "explanation": "Replication is an attitude of science that states that studies must be replicated to demonstrate convincing effectiveness. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a team meeting with your client and other team members, one of your coworkers makes a statement exaggerating your progress with the client. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Correct the statement immediately",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Leave it alone, but do not add to the exaggerations",
                  "Participate in the exaggerations to ensure continued funding",
                  "Correct the statement in an email to the team later on"
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to correct the statement immediately. Behavior analysts avoid and correct false or deceptive statements. (Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 4.07)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design might be selected if you are already implementing an intervention and did not collect baseline data?",
                "correctAnswer": "B-A-B reversal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Changing criterion",
                  "A-B-A reversal",
                  "Multiple baseline with delayed baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "B-A-B reversal is appropriate to implement and show experimental control when you have already begun treatment without baseline data."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design might be selected if you are incrementally helping a client decrease smoking cigarettes?",
                "correctAnswer": "Changing criterion ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A reversal",
                  "Multiple probe",
                  "Multiple baseline"
                ],
                "explanation": "Changing criterion design is used when incrementally changing a single behavior. "
              },
              {
                "question": "When looking at the graph of your client, there appears to be no clear trend in the behavior. You enter a trend line on the graph and there is a very slight improving trend that isn’t evident with a visual analysis. When talking to the client about their progress, what should you say?",
                "correctAnswer": "Your behavior hasn’t change significantly",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Your behavior has improved",
                  "Your behavior has slightly improved",
                  "Your behavior appears to be worsening"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts are honest. If there isn’t improvement with a visual analysis, that should be stated to the individual."
              },
              {
                "question": "Using experimental designs in practice:",
                "correctAnswer": "Is essential to making data-based decisions",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Should be done when convenient",
                  "Is typically not realistic to do",
                  "Data collection is an optional practice in behavior analysis"
                ],
                "explanation": "Using experimental designs in practice is essential to making data-based decisions."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "Delayed multiple baseline design",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Changing criterion design",
                  "Multiple probe design",
                  "Reversal design"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is the delayed multiple baseline design. "
              },
              {
                "question": "There are several interventions that could help your client. You want to establish which intervention is most effective with you client’s current problem behaviors. Which experimental design could you use to compare different interventions?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternation treatments",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Component analysis",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "A-B-A-B"
                ],
                "explanation": "Alternating treatments design is useful in comparing different interventions that may be effective."
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of experimental design is depicted in this graph?",
                "correctAnswer": "A-B-A-B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A-B-A",
                  "Multiple baseline",
                  "Alternating treatments"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an A-B-A-B design."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "When a behavior is to be decreased, select an acceptable alternative behavior to be established or increased",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is something that generally must occur before selecting a replacement behavior to a problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional behavior assessment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Preference assessment",
                  "Reinforcer assessment",
                  "Punisher assessment"
                ],
                "explanation": "A functional behavior assessment must take place before selecting an alternative behavior to a problem behavior. Though, when using an incompatible behavior as an alternative behavior, a functional behavior assessment isn’t absolutely necessary, but is still recommended."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and the results indicated that engaging in head slapping occurred during all trials including alone, play, escape, and attention at similar rates. What might be an appropriate, function based intervention to implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach him to clap his hands to mimic the same sensation as head hitting, without the same level of danger.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Continue to prompt task completion, even when they engage in head slapping"
                ],
                "explanation": "This behavior appears to be automatically reinforced. DRA procedure would be an appropriate function based intervention."
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the functional behavior assessment timothy engages in kicking when he is asked to complete tasks as well as when he is ignored. What function based intervention could be implemented?",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide breaks during tasks when he requests appropriately",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Non-contingently deliver access to preferred items",
                  "A response cost program for kicking",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Providing breaks during tasks when he requests appropriately is a function based intervention that could be part of the intervention package. "
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with attention as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based alternative behavior to teach?",
                "correctAnswer": "Verbally requesting attention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Frequently deliver attention on a time-based schedule",
                  "Response cost program"
                ],
                "explanation": "Verbally requesting attention is an appropriate replacement behavior to a behavior maintained by attention."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which procedure is used to differentially teach a functionally equivalent replacement behavior and decrease problem behaviors?",
                "correctAnswer": "DRA",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRO",
                  "DRI",
                  "DRL"
                ],
                "explanation": "DRA procedures (Differential reinforcement of alternative behaviors) are used to teach replacement behaviors and decrease problem behaviors."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are helping a child reduce the frequency of tantrum behaviors by implementing extinction. What might you do to minimize the extinction burst?",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach a functionally equivalent alternative behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver punishment contingent on the extinction burst",
                  "Deliver reinforcement during the extinction burst",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Teaching a functionally equivalent alternative behavior may help minimize the extinction burst."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional analysis and identify that your client engages in property destruction with escape from schoolwork as a primary function. What might be an appropriate, function based alternative behavior to teach?",
                "correctAnswer": "Request breaks using a “break card” program",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Give breaks non-contingently",
                  "Minimize schoolwork demands",
                  "Appropriate attention seeking"
                ],
                "explanation": "Requesting a break using a “break card” program is an appropriate function based alternative behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "You conduct a functional behavior assessment and identify that your client engages in property destruction with access to his toys as a primary function. His toys are kept on a shelf out of reach. What might be an appropriate, function based alternative behavior to teach?",
                "correctAnswer": "How to climb up onto the stool to get his toys out himself",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Move the toys on to ground level",
                  "Give him his toys non-contingently throughout the day",
                  "Planned ignore"
                ],
                "explanation": "Although NCR and environmental accommodations may help, the function based replacement behavior in the answers above is teaching the child to climb up onto the stool to get his toys out."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which intervention is used to teach an individual an appropriate behavior that is impossible to occur at the same time as their current problem behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "DRI",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRO",
                  "DRA",
                  "DRL"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differential reinforcement of Incompatible behaviors is used to teach an individual an appropriate behavior that is impossible to occur at the same time as their current problem behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which differential reinforcement procedure decreases problem behavior without teach an appropriate replacement behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "DRO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRI",
                  "DRA",
                  "DRH"
                ],
                "explanation": "Differentially reinforcing other behavior does not teach an alternative behavior. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Program for stimulus and response generalization",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral Cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when the learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated.",
                "correctAnswer": "Maintenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Maintenance occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior that once learned, introduces the learner to new contingencies.",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "A behavioral cusp, once learned, introduces the learner to new contingencies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary learns to play Tuba during band class. She then plays the same song learned in band class on stage during a performance. Playing tuba on stage is evidence of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is evidence of stimulus generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jen was taught to wash dishes using a sponge. When a sponge was not available she washed dishes with a dish rag, without being taught how to use a dish rag. This is evidence of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance ",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is response generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jen was taught to wash dishes using a sponge while at her house. She is at her friend’s house and helps wash dishes. This is evidence of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of stimulus generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jen learns how to walk, is now is able to reach on to the couch, gain access to her own toys, all because she learned how to walk. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "A behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of a behavioral cusp. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is taught to kill flies with a fly swatter. He sees a spider and kills it with the fly swatter.",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is stimulus generalization. Killing the spider requires the same behavior as killing the fly, but the situation was different. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is taught to kill flies with a fly swatter. A fly swatter is not available and so he uses a shoe to kill the fly. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of response generalization. Swatting the fly with a she is a different response. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Program for maintenance",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral Cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when the learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated.",
                "correctAnswer": "Maintenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Maintenance occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior that once learned, introduces the learner to new contingencies.",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "A behavioral cusp, once learned, introduces the learner to new contingencies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "One way for promoting generalization and maintenance is to make the instructional setting similar to the generalized setting. How might you do that?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Program common stimului",
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "Randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are methods for promoting generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ella is learning job skills in a classroom. Before going in to the workplace, the instructor makes the classroom feel as much like a workplace as possible including many features of the jobsite in the classroom. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Programming common stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Randomly varying noncritical aspects of the instructional setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of programming common stimuli. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This strategy promoting generalization requires instructors to randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting.",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach loosely",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Program common stimuli",
                  "Teach sufficient examples",
                  "Contrived contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Teaching loosely requires instructors to randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While preparing to take the BCBA exam, you study thousands of practice questions to ensure you have studied enough possible variations of concepts to pass the exam. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach sufficient examples",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "Program common stimuli",
                  "Contrived contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of teaching sufficient examples. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a strategy for achieving response maintenance?",
                "correctAnswer": "Ensure the learner is coming in to contact with reinforcement from the natural environment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tell the individual that they need to keep doing well, even when interventions are not in place",
                  "Maintain interventions present throughout the individual’s life",
                  "Slowly increase the intrusiveness of interventions, such as increasing the amount of reinforcement the individual earns."
                ],
                "explanation": "Ensuring that the learner is coming in to contact with reinforcement from the natural environment will promote response maintenance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a strategy for achieving response maintenance?",
                "correctAnswer": "Slowly decrease the intrusiveness of interventions.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tell the individual that they need to keep doing well, even when interventions are not in place",
                  "Maintain interventions present throughout the individual’s life",
                  "Slowly increase the intrusiveness of interventions, such as increasing the amount of reinforcement the individual earns."
                ],
                "explanation": "Fading interventions responsibly is an important part of promoting response maintenance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Select behavioral cusps as goals for intervention when appropriate",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior that when changed, exposes the individual to new environments and contingencies.",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pivotal behavior",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is a behavioral cusp. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a behavior, that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Pivotal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral cusp",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A pivotal behavior is on that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Teaching an individual self-management skills which results in the learner engaging in untrained behaviors, is an example of what kind of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Pivotal behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral cusp",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A pivotal behavior is on that once learned, produces corresponding modifications in other adaptive untrained behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A child learns how to walk, and now is able to come into contact with new contingencies that were unavailable until they could walk. This is an example of what kind of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral cusp",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pivotal behavior",
                  "Target behavior",
                  "Maladaptive behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A behavioral cusp is a behavior that when changed, exposes the individual to new environments and contingencies. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "Speaking",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Doing a summersault ",
                  "Asking for a break",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Speaking is likely a behavioral cusp"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Walking",
                  "Speaking",
                  "Using an augmentative communication system"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are likely behavioral cusps"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reading",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Identifying “truck” from an array of images",
                  "Pouring a glass of water",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reading is likely a behavioral cusp"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "Using the public transportation system",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pouring a glass of water",
                  "Saying another person’s name",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Using public transportation system is likely a behavioral cusp."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "Driving a car",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Putting on a seatbelt",
                  "Identifying “truck” from an array of images",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Driving a car is likely a behavioral cusp"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following behaviors is most likely a behavioral cusp?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reading",
                  "Driving a car",
                  "Using the public transportation system"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are likely behavioral cusps. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Arrange instructional procedures to promote generative learning",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits untrained responses that are functionally equivalent to the trained target behavior. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral Cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when the learner emits the trained response in an untrained setting or situation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "One way for promoting generalization and maintenance is to make the instructional setting similar to the generalized setting. How might you do that?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Program common stimului",
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "Randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are methods for promoting generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ella is learning job skills in a classroom. Before going in to the workplace, the instructor makes the classroom feel as much like a workplace as possible including many features of the jobsite in the classroom. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Programming common stimuli",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "All of the above",
                  "Randomly varying noncritical aspects of the instructional setting"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of programming common stimuli. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This strategy promoting generalization requires instructors to randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting.",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach loosely",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Program common stimuli",
                  "Teach sufficient examples",
                  "Contrived contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Teaching loosely requires instructors to randomly vary noncritical aspects of the instructional setting. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While preparing to take the BCBA exam, you study thousands of practice questions to ensure you have studied enough possible variations of concepts to pass the exam. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Teach sufficient examples",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach loosely",
                  "Program common stimuli",
                  "Contrived contingency"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of teaching sufficient examples. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Engaging in behaviors that are not taught, but they are learned through derived relations, refers to what?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generative learning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus equivalence",
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Generative learning refers to engaging in behaviors that are not taught, but they are learned through derived relations. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are conducting discrimination training, and you frequently change the type of clothing you wear, change the decorations in the room, and change odors by using different scented candles. None of these stimuli are directly related to the discrimination training. What are you doing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Teaching loosely",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Teach sufficient examples",
                  "Program common stimuli",
                  "Generative learning"
                ],
                "explanation": "You are teaching loosely by mixing up stimuli not directly related to the training. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jen was taught to wash dishes using a sponge. When a sponge was not available she washed dishes with a dish rag, without being taught how to use a dish rag. This is evidence of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Maintenance ",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is response generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jen was taught to wash dishes using a sponge while at her house. She is at her friend’s house and helps wash dishes. This is evidence of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Maintenance",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of stimulus generalization. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Base decision-making on data displayed in various formats",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are working with a client who engages in bullying. You begin to address the behavior using a behavioral intervention without collecting any baseline data. Which of the following is the best course of action moving forward, assuming the graph below is displaying your client’s bullying behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Remove the intervention and collect baseline data",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continue implementing the intervention",
                  "Conduct a component analysis",
                  "Praise the client for their improved behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intervention does not appear to be working; however without baseline data we cannot be sure."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a client who engages in bullying. You begin to address the behavior using a behavioral intervention without collecting any baseline data. Which of the following is the best course of action moving forward, assuming the graph below is displaying your client’s bullying behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continue implementing the intervention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Remove the intervention and collect baseline data",
                  "Conduct a component analysis",
                  "Consider implementing a different intervention"
                ],
                "explanation": "Although the improving data is variable, it appears to be decreasing. Continued implementation of the intervention is justified by the improvements the client has made."
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line.",
                "correctAnswer": "Line graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "Line graphs allow for data to be displayed between two dimensions (e.g., frequency of behavior across time). Each data point is connect to the next with a line. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled.",
                "correctAnswer": "Bar graph",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The bar graph allows you to display and compare discrete sets of data that are not related to one another by a common underlying dimension by which the horizontal axis can be scaled. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph allows you to discover the temporal distribution of a target behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Scatterplot",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Line graph",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Cumulative record"
                ],
                "explanation": "The scatterplot shows the relative distribution of individual measures in a data set with respect to the variables depicted by the x and y axes. Data points are unconnected. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation.",
                "correctAnswer": "Cumulative record",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph",
                  "Standard celeration chart"
                ],
                "explanation": "The cumulative record displays the total number of responses emitted during a single session of observation. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This type of graph is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments.",
                "correctAnswer": "Standard celeration chart",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cumulative record",
                  "Bar graph",
                  "Line graph"
                ],
                "explanation": "The standard celeration chart is used to display behaviors that are accelerating or decelerating in rate. The vertical axis displays frequency at increasing and non-proportional increments. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the x axis (or abscissa)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Horizontal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Vertical",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Ordinate"
                ],
                "explanation": "The x axis is also known as the horizontal axis, or abscissa. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which axis is the y axis (or ordinate)?",
                "correctAnswer": "Vertical",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Horizontal",
                  "Diagonal",
                  "Abscissa"
                ],
                "explanation": "The y axis is the vertical axis, or ordinate. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Implementation, Management, and Supervision",
        "phase": [
          {
            "name": "Provide for ongoing documentation of behavioral services",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Why is it important to document behavior services you provide?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To facilitate further services by you or other professionals",
                  "To ensure accountability",
                  "To meet requirements of the law and of your organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are important reasons to document behavior services. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.10."
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is it important to document behavior services you provide?",
                "correctAnswer": "To facilitate further services by you or other professionals",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "To ensure treatment integrity",
                  "To increase billable hours that the behavior analyst may be paid for"
                ],
                "explanation": "To facilitate further services by you or other professionals. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.10."
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is it important to document behavior services you provide?",
                "correctAnswer": "To ensure accountability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To ensure treatment integrity",
                  "To increase billable hours that the behavior analyst may be paid for",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "To ensure accountability. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.10."
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is it important to document behavior services you provide?",
                "correctAnswer": "To meet requirements of the law and your organization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "To ensure treatment integrity",
                  "To increase billable hours that the behavior analyst may be paid for",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "To meet requirements of the law and your organization. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.10."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of applied behavior analysis applies to the behavior analyst providing sufficient documentation that services will easily be continued when referred to another provider because of the detail in the documentation?",
                "correctAnswer": "Technological",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Analytic",
                  "Conceptually systematic",
                  "Effective"
                ],
                "explanation": "The dimension “Technological” is relevant to the situation described."
              },
              {
                "question": "According to the BACB’s ethical code, how long are behavior analysts to keep records?",
                "correctAnswer": "7 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "2 years (and as otherwise required by law)",
                  "Until termination of services",
                  "5 years (and as otherwise required by law)"
                ],
                "explanation": "The BACB requires that records be stored for at least 7 years and as otherwise required by law. This is according to the BACB “Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analyst” section 2.11."
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "State the nature of the services provided",
                  "State the fees or charges",
                  "State the identity of the provider"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above should be included. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.13"
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the nature of the services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "A record of billing from the past 12 months",
                  "An increase in you fees each year"
                ],
                "explanation": "The billing report should state the nature of the services provided. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.13"
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the fees or charges",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "A record of billing from the past 12 months",
                  "An increase in you fees each year"
                ],
                "explanation": "The billing report should state the fees or charges. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.13"
              },
              {
                "question": "When billing for services you provide, what should you include in the billing reports?",
                "correctAnswer": "State the identity of the provider",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "A record of billing from the past 12 months",
                  "An increase in you fees each year"
                ],
                "explanation": "The billing report should state the identity of the provider. Professional and Ethical Compliance Code for Behavior Analysts: Section 2.13"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Identify the contingencies governing the behavior of those responsible for carrying out behavior change procedures and design interventions accordingly",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You have just established a behavioral goal for one of your clients. You have several staff working for you. In relation to your staff’s behavior, what might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Train staff in the necessary skills to complete the task",
                  "Monitor staff performance",
                  "Support proficient staff performance"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "You created a goal for one of your clients, and wrote a behavior support plan specifying what staff must do. What might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Train staff in the necessary skills to complete the task",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Monitor staff performance",
                  "Support proficient staff performance",
                  "Correct nonproficient staff performance"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "You created a goal for one of your clients, wrote a behavior support plan specifying what staff must do, and trained staff in the necessary skills to complete the task. What might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Monitor staff performance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Support proficient staff performance",
                  "Correct nonproficient staff performance",
                  "Continuously evaluate staff performance and consumer outcome attainment"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "You created a goal for one of your clients, wrote a behavior support plan specifying what staff must do, and trained staff in the necessary skills to complete the task. You are monitoring staff’s performance and staff are implementing the procedure well. What might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Support proficient staff performance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Correct nonproficient staff performance",
                  "Continuously evaluate staff performance and consumer outcome attainment",
                  "Train staff in the necessary skills to complete the task"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "You created a goal for one of your clients, wrote a behavior support plan specifying what staff must do, and trained staff in the necessary skills to complete the task. You are monitoring staff’s performance and staff are not implementing the procedure well. What might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Correct nonproficient staff performance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Support proficient staff performance",
                  "Continuously evaluate staff performance and consumer outcome attainment",
                  "Train staff in the necessary skills to complete the task"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "You created a goal for one of your clients, wrote a behavior support plan specifying what staff must do, and trained staff in the necessary skills to complete the task. You have monitored staff’s behavior and corrected any concerns and supported appropriate performance. What might be the next task to complete?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continuously evaluate staff performance and consumer outcome attainment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Train staff in the necessary skills to complete the task",
                  "Correct nonproficient staff performance",
                  "Support proficient staff performance"
                ],
                "explanation": "According to “The Supervisor’s Guidebook”, there are 7 steps to a protocol for evidence-based supervision. 1. Identify desired consumer outcomes. 2. Specify what staff must do to assist consumers in attaining desired outcomes. 3. Train staff in the performance skills specified in step 2. 4. Monitor staff performance. 5. Support proficient staff performance. 6. Correnct nonprovicient staff performance. 7. Continuously evaluate staff performance."
              },
              {
                "question": "How do behavioral principles apply to employees compared to clients with developmental disabilities?",
                "correctAnswer": "The exact same",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral principles apply more to people with disabilities",
                  "Behavior principles apply more to employees than people with disabilities",
                  "They should not be applied to employees"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral principles apply the same to employees as with other clients. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a common socially mediated positive reinforcer that applies well in the workplace?",
                "correctAnswer": "Praise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pay",
                  "Corrective action",
                  "Token economy"
                ],
                "explanation": "Praise is a common and effective socially mediated positive reinforcer that applies well in the workplace."
              },
              {
                "question": "What is the application of behavioral principles to the workplace called?",
                "correctAnswer": "Organizational Behavior Management",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Supervising",
                  "Applied Behavior Analysis at Work",
                  "Employee Behavior Management"
                ],
                "explanation": "OBM is the application of behavioral principles to the workplace."
              },
              {
                "question": "Interventions used for staff should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Be evidence based",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Use large amounts of aversive stimuli",
                  "Not be used",
                  "Avoid pay, praise, and other incentives to change behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Interventions used for staff should be evidence based."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and use competency based training for persons who are responsible for carry out behavioral assessment and behavior change procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a step of behavioral skills training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Staff describe what the already know to the instructor",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Describe and discuss the skill",
                  "Demonstrate the target skill",
                  "Staff practice the target skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "Staff do not need to discuss the skills they already know to the instructor as part of behavior skills training. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are training staff on how to implement planned ignore. You have described the procedure to them, and even provided a written summary of the steps. What do you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Demonstrate the target skill",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Staff practice the target skill",
                  "Feedback is delivered, and then they go through the procedure again until they demonstrate mastery",
                  "Describe and discuss the skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "The next step would be to demonstrate the target skill. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are training staff on how to implement planned ignore. You have described the procedure to them, and even provided a written summary of the steps. You also modeled for them how to implement planned ignore. What do you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Staff practice the target skill",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Feedback is delivered, and then they go through the procedure again until they demonstrate mastery",
                  "Describe and discuss the skill",
                  "Demonstrate the target skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "The next step would be for staff to practice the target skill. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are training staff on how to implement planned ignore. You have described the procedure to them, and even provided a written summary of the steps. You also modeled for them how to implement planned ignore. Staff have also practiced implementing planned ignore. What do you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Feedback is delivered, and then they go through the procedure again until they demonstrate mastery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Describe and discuss the skill",
                  "Demonstrate the target skill",
                  "Staff practice the target skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "Feedback should be given. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are training staff on how to implement planned ignore. You have described the procedure to them, and even provided a written summary of the steps. You modeled for them how to implement planned ignore and then they practiced implementing planned ignore. They made several mistakes while practicing. What do you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Feedback is delivered, and then they go through the procedure again until they demonstrate mastery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Describe and discuss the skill",
                  "Staff have completed training",
                  "Staff practice the target skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "Feedback should be given. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are training staff on how to implement planned ignore. You have described the procedure to them, and even provided a written summary of the steps. You modeled for them how to implement planned ignore and then they practiced implementing planned ignore. They did not make any mistakes while implementing planned ignore. What do you do next?",
                "correctAnswer": "Staff have completed training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Feedback is delivered, and then they go through the procedure again until they demonstrate mastery",
                  "Describe and discuss the skill",
                  "Staff practice the target skill"
                ],
                "explanation": "Staff have completed training. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is necessary before you should conduct behavior skills training?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Practice the role play prior to behavior skills training",
                  "Be able to perform the task yourself",
                  "Write down the necessary steps of the task (task analysis)"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above should take place before you conduct behavior skills training. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is necessary before you should conduct behavior skills training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Practice the role play prior to behavior skills training.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Know how many of the steps your staff is able to implement",
                  "All employees must already know how to implement the task"
                ],
                "explanation": "You should practice the role play prior to behavior skills training. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is necessary before you should conduct behavior skills training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Be able to perform the task yourself",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Know how many of the steps your staff is able to implement",
                  "All employees must already know how to implement the task",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "You should be able to perform the task yourself. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is necessary before you should conduct behavior skills training?",
                "correctAnswer": "Write down the necessary steps of the task (task analysis)",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Know how many of the steps your staff is able to implement",
                  "All employees must already know how to implement the task",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "You should write down the necessary steps of the task prior to conducting BST. (Reid, 2012)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and use effective performance monitoring and reinforcement systems",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Monitoring staff work performance:",
                "correctAnswer": "Is essential for any effective supervisor",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Is often excessive and unnecessary",
                  "Is optional",
                  "Should not be done"
                ],
                "explanation": "Monitoring staff work performance is essential for any effective supervisor. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Systematically observing a designated aspect of staff work performance is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Formal monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Performance monitoring",
                  "Informal monitoring",
                  "Monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "Formal monitoring is when the supervisor systematically observes a designated aspect of staff work performance. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a possible scenario that may constitute formal monitoring of staff performance?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Staff are expected to perform new skills",
                  "Corrective action has just been taken by a supervisor",
                  "A supervisor is concerned about the quality of work of the employee"
                ],
                "explanation": "All answers are possible scenarios that may constitute formal monitoring of staff performance. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a possible scenario that may constitute formal monitoring of staff performance?",
                "correctAnswer": "Staff were recently trained on a new skill",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Staff are implementing programs without any concern",
                  "Staff are concerned about the behavior analyst’s performance",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "If staff were recently trained on a new skill, formal monitoring may be necessary. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Making quick performance observations without using a prepared tool is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Informal monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Formal monitoring",
                  "Performance monitoring",
                  "Monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "Informal monitoring occurs when making quick performance observations without using a prepared tool. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a benefit of frequent informal monitoring?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior analyst is available to staff",
                  "Increased opportunities to support proficient performance",
                  "Able to quickly respond to performance that is not proficient."
                ],
                "explanation": "All answers above are benefits of frequent informal monitoring. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when staff change their behavior while they are in the presence of their supervisor:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reactivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Formal monitoring",
                  "Response adherence",
                  "Interobserver agreement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reactivity occurs when staff change their behavior while they are in the presence of their supervisor. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is NOT an appropriate method to reduce reactivity?",
                "correctAnswer": "Covert monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Monitor frequently",
                  "Begin monitoring immediately upon entering the staff workplace",
                  "Conduct unexpected “return” monitoring sessions"
                ],
                "explanation": "Covert monitoring has many problems associated with it. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which form of monitoring is not recommended due to possible problems?",
                "correctAnswer": "Covert monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Overt monitoring",
                  "Formal monitoring",
                  "Informal monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "Covert monitoring is not recommended because staff usually find out they are being monitored they often lose respect for the supervisor. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Inform them ahead of time of the monitoring",
                  "Greet staff prior to the formal monitoring",
                  "Provide feedback soon after monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "All options provided are ways to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff. (Reid, 2012)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Design and use systems for monitoring procedural integrity",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Inform them ahead of time of the monitoring",
                  "Greet staff prior to the formal monitoring",
                  "Provide feedback soon after monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "All options provided are ways to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "Inform them ahead of time of the monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Conduct formal monitoring frequently",
                  "The monitoring should take place covertly"
                ],
                "explanation": "Informing the staff ahead of time of the monitoring may help make monitoring more acceptable. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "Greet staff prior to the formal monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Conduct formal monitoring frequently",
                  "The monitoring should take place covertly"
                ],
                "explanation": "Greet staff prior to the formal meeting will make formal monitoring more acceptable to staff. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide feedback soon after monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Conduct formal monitoring frequently",
                  "The monitoring should take place covertly"
                ],
                "explanation": "Provide feedback soon after monitoring will help make the process more acceptable to staff. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What can you do to make formal monitoring acceptable to staff?",
                "correctAnswer": "Acknowledge staff directly following the formal monitoring",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Conduct formal monitoring frequently",
                  "Delay feedback after monitoring"
                ],
                "explanation": "Acknowledge staff directly following the formal monitoring. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is done to evaluate the fidelity of the independent variable:",
                "correctAnswer": "Treatment integrity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "IOA",
                  "Reliability",
                  "External validity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Treatment integrity is evaluated to determine the fidelity of the independent variable.(Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In practice, when there is low treatment integrity, what should take place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Staff need to be retrained, unless another concern is evident",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Another treatment should be implemented",
                  "The client will need to be retrained",
                  "The behavior analyst will need to update the behavior intervention plan"
                ],
                "explanation": "Staff need to be retrained, unless another concern is evident. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the independent variable differs during implementation from the onset of the implementation.",
                "correctAnswer": "Treatment drift",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Observer drift",
                  "Treatment integrity",
                  "Reliability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Treatment drift occurs when, simply put, the intervention stops being run how it was intended to be run. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a benefit of frequent informal monitoring?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior analyst is available to staff",
                  "Increased opportunities to support proficient performance",
                  "Able to quickly respond to performance that is not proficient."
                ],
                "explanation": "All answers above are benefits of frequent informal monitoring. (Reid, 2012)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when staff change their behavior while they are in the presence of their supervisor:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reactivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Formal monitoring",
                  "Response adherence",
                  "Interobserver agreement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reactivity occurs when staff change their behavior while they are in the presence of their supervisor. (Reid, 2012)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Provide supervision for behavior change agents. Evaluate the effectiveness of the behavioral program.",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Why is treatment integrity important?",
                "correctAnswer": "It relates to consumer outcomes",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Staff should learn to respect their supervisor",
                  "Staff need to develop appropriate skills ",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "High treatment integrity usually results in more behavior change for the consumer. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Why is treatment integrity important?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It relates to consumer outcomes",
                  "It reduces confounds in research studies",
                  "Data are more difficult to understand"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the provided answers are correct. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is NOT a way to increase treatment integrity?",
                "correctAnswer": "Create a thorough and intense treatment package",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Simplify the interventions",
                  "Conduct behavior skills training (competency based training)",
                  "Standardize interventions"
                ],
                "explanation": "Interventions that are simple and standardized are more likely to be implemented correctly; however, for difficult behavior change, this is not always possible or ethical. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Your client made excellent improvements, however when treatment integrity was measured, it was very low. What does this indicate?",
                "correctAnswer": "You don’t know for certain that behavior change was due to your intervention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior change was NOT due to your intervention",
                  "The behavior change was likely due to your intervention",
                  "Behavior change did not actually occur"
                ],
                "explanation": "You don’t know for certain that behavior change was due to your intervention. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Feedback to staff should most often be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Immediate, positive, and certain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Immediate, negative, and certain",
                  "Delayed, positive, and certain",
                  "Immediate, negative, and uncertain"
                ],
                "explanation": "Feedback to staff should most often be immediate, positive, and certain"
              },
              {
                "question": "Your employee is not running the behavioral interventions consistently. He is scoring low on treatment integrity. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Consider the function of his behavior and other environmental variables",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver corrective feedback",
                  "Retrain the employee on the skill",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Before correcting your employee’s behavior, you should consider the function of the behavior. Is this a skill deficit, or behavior problem? Do they have skills necessary to complete the task?"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are asked to supervise a behavior analyst who wants to practice OBM, however you do not have experience in organizational behavior management. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Turn down the opportunity. Look for experience opportunities down the road.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Take a course on OBM before starting supervision",
                  "Take a course on OBM after starting supervision",
                  "Turn down the opportunity because you are supervising too many behavior analysts."
                ],
                "explanation": "Turn down the opportunity. Look for experience opportunities down the road."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are asked to supervise a behavior analyst, but you are already supervising several behavior analysts. This behavior analyst doesn’t have any other options, but you are too busy. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Politely decline the opportunity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Supervise him, otherwise he will practice without any supervision",
                  "Supervise him. You can always find time for one more supervisee",
                  "Politely decline. You do not have experience necessary to supervise him."
                ],
                "explanation": "Decline the opportunity. Behavior analysts do not supervise more individuals than what allows them to be effective."
              },
              {
                "question": "You are supervising a BCBA who does not feel confident and has not demonstrated skills in conducting discrete trials. What should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conduct competency based training to gain more practice",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Send him to conduct discrete trials without you",
                  "Go observe him conducting discrete trials",
                  "Deliver feedback that he must learn to conduct discrete trials."
                ],
                "explanation": "Conduct competency based training to gain more practice if he does not have the skills to complete the task."
              },
              {
                "question": "Reinforcement programs should be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Designed for both Clients and employees",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Designed only for clients",
                  "Designed only for employees",
                  "Excluded from the workplace"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement programs should be designed for both clients and employees. "
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Establish support for behavior-analytic services from direct and indirect consumers. Secure the support of others to maintain the client’s behavioral repertoires in their natural environments",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "This phenomenon occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "High-probability request sequences",
                  "Matching law",
                  "Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary loses TV time when her mother is home and Mary doesn’t clean her room. Mary usually cleans her room when her mother is home. When her mother is not home, Mary never cleans her room. What effect appears to be occurring?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral Contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔP ",
                  "Punishment",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when changes in one component of a schedule results in an increase or decrease in the rate of responding but also results in the opposite effect in environments in which the schedule was not changed. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by:",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Using the intervention in ALL applicable settings and conditions",
                  "Withhold reinforcement for all occurrences of problem behavior",
                  "Provide alternative desirable behaviors"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above can be used to minimize behavioral contrast effects. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Provide alternative desirable behaviors",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ask the person to not engage in the problem behavior",
                  "Collect data",
                  "All of the above"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast effects can be minimized by providing alternative desirable behaviors. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "During a team meeting for your client, one team member is adamant about starting a treatment that is not evidence based. What is should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated.",
                  "As the BCBA, you should not implement the treatment",
                  "Ask the team member if they have any research they could provide on the effects of the treatment."
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the answers above would be appropriate."
              },
              {
                "question": "During a team meeting for your client, one team member is adamant about starting a treatment that is not evidence based. What is should you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Tell the team that you will not be part of a team that uses non-evidence based treatments",
                  "Implement your own treatment to counteract anything that the rest of the team does."
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to ask the team to take data on the effects of the treatment. If no improvement is seen, then it should be terminated."
              },
              {
                "question": "Who is defined as a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services provided",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The individual with disabilities",
                  "Whoever funds the services",
                  "The behavior analyst"
                ],
                "explanation": "The client is whoever benefits from the behavior analytic services according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be identified as a “client”?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The service recipient",
                  "The parent",
                  "An organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above may be identified as a client according to the BACB ethics code 2.0."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be identified as a “direct consumer”?",
                "correctAnswer": "The service recipient",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The parent",
                  "A teacher",
                  "An organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "The service recipient is the direct consumer."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be identified as an “indirect consumer”?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The parent",
                  "A teacher",
                  "An organization"
                ],
                "explanation": "All of the above are indirect consumers."
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Arrange for the orderly termination of services when they are no longer required",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are working with Ella who engages in frequent tantrums. You have worked with her for 12 months and have not seen any progress. You have changed the behavior intervention plan multiple times, but they haven’t seemed to help the behavior. What could you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Refer the client to another behavior analyst who may have more experience",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All of the above",
                  "Seek out a mental health diagnosis",
                  "Immediately terminate services"
                ],
                "explanation": "Refer the client to someone who may have more experience with similar situations."
              },
              {
                "question": "Joey is sleeping well and no longer engaging in angry outbursts. He has met the criteria established at the onset of services to discontinue services. As the behavior analyst, what do you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Terminate services by slowly fading all behavioral interventions you are providing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Immediately terminate services once the criteria are met",
                  " Look for more behaviors that would benefit from your services",
                  "Ask Joey if he wants you to leave or stay working with him"
                ],
                "explanation": "Terminate services once he has met the established criteria by slowly fading all behavioral interventions."
              },
              {
                "question": "Adam is receiving behavior analysis services, but is unhappy with the service you provide. He asks for termination of services. What do you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Terminate services",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Provide data to show the positive effect of your services",
                  "Provide a termination of services fee to deter him from terminating services",
                  "Provide a list of testimonials of satisfied consumers"
                ],
                "explanation": "It is appropriate to terminate services as requested by the client. "
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a strategy for achieving response maintenance?",
                "correctAnswer": "Ensure the learner is coming in to contact with reinforcement from the natural environment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tell the individual that they need to keep doing well, even when interventions are not in place",
                  "Maintain interventions present throughout the individual’s life",
                  "Slowly increase the intrusiveness of interventions, such as increasing the amount of reinforcement the individual earns."
                ],
                "explanation": "Ensuring that the learner is coming in to contact with reinforcement from the natural environment will promote response maintenance. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated.",
                "correctAnswer": "Maintenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Behavioral cusp"
                ],
                "explanation": "Maintenance occurs when the learner continues to perform the target behavior after the intervention has been terminated. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },              {
                "question": "Mary is a BCBA serving several clients in her area. Due to a family emergency she needs to relocate to another state for several months. Mary should:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not abandon the clients without ensuring the cases are transferred",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Do what she needs to do in emergency situations",
                  "Inform the clients that she may be able to continue services in a few months when she returns.",
                  "Resolve the family situation first, and then decide later on what to do with the caseload."
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary should do everything possible to ensure the cases are transferred to a qualified replacement."
              },
              {
                "question": "When would be an appropriate time to discontinue services with a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The client requests discontinuation of services",
                  "Is not benefitting from the service",
                  "Is being harmed by the service"
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to discontinue services for all of the reasons listed above. "
              },
              {
                "question": "When would be an appropriate time to discontinue services with a client?",
                "correctAnswer": "The client has met the measurable objectives laid out at the onset of services",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior analyst is sick, and will be unable to work for several days",
                  "All of the above",
                  "The client has met one of the two measureable objectives laid out at the onset of services."
                ],
                "explanation": "It would be appropriate to discontinue services if the client has met the measurable objectives laid out at the onset of services"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hired to consult with a young boy who engages in frequent hitting. His mother wants you to help the boy learn not to hit. What might be the criterion you set to discontinue services?",
                "correctAnswer": "When the boy has gone 2 weeks without engaging in any hitting",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "When the boy has gone 12 months without engaging in any hitting",
                  "When the boy is no longer aggressive",
                  "With the boy has progressed to the point to where services are no longer needed."
                ],
                "explanation": "There needs to be set criteria that includes a reasonable amount of time."
              },
              {
                "question": "When is the most preferred situation for an individual to terminate services?",
                "correctAnswer": "The client has met the established criterion for discontinuing services",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The client requests discontinuation of services",
                  "Is not benefitting from the service",
                  "Is being harmed by the service"
                ],
                "explanation": "The most preferred situation for an individual to terminate services is when the client has met the established criterion for discontinuing services."
              }
            ]
          }
        ]
      },
      {
        "name": "Foundational Knowledge",
        "phase": [
		  {
            "name": "Lawfulness of behavior, Determinism, Empiricism, Parsimony, Pragmatism",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Laura has been told that high probability request sequences have been shown within the literature to increase responding to more difficult tasks. Laura thinks this is unlikely, but ultimately practices according she is demonstrating:",
                "correctAnswer": "Philosophical doubt",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative thinking",
                  "Parsimonious thinking",
                  "Parsimony"
                ],
                "explanation": "Philosophical doubt - Laura has a healthy skepticism toward information she has been provided. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not an attitude of science recognized by behavior analysts?",
                "correctAnswer": "Technological",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Replication"
                ],
                "explanation": "Technological is one of the defining characteristics of ABA. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007)"
              },
              {
                "question": " I want to help my student improve his test score so I measure how often he engages in appropriate behavior (which I clearly define) during recess. This is lacking which dimension of ABA?",
                "correctAnswer": "Effective",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral",
                  "Conceptually systematic",
                  "Generality"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral dimension states that the target behavior must be socially significant. Measuring behavior during recess isn’t an effective method to improve test scores ( cooper, 16)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A parent believes that their child throws a tantrum every time in the store's candy isle because the lighting in the isle is brighter than the other isles. However, in the past the child has been given candy after throwing a tantrum in the candy isle. The second explanation for the behavior is an example of which philosophical principle of behavior analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Pragmatism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Parsimony",
                  "Determinism",
                  "Empiricism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior analysts hold a pragmatic view, in that they view behavior in a practical and realistic manner as opposed to entertaining theoretical considerations."
              },
              {
                "question": "Ida demonstrates arm flapping throughout the day. It has become more severe to the point where she has dislocated her shoulder.  The BCBA has determined that arm flapping is socially significant for Ida. Which dimension of Applied Behavior Analysis does this demonstrate?",
                "correctAnswer": "Applied",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Analytical",
                  "Generality",
                  "Behavioral"
                ],
                "explanation": "“Applied” refers to the extent that behavior analysts are committed to improving behaviors that will enhance and improve people’s lives."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT an attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Correlation ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Philosophical Doubt",
                  "Parsimony"
                ],
                "explanation": "Correlation is not an attitude of science, although it relates to “Prediction” which is one of the purposes of science. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007 pages 5 & 6)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which attitude of science requires the practitioner to rule out simple explanations of the phenomena prior to moving on to more complex explanations?",
                "correctAnswer": "Parsimony",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Philosophical doubt",
                  "Determinism",
                  "Empiricism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Parsimony requires the practitioner to rule out simple explanations of the phenomena prior to moving on to more complex explanations. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007 pages 5 & 6)"
              },
              {
                "question": "David is working with a child who frequently runs away. The research suggests that giving the child non-contingent breaks throughout the day may decrease this behavior. David’s opinion is that giving that break won’t be effective, despite contradicting research. David doesn’t implement the procedure. David is violating which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Empiricism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Parsimony"
                ],
                "explanation": "Empiricism is the attitude that scientists are objective in their observations, meaning they make decisions independently of their individual prejudices, tastes, and private opinions. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007 pages 5 & 6)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior is lawful, in that it occurs as the result of other events. Which attitude of science is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Determinism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Empiricism",
                  "Parsimony",
                  "Pragmatism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Determinism is the attitude that the universe (including behavior) is lawful, and phenomena occur as the result of other events. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007 pages 5 & 6)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior analysts are objective in their observations. Decisions are made independently of their individual prejudices, tastes, and private opinions. This is which attitude of science?",
                "correctAnswer": "Empiricism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Determinism",
                  "Experimentation",
                  "Parsimony"
                ],
                "explanation": "Empiricism is the attitude that scientists are objective in their observations, meaning they make decisions independently of their individual prejudices, tastes, and private opinions. (Cooper, Heron, Heward, 2007 pages 5 & 6)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Selectionism",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "All members of a species generally share the same unconditioned punishers. This is a product of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Phylogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogeny",
                  "Aversive control",
                  "Selectionism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Phylogeny refers to attributes that have a genetic provenance. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Selection by consequences is synonymous with:",
                "correctAnswer": "Ontogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Phylogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Ontogeny refers to attributes (behaviors) that have formed due to the organisms learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior occurs and is influenced by genetics as well as the orgnasim’s learning history. Considering the provenence (source) of behavior refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Selectionism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogeny",
                  "Phylogeny",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Selectionism refers to considering the provenence (source) of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jimmy walks outside and the sun shines on his face. The bright sun elicits Jimmy’s pupils to contract. This behavior appears to have a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Phylogenic provenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogenic provenance",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned reflexes are part of the organisms genetic endowment, and relate to selectionism by phylogeny. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally touches a hot pan and immediately flinches her hand away. Flinching her hand away appears to have a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Phylogenic provenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogenic provenance",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned reflexes are part of the organisms genetic endowment, and relate to selectionism by phylogeny. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Kyle ate an excessive amount of food and he throws up. Throwing up occurs due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Phylogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned reflexes are part of the organisms genetic endowment, and relate to selectionism by phylogeny. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Kyle speeds while driving. Kyle is pulled over and given a ticket. From then on Kyle drives much slower (especially when a police car is present). Kyle driving slow, especially around police cars, occurs due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Ontogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Phylogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Ontogeny refers to attributes (behaviors) that have formed due to the organisms learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally says “Dada” and her dad responds with high levels of praise. Sally is more likely to say “dada” in the future. Saying “dada” occurs due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Ontogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Phylogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Ontogeny refers to attributes (behaviors) that have formed due to the organisms learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jimmy walks outside and the sun shines on his face. Jimmy immediately places sunglasses over his eyes. Placing sunglasses over his eyes occurs due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Ontogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Phylogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Ontogeny refers to attributes (behaviors) that have formed due to the organisms learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jenny hears a loud noise and she immediately blinks her eye. Blinking her eye occurs due to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Phylogeny",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Ontogeny",
                  "Selectionism",
                  "Aversive control"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned reflexes are part of the organisms genetic endowment, and relate to selectionism by phylogeny. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 32)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Environmental explanations of behavior",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Lyle screams when he can’t drink soda. When asked why he does this, his mother says “Lyle screams because he has oppositional defiant disorder. His mind just works differently than ours”.  In this example, the term “mind” is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Hypothetical construct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalistic explanation",
                  "Environmental explanation",
                  "Circular reasoning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Hypothetical constructs are presumed but not observed entities, such as “the mind”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lyle screams when he can’t drink soda. When asked why he does this, his mother says “Lyle screams because he has oppositional defiant disorder. His mind just works differently than ours”. When asked how the mom new her son has oppositional defiant disorder, she says “Because he always screams when he can’t get what he wants”.  In this example, the mother appears to be using:",
                "correctAnswer": "Circular reasoning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Hypothetical construct",
                  "Environmental explanation",
                  "Mentalistic explanation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Circular reasoning occurs when the explanation for the behavior is the same as the description of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lyle screams when he can’t drink soda. When asked why he does this, his mother says “Lyle screams because he has oppositional defiant disorder”.  In this example, the mother appears to be using which type of explanation for her son’s behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mentalistic explanation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Diagnostic  ",
                  "Hypothetical construct",
                  "Environmental explanation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mentalistic explanations (explanatory fiction) use hypothetical constructs and circular reasoning when explaining behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lyle screams when he can’t drink soda. When asked why he does this, his mother says “Lyle screams because it typically results in us giving him soda”.  In this example, the mother appears to be using which type of explanation for her son’s behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Environmental explanation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalistic explanation",
                  "Diagnostic  ",
                  "Hypothetical construct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Environmental explanations of behavior use observable factors that are verifiably influencing the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tabitha looks at the bottle of milk and says “Miiik”. You explain this behavior by saying “Tabitha says “Miiik” because she is getting so smart!” Which type of explanation does this appear to be?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mentalistic explanation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Diagnostic",
                  "Environmental explanation",
                  "Hypothetical construct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mentalistic explanations (explanatory fiction) use hypothetical constructs and circular reasoning when explaining behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tabitha looks at the bottle of milk and says “Miiik”. You explain this behavior by saying “Tabitha says “Miiik” because each approximation she makes to saying “Milk” is reinforced by Tabitha gaining access to milk.” Which type of explanation does this appear to be?",
                "correctAnswer": "Environmental explanation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalistic explanation",
                  "Diagnostic  ",
                  "Hypothetical construct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Environmental explanations of behavior use observable factors that are verifiably influencing the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James is at school and frequently runs out of the classroom. The teacher explains this by saying “James runs away from the classroom because he doesn’t want to be here”. When asked how the teacher knows that James doesn’t want to be there she replies “because he is always trying to run away”. The teacher appears to be using:",
                "correctAnswer": "Circular reasoning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Hypothetical construct",
                  "Environmental explanation",
                  "Diagnostic explanation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Circular reasoning occurs when the explanation for the behavior is the same as the description of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James is at school and frequently runs out of the classroom. The teacher explains this by saying “James runs away from the classroom because he has not yet developed the intrinsic motivation for remaining in school.” The term “Intrinsic motivation” is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Hypothetical construct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Circular reasoning",
                  "Environmental explanation",
                  "Diagnostic explanation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Hypothetical constructs are presumed but not observed entities, such as “the mind”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James is at school and frequently runs out of the classroom. The teacher explains this by saying “James runs away from the classroom because he has not yet developed the intrinsic motivation for remaining in school.” The teacher appears to be using which type of explanation of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Explanatory fiction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Hypothetical construct",
                  "Mentalistic explanation",
                  "Environmental explanation"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mentalistic explanations (explanatory fiction) use hypothetical constructs and circular reasoning when explaining behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)"
              },
              {
                "question": "James is at school and frequently runs out of the classroom. The teacher explains this by saying “James runs away from the classroom because it typically results in him getting out of schoolwork.” The teacher appears to be using which type of explanation for behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Environmental explanation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mentalistic explanation",
                  "Diagnostic  ",
                  "Hypothetical construct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Environmental explanations of behavior use observable factors that are verifiably influencing the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Radical and methodological behaviorism",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Who first used the term “radical behaviorism”?",
                "correctAnswer": "Skinner",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Watson",
                  "Hull",
                  "Tolman"
                ],
                "explanation": "Skinner first used the term “Radical Behaviorism”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behaviorism rejects the study of private events?",
                "correctAnswer": "Methodological behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Radical behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Methodological behaviorism rejects the study of private events. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behaviorism acknowledges the existence of mental events? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Both answers are correct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Neither answer is correct",
                  "Radical behaviorism",
                  "Methodological behaviorism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Both radical and methodological behaviorism acknowledges the existence of mental events. Methodological behaviorists reject to study such phenomena. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behaviorism was prevalent prior to Skinner’s influence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Methodological behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Radical behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Methodological behaviorism rejects the study of private events. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behaviorism was prevalent only after Skinner’s influence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Radical behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Methodological behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Radical behaviorism was prevalent only after Skinner’s influence. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behaviorism is most prevalent today?",
                "correctAnswer": "Radical behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Methodological behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Radical behaviorism was prevalent only after Skinner’s influence, and continues to be prevalent today. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "“Radical” in “Radical Behaviorism” refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Far-reaching or thoroughgoing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Strange or weird",
                  "Extreme or “Cultish”",
                  "Difficult to accept or apply"
                ],
                "explanation": "“Radical” refers to behaviorism being far-reaching or thoroughgoing. Radical behaviorism attempts to encompass all behavior including private events. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a behavior analyst under the assumption that people “Think” but he can’t observe that. John doesn’t attempt to observe or change this type of behavior. John accepts that mental events occur, but does not consider them when studying behavior. John’s behavior is most similar to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Methodological behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Radical behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Methodological behaviorism rejects the study of private events. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a behavior analyst and accepts that people “think”, and engage in other mental events. John’s behavior is most similar to:",
                "correctAnswer": " Both answers are correct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Neither answer is correct",
                  "Radical behaviorism",
                  "Methodological behaviorism"
                ],
                "explanation": "Both radical and methodological behaviorism acknowledges the existence of mental events. Methodological behaviorists reject to study such phenomena. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is a behavior analyst and accepts that people “think”, and engage in other mental events. John does everything he can to consider these events. John is innovative in finding and studying methods to scientifically observe and understand these private events. John’s behavior is most similar to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Radical behaviorism",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Methodological behaviorism",
                  "Both answers are correct",
                  "Neither answer is correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "Radical behaviorism accepts that private events occur, and do what they can to scientifically study these behaviors. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 12-13)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conceptual analysis of behavior, EAB, ABA, and behavioral service delivery",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which domain of behavior analysis focuses primarily on the theory and philosophy of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conceptual analysis of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Behavioral service delivery"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conceptual analysis of behavior primarily focuses on theory and philosophy of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which domain of behavior analysis has the primary goal of discovering and clarifying basic principles of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Experimental analysis of behavior focuses on discovering and clarifying basic principles of behavior, often taking place in an animal research lab. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which domain of behavior analysis may take place in an animal research lab?",
                "correctAnswer": "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Experimental analysis of behavior focuses on discovering and clarifying basic principles of behavior, often taking place in an animal research lab. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John spends hours each day in a pigeon research lab. He uses theoretical behavior principles such as deprivation, reinforcement, and extinction to enact change in the pigeon’s behavior. John is most likely practicing in which domain of behavior analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Experimental analysis of behavior focuses on discovering and clarifying basic principles of behavior, often taking place in an animal research lab. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which domain of behavior analysis conducts research while improving socially significant behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Applied behavior analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Applied behavior analysis occurs in the applied setting such as a classroom, a home, or wherever the behavior typically occurs. ABA practitioners conduct research and improve socially significant behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Susie recently published a research article showing the behavioral methods she used to reduce self-stimulatory behavior in children with autism. Which domain of behavior analysis does this best exemplify?",
                "correctAnswer": "Applied behavior analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Applied behavior analysis occurs in the applied setting such as a classroom, a home, or wherever the behavior typically occurs. ABA practitioners conduct research and improve socially significant behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John helped a young child learn to take a bath using behavioral principles. John did not use an established program to do this, rather he created his own intervention package using evidenced based treatments found in the literature. John used a multiple probe experimental design. Which domain of behavior analysis does this best exemplify?",
                "correctAnswer": "Applied behavior analysis",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                  "Behavioral service delivery",
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Applied behavior analysis occurs in the applied setting such as a classroom, a home, or wherever the behavior typically occurs. ABA practitioners conduct research and improve socially significant behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which domain of behavior analysis is the implementation of already established treatments and protocols to help make socially significant changes in behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral service delivery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior",
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral service delivery is the implementation of established treatments and interventions that have been shown to make socially significant changes in behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John is an RBT, and implements the intervention designed for his specific client. John is most likely practicing in which domain of behavior analysis?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral service delivery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conceptual analysis of behavior",
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral service delivery is the implementation of established treatments and interventions that have been shown to make socially significant changes in behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Susie is a college professor and recently published an article regarding the unwanted effects of punishment. Susie referenced many studies throughout her article, however she did not conduct her own research. Which domain of behavior analysis does this best exemplify?",
                "correctAnswer": "Conceptual analysis of behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Experimental analysis of behavior",
                  "Applied behavior analysis",
                  "Behavioral service delivery"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conceptual analysis of behavior primarily focuses on theory and philosophy of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 21)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Behavior, response, response class",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is defined as everything a person does?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response",
                  "Functional response class",
                  "Topographical response class"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavior is defined as everything a person does. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is defined as one specific instance of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response class",
                  "Behavior",
                  "Functional response class"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response is defined as one specific instance of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas picks flowers when he goes on walks. “Picking flowers” is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional response class",
                  "Response",
                  "Response class"
                ],
                "explanation": "Picking flowers is a behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas picked a flower while he was on a walk. This specific occurrence of the behavior is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior",
                  "Response class",
                  "Topographical response class"
                ],
                "explanation": "A specific occurrence of behavior is a response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas picks flowers with his left hand. Sometimes he picks flowers with his right hand. He even picked a flower with his toes once. All of these behaviors are topographically different but get the same result. These are an example of a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional response class",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Topographical response class",
                  "Behavior",
                  "Response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A functional response class include all forms of the behavior that have the same result. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas picks flowers. He always uses his right hand, grips the plant, and pulls the plant out. Sometimes he smells the flower, sometimes he throws it away, and sometimes he gives it to his mother. This definition of “picking” includes what the behavior looks like, and has no regard to the result of the behavior. This is an example of a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Topographical response class",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional response class",
                  "Behavior",
                  "Response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A topographical response class include a defined form of the behavior, and includes all responses regardless of the result of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a group of responses that all take the same form, but may vary in result of the behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Topographical response class",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functional response class",
                  "Behavior",
                  "Response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A topographical response class include a defined form of the behavior, and includes all responses regardless of the result of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a group of responses that may vary in form, but have the same result.",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional response class",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Topographical response class",
                  "Behavior",
                  "Response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A functional response class include all forms of the behavior that have the same result. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a behavior:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not doing classwork",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Disrupting the class",
                  "Shouting",
                  "Leaving the classroom"
                ],
                "explanation": "“Not” doing something is not a behavior. If a dead man can do it, then it isn’t a behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is NOT a behavior:",
                "correctAnswer": "Not drinking soda",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Drinking water",
                  "Running",
                  "Lifting weights"
                ],
                "explanation": "“Not” doing something is not a behavior. If a dead man can do it, then it isn’t a behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 25-26)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Environment, stimulus, stimulus class",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is defined as “the conglomerate of real circumstances in which the organism exists”?",
                "correctAnswer": "Environment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus ",
                  "Stimulus class",
                  "Antecedent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Environment is defined as the conglomerate of real circumstances in which the organism exists. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is defined as “an energy change that affects an organism through its receptor cells”?",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus class",
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Environment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus is defined as an energy change that affects an organism through its receptor cells. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is defined as “a group of stimuli sharing a predetermined set of common elements”?",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus class",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Antecedent",
                  "Environment",
                  "Stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus class is defined as a group of stimuli sharing a predetermined set of common elements. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A stimulus class may described by all of the following EXCEPT:",
                "correctAnswer": "Informally",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Functionality",
                  "Temporally",
                  "Formally"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus classes may be described by functionality, temporally, or formally. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a stimulus class, there is a green truck, a green ball, and a green candy. Which dimension do all stimuli in this class have in common?",
                "correctAnswer": "Formal dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal dimension",
                  "Functional dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formal dimension refers to stimuli that have physical attributes in common. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Attention from peers, access to toys, and escape from schoolwork are all part of a stimulus class, because they all may occur immediately following the child’s behavior. Which dimension do all stimuli in this class have in common?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Formal dimension",
                  "Functional dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The temporal dimension refers to stimuli that occur at the same time in relation to problem behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The school bus arrives and honks the horn. The parent tells the child that it’s time to go get on the bus. The child’s alarm went off which indicates time to go to school. All of these stimuli evoke the same behavior of the child walking out of the house and on to the bus. These stimuli share which dimension to form a stimulus class?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal dimension",
                  "Formal dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The functional dimension refers to stimuli that have the same effect on behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Your stomach aches with hunger. The oven timer goes off indicating the food is ready. You see that a fork and plate are readily available. All of these stimuli evoke the same behavior. You eat. These stimuli share which dimension to form a stimulus class?",
                "correctAnswer": "Functional dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal dimension",
                  "Formal dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The functional dimension refers to stimuli that have the same effect on behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The basketball is available. Your opponent has their hands up trying to block your shot. The buzzer is about to go off. All of these stimuli occur prior to the behavior of shooting a ball. These stimuli share which dimension to form a stimulus class?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Formal dimension",
                  "Functional dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The temporal dimension refers to stimuli that occur at the same time in relation to problem behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)"
              },
              {
                "question": "There is a ball, a toy truck, and a candy within close proximity to the child. These stimuli share which dimension to form a stimulus class?",
                "correctAnswer": "Formal dimension",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal dimension",
                  "Functional dimension",
                  "Informal dimension"
                ],
                "explanation": "The formal dimension refers to stimuli that have physical attributes in common. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 27-28)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Stimulus equivalence",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Sara was taught a spoken word Apple is the same as a written word Apple. She was also taught a written word Apple was same as a picture of Apple. Sara being able to give the picture of Apple to the therapist, when the therapist says “Apple” is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus equivalence",
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Symmetry"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity occurs when A=B and B=C are trained. Then A=C is demonstrated without training. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Stimulus equivalence is present when the client can demonstrate: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity, symmetry,  AND transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Transitivity only",
                  "Reflexivity, symmetry, transitive",
                  "Reflexive, symmetry, AND transitivity"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity A=A, Symmetry A=B, B=A, Transitivity A=C. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John was able to demonstrate that A=A, and the B=A after being taught that A=B. He was also able to demonstrate that A=C after being taught that A=B and B=A. John has demonstrated:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus equivalence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Symmetry"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus equivalence is demonstrated when reflexivity, symmetry, AND transitivity have been demonstrated. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Being able to show that A=A without prior training demonstrates which test of stimulus equivalence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity is demonstrating that A=A without training. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Being able to show that B=A after being trained that A=B demonstrates which test of stimulus equivalence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry is demonstrated when showing that B=A after being trained that A=B. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Being able to show that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C demonstrates which test of stimulus equivalence?",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Reflexivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity is demonstrated when showing that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a demonstration of Reflexivity?",
                "correctAnswer": "Showing that A=A without being trained",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Showing that B=A after being trained that A=B",
                  "Showing that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C",
                  "Showing that A=A after being trained"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity is demonstrated by showing that A=A without being trained. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a demonstration of Symmetry?",
                "correctAnswer": "Showing that B=A after being trained that A=B",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Showing that A=A without being trained",
                  "Showing that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C",
                  "Showing that A=A after being trained"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry is demonstrated by showing that B=A after being trained that A=B. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a demonstration of transitivity?",
                "correctAnswer": "Showing that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Showing that B=A after being trained that A=B",
                  "Showing that A=A without being trained",
                  "Showing that A=A after being trained"
                ],
                "explanation": "Transitivity is demonstrated when showing that A=C after being trained that A=B and B=C. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A child is shown the written word A, then points to the written word A. This is demonstrates:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexivity",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Symmetry",
                  "Transitivity",
                  "Stimulus equivalence"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexivity is demonstrating that A=A without training. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 398-399)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Reflexive relations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "A loud sound elicits your eye to blink. This is unlearned behavior. This stimulus-response relation is called a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflex",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Respondent behavior",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A reflex is the unlearned stimulus-response relation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A loud sound elicits your eye to blink. This is unlearned behavior. The loud sound is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned stimulus is the stimulus which elicits the response without prior learning. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A loud sound elicits your eye to blink. This is unlearned behavior. The behavior of “blinking your eye” is specifically a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned response is the specific term for a respondent behavior whose stimulus-response relation is unlearned. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A loud sound elicits your eye to blink. The general term for this stimulus-response behavior is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Respondent behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent behavior is the general term for any behavior with this similar stimulus-response relation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The temperature in the room is warm. You begin to perspire. The general term for this stimulus-response behavior is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Respondent behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent behavior is the general term for any behavior with this similar stimulus-response relation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The temperature in the room is warm. You begin to perspire. The behavior of perspiring is specifically a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned response is the specific term for a respondent behavior whose stimulus-response relation is unlearned. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The temperature in the room is warm. You begin to perspire. The warm temperature is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflex",
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned stimulus is the stimulus which elicits the response without prior learning. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The temperature in the room is warm. You begin to perspire. This stimulus-response relation is called a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflex",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Respondent behavior",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A reflex is the unlearned stimulus-response relation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The temperature in the room is warm. You begin to perspire. Which of the following is the unconditioned stimulus in the example?",
                "correctAnswer": "The warm room",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "You perspire",
                  "The warm room elicits perspiration",
                  "There is no unconditioned stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned stimulus is the stimulus which elicits the response without prior learning. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A loud sound elicits your eye to blink. This is unlearned behavior. Which of the following is the unconditioned response?",
                "correctAnswer": "Your eye blinks",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The loud sound",
                  "The loud sound elicits your eye to blink",
                  "There is no unconditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "The unconditioned response is the specific term for a respondent behavior whose stimulus-response relation is unlearned. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Respondent conditioning & contiguity",
			"quizquestion": [			
              {
                "question": "John went out to dinner and ate a pulled chicken sandwich. That night, he became sick with food poisoning. Now every time John sees pulled chicken, he feels nauseous. Pulled chicken is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Conditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A conditioned stimulus is one that elicits a response as a result of respondent conditioning. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John went out to dinner and ate a pulled chicken sandwich. That night, he became sick with food poisoning. Now every time John sees pulled chicken, he feels nauseous. “Feeling nauseous” now functions as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "A conditioned response is the response in a conditioned reflex. It is elicited by a conditioned stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John went out to dinner and ate pulled chicken sandwich. That night, he became sick with food poisoning. Now every time John sees pulled chicken, he feels nauseous. Seeing pulled chicken had never had this effect on John’s body before that night. Before that night, seeing pulled chicken was a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned response",
                  "Conditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "A neutral stimulus is one which does not elicit respondent behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John went out to dinner and ate pulled chicken sandwich. That night, he became sick with food poisoning. Now every time John sees pulled chicken, he feels nauseous. Vomiting, that first time, is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned response",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "An unconditioned response is one which is elicited by a stimulus without prior training. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Respondent conditioning is most effective when:",
                "correctAnswer": "The NS is presented just before or at the same time as the US",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The NS is presented at the same time or just after the US",
                  "The NS is presented a while before the US",
                  "The NS is presented a while after the US"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent conditioning is most effective when the neutral stimulus is presented just before or at the same time as the unconditioned stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A neutral stimulus can become a conditioned stimulus by being paired with a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Either a conditioned or unconditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A neutral stimulus can be paired with either a conditioned or unconditioned stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The presentation of a loud noise elicits an accelerated heart rate. A toy is presented just before the loud noise repeatedly. Now the presentation of the toy results in an accelerated heart rate. The accelerated heart rate following the loud noise is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned stimulus",
                  "Conditioned response",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "An unconditioned response is one which is elicited by a stimulus without prior training. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The presentation of a loud noise elicits an accelerated heart rate. A toy is presented just before the loud noise repeatedly. Now the presentation of the toy results in an accelerated heart rate. The presentation of the loud noise is an example of a(n)",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned stimulus",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Unconditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "The presentation of the loud noise is an example of an unconditioned stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The presentation of a loud noise elicits an accelerated heart rate. A toy is presented just before the loud noise repeatedly. Now the presentation of the toy results in an accelerated heart rate. Now, the toy functions as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned response",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Conditioned response"
                ],
                "explanation": "A conditioned stimulus is one that elicits a response as a result of respondent conditioning. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The procedure of repeatedly presenting a conditioned stimulus without the unconditioned stimulus until the conditioned stimulus no longer elicits the conditioned response is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Respondent extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Respondent conditioning",
                  "Operant conditioning",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent extinction occurs by repeatedly presenting a conditioned stimulus without the unconditioned stimulus until the conditioned stimulus no longer elicits the conditioned response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-30)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Operant conditioning",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which type of behavior is made more likely or less likely based on its history of consequences?",
                "correctAnswer": "Operant behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Respondent behavior",
                  "Respondent conditioning",
                  "Operant conditioning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Operant behavior is made more likely or less likely based on its history of consequences. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of behavior is elicited by antecedent stimuli?",
                "correctAnswer": "Respondent behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Operant behavior",
                  "Respondent conditioning",
                  "Operant conditioning"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent behavior is elicited by antecedent stimuli. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is known as the process and selective effects of consequences on behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Operant conditioning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Operant behavior",
                  "Respondent conditioning",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Operant conditioning is the process and selective effects of consequences on behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is known as the process of new stimuli acquiring the ability to elicit responses?",
                "correctAnswer": "Respondent conditioning",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Operant behavior",
                  "Operant conditioning",
                  "Respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent conditioning is known as the process of new stimuli acquiring the ability to elicit responses. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When operant conditioning consists of an increase in response frequency, what has taken place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reinforcement is what has taken place when operant conditioning consists of an increase in response frequency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In operant conditioning the stimulus change contingent on the behavior that results in an increase in that behavior is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "In operant conditioning the stimulus change contingent on the behavior that results in an increase in that behavior is known as a reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In operant conditioning the stimulus change contingent on the behavior that results in a decrease in that behavior is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "In operant conditioning the stimulus change contingent on the behavior that results in a decrease in that behavior is known as a punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When operant conditioning consists of a decrease in response frequency, what has taken place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "In operant conditioning, punishment occurs when there is a decrease in response frequency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Operant conditioning is most effective when:",
                "correctAnswer": "Consequences are delivered immediately following the response",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The learner is aware that their behavior was reinforced",
                  "Consequences are delivered immediately before the response",
                  "The learner is unaware of the contingency in place"
                ],
                "explanation": "Operant conditioning is most effective when consequences are delivered immediately following the response. Operant conditioning is effective regardless of the awareness of the learner. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Consequences affect:",
                "correctAnswer": "Only future behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Only current behavior",
                  "Both current and future behavior",
                  "Neither current nor future behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Consequences affect only future behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 31-34)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Respondent-operant interactions",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "A behavior technician presented a toy slightly before presenting a highly preferred toy, allowing for the overlap of both toys. This procedure was repeated several times. This procedure best illustrates: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Backward conditioning",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Premack principle"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing is the procedure for establishing a stimulus as a conditioned reinforcer or punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A behavior technician presented a toy slightly before presenting a highly preferred toy, allowing for the overlap of both toys. Both toys now function as reinforcers. The toy that was a neutral stimulus before, now functions as a: ",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "The toy now functions as a conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A neutral stimulus can be made into a reinforcer by:",
                "correctAnswer": "Pairing it with an unconditioned stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pairing it with an unconditioned response",
                  "Presenting in individually after a response multiple times",
                  "A neutral stimulus cannot be made into a reinforcer. "
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing is the process of pairing a neutral stimulus, with a reinforcer or punisher, which results in the neutral stimulus acquiring the behavior altering properties of the reinforcer or punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Behavior analysts should focus on:",
                "correctAnswer": "Both operant AND respondent behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Operant behavior",
                  "Respondent behavior",
                  "Neither operant nor respondent behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Respondent and operant behavior are relevant to behavior analysts. Often, both behavior may occur simultaneously.  (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a child, and have demonstrated that treats are reinforcing for the child. Praise, however, does not appear to be reinforcing. What can you do to establish praise as a reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver praise at the same time that you deliver treats as a reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deliver praise instead of treats as a reinforcer",
                  "Deliver praise before the behavior, then deliver treats after the behavior",
                  "Deliver treats before the behavior, then deliver praise after the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Deliver praise at the same time that you deliver treats as a reinforcer. This is known as stimulus-stimulus pairing. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a child, and have demonstrated that treats are reinforcing for the child. Praise, however, does not appear to be reinforcing. You deliver praise at the same time that you deliver treats as a reinforcer. Praise now functions as a reinforcer. Praise is now a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Praise now functions as a conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are working with a child, and have demonstrated that treats are reinforcing for the child. Praise, however, does not appear to have any reinforcing or punishing properties. You deliver praise at the same time that you deliver treats as a reinforcer. Praise now functions as a reinforcer. Prior to stimulus-stimulus pairing, praise was a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to stimulus-stimulus pairing, praise was a neutral stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You deliver a reprimand to your supervisee, however it does not result in a decrease in inappropriate workplace behavior. If you wanted to establish reprimands as a punisher, what might you do?",
                "correctAnswer": "Deliver a reprimand just before delivering a pay decrease",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Continue delivering reprimands until they function as a punisher",
                  "Focus on increasing appropriate replacement behavior through positive reinforcement",
                  "Deliver reprimands on a delayed schedule, at least 1 day following the behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive reinforcement should always be used (especially in the work place!) However that wasn’t the question. If you wanted to establish reprimands as a punisher, it should be paired with a punisher (such as a pay decrease). (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You deliver a reprimand to your supervisee, however it does not result in a decrease in inappropriate workplace behavior. Reprimands do not appear to function as a reinforcer or punisher. You pair reprimands with a pay decrease, and reprimands now function as a punisher. Prior to stimulus-stimulus pairing, reprimands functioned as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to stimulus-stimulus pairing, reprimand was a neutral stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You deliver a reprimand to your supervisee, however it does not result in a decrease in inappropriate workplace behavior. Reprimands do not appear to function as a reinforcer or punisher. You pair reprimands with a pay decrease, and reprimands now function as a punisher. Reprimands now function as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "reprimands now function as a conditioned punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 29-37)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Unconditioned reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are teaching your dog basic commands like sit, stay, come and give paw. Each time he correctly displays the command, you provide him with a treat. This increases those appropriate responses. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a common example of a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned positive reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Food",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Removal of pain",
                  "Money",
                  "Praise"
                ],
                "explanation": "Food is a common example of a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned positive reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a common example of a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned positive reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Warmth",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pain",
                  "Removal of pain",
                  "Money"
                ],
                "explanation": "Warmth is a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned positive reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a common example of a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned negative reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Removal of pain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pain",
                  "Sexual stimulation",
                  "Water"
                ],
                "explanation": "Removal of pain is an unconditioned negative reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a common example of a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned negative reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "The termination of a loud noise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A loud noise",
                  "The removal of water",
                  "Food"
                ],
                "explanation": "The termination of a loud noise is a stimulus that may function as an unconditioned negative reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "All of the following are unconditioned reinforcers except:",
                "correctAnswer": "Pain",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Removal of a loud noise",
                  "Food ",
                  "Water"
                ],
                "explanation": "Pain is not an unconditioned reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What has occurred when behavior has increased due to the delivery of consequences that have no particular learning history?",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcement",
                  "Unconditioned punishment",
                  "Conditioned punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Unconditioned reinforcement occurs when behavior increases due to the delivery of consequences that have no particular learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joe has a headache and takes Ibuprofen. The headache goes away. Joe is more likely to take Ibuprofen in the future when he has a headache. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of negative reinforcement. The pain goes away, which increases the likelihood of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What has occurred when behavior has increased due to the delivery of consequences that have acquired reinforcing properties through a learning history.",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conditioned reinforcement occurs when behavior increases due to the delivery of consequences that have acquired reinforcing properties through a learning history. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joe is cold and puts a blanket around him. Joe is now a comfortable temperature, and is more likely to put a blanket around him when he is cold. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Wearing a blanket adds heat, and reinforced the behavior. This is positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conditioned reinforcement",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "A child and his mother are at the store. The child sees a toy he wants. He screams. His mother is embarrassed that everyone around her is staring, so buys the toy. He stops screaming and people stop staring. The mother is more likely to buy a toy when the child screams in the store in the future because of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The contingency influencing the mother is negative reinforcement. The child stopped crying, which increased the likelihood that the mom would do this again. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A child is constantly crying. His mother offers him a lollipop to stop crying. The child stops. What kind of reinforcement is reinforcing the mother behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The contingency influencing the mother is negative reinforcement. The child stopped crying, which increased the likelihood that the mom would do this again. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mrs. Smith has a dog. Every time the dog sits when she says “sit” she gives him a treat. In the future, her dog sits more often every time she says “sit.” This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A parent wants to deliver a sticker to Ryan every time he says “Please.” This would be considered positive reinforcement if:",
                "correctAnswer": "The behavior of saying “Please” increases over time.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The behavior of saying “Please” decreases over time.",
                  "The behavior of saying “Please” does not change over time.",
                  "The behavior of sticker giving decreases over time."
                ],
                "explanation": "A stimulus is a reinforcer only if the behavior for which it was delivered contingently increases in the future. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Bob gets put in the timeout room each time he yells in the classroom. In the future, the frequency of yelling increases. In this case, the timeout room is functioning as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "The intervention was likely in place to decrease the behavior, but it appears to be reinforcing the behavior instead. This is an example of negative reinforcement because he is removed from the class and the behavior increases. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Money",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Sex",
                  "Food",
                  "Pain"
                ],
                "explanation": "Money is a conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Praise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Warmth",
                  "Water",
                  "Removal of pain"
                ],
                "explanation": "Praise is an example of a conditioned reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is defined as a reinforcer that as a result of being paired with many reinforcers it does not depend on a current EO for any particular form of reinforcement for its effectiveness?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned reinforcer",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Motivating operation"
                ],
                "explanation": "A generalize conditioned reinforcer is a reinforcer that as a result of being paired with many reinforcers it does not depend on a current EO for any particular form of reinforcement for its effectiveness. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an example of a generalized conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Tokens in a token economy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Money",
                  "Praise",
                  "All answers provided are correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "A generalize conditioned reinforcer is a reinforcer that as a result of being paired with many reinforcers it does not depend on a current EO for any particular form of reinforcement for its effectiveness. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an example of a generalized conditioned reinforcer?",
                "correctAnswer": "Tokens in a token economy",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Food",
                  "A toy",
                  "Removal of pain"
                ],
                "explanation": "A generalize conditioned reinforcer is a reinforcer that as a result of being paired with many reinforcers it does not depend on a current EO for any particular form of reinforcement for its effectiveness. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 269-274)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Unconditioned punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "What is a stimulus that can decrease the future frequency of a behavior that precedes it without prior pairing with other punishers?",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of an unconditioned punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jerry has enuresis where he often wets the bed. The behavior analyst uses a urine alarm where when it senses wetness, it wakes him up with a loud beep. The loud beep decreases the future frequency of wetting the bed, and is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive punishment occurs when a stimulus is added which decreases the future frequency of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following are not negative side effects of punishment?",
                "correctAnswer": "Aversive control",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Emotional outbursts",
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Aggression"
                ],
                "explanation": "Aversive control is a term used to mean any form of punishment or negative reinforcement (any application of aversive stimulation). (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following stimuli may function as an unconditioned punisher?",
                "correctAnswer": "All answers are correct",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Loud noise",
                  "Pain",
                  "Physical restraint"
                ],
                "explanation": "All answers provided are stimuli that may function as an unconditioned punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following stimuli may function as an unconditioned punisher?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extreme muscular effort",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "All answers are correct",
                  "Reprimand",
                  "Planned ignore"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extreme muscular effort may function as an unconditioned punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally is experiencing pain in her foot, until she moves her foot away from her dog who is nibbling on her toes. Sally is more likely to move her foot in a similar situation in the future. This contingency is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of negative reinforcement. There was an increase in the future likelihood of the behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Sally sets her foot down next to her dog, who begins nibbling on her toes. Sally is less likely to put her foot down in front of her dog in the future. This contingency is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Pain in the foot was added when she placed her foot near the dog. This made her less likely to do so in the future. This is positive punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when an aversive stimulus is removed contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in an increased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement occurs when an aversive stimulus is removed contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in an increased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again."
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when an appetitive stimulus is removed contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in a decreased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again.",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative punishment occurs when an appetitive stimulus is removed contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in a decreased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when an aversive stimulus is delivered contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in a decreased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again. ",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Positive punishment occurs when an aversive stimulus is delivered contingent on the person’s behavior, which results in a decreased likelihood of engaging in that behavior again. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-337)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Conditioned punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "David raised his hand in class to volunteer to help. The teacher enthusiastically praised David, “You are awesome!  Such a fine young boy who is always willing to help!”  In the future, David's handraising to volunteer decreases. The teacher’s praise appears to function as a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Punishment",
                  "Reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The teacher was likely attempting positive reinforcement, but praise for this child had the opposite effect on the child’s behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which one is not a form of non-exclusionary time out?",
                "correctAnswer": "Partition time out",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Contingent observation",
                  "Time-out ribben"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partition time out is a form exclusionary time out. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "After determining it necessary, Raquel has started removing a token from Matthew’s board every time he engages in aggression towards others. Following this intervention, Matthew’s aggression has decreased. Raquel is implementing",
                "correctAnswer": "Response cost",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Token economy",
                  "Time-Out",
                  "DRO"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of a response cost. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ian was reading a book in the doctors waiting room. A lady approached him and began talking to him about his book. From now on when he is in a waiting room he does not read books. This contingency is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Negative punishment",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This is an example of positive punishment. The negative attention that Ian received was a stimulus added which decreased the frequency of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Michael threw a paper on the school playground. The teacher then told him to pick the paper and throw it in the garbage and  also collect all the other papers from the school playground. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Restitutional overcorrection",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response cost",
                  "Reprimand",
                  "Contingent exercise"
                ],
                "explanation": "Restitutional overcorrection takes place be requiring the learner to repair the damage from caused by the behavior, and also improving the environment to a better standard than where it was prior to the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may function as a conditioned punisher?",
                "correctAnswer": "Praise",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Pain",
                  "Loud noise",
                  "Physical restraint"
                ],
                "explanation": "Pain, loud noise, and physical restraint are all primary punishers. Praise, on the other hand, may unintentionally be conditioned to be a punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy engages in frequent physical aggression. After trying more positive interventions, you decide to include reprimands as punishment. Reprimands do not seem to have a reinforcing or punishing effect on Lucy’s behavior. You use a reprimand just before putting Lucy in time out, until reprimands function as punishers. Prior to being paired with time out, reprimands appear to have functioned as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Neutral stimulus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Stimulus-stimulus pairing"
                ],
                "explanation": "Prior to being paired with time out, reprimands appear to have functioned as a neutral stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy engages in frequent physical aggression. After trying more positive interventions, you decide to include reprimands as punishment. Reprimands do not seem to have a reinforcing or punishing effect on Lucy’s behavior. You use a reprimand just before putting Lucy in time out, until reprimands function as punishers. After being paired with time out, reprimands functioned as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned punisher",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Neutral stimulus",
                  "Stimulus-stimulus pairing"
                ],
                "explanation": "Conditioned punishers are those that have been paired with a punisher to establish its punishing effect. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy engages in frequent physical aggression. After trying more positive interventions, you decide to include reprimands as punishment. Reprimands do not seem to have a reinforcing or punishing effect on Lucy’s behavior. You use a reprimand just before putting Lucy in time out, until reprimands function as punishers. The process of establishing reprimands as a punisher is called:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned punisher",
                  "Unconditioned punisher",
                  "Neutral stimulus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus-stimulus pairing is the process of pairing a punisher or reinforcer with a neutral stimulus to give that stimulus its punishing/reinforcing effect. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Lucy engages in frequent physical aggression. After trying more positive interventions, you decide to include reprimands as punishment. With this contingency in place, there was no apparent increase or decrease in the frequency of physical aggression. What is the best description of the contingency in place:",
                "correctAnswer": "Neither reinforcement nor punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Positive punishment",
                  "Negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Neither reinforcement nor punishment are occurring because there was no change in the future frequency of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 327-371)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Schedules of reinforcement and punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Sean put himself on a reinforcement study schedule. After every 15 powerpoint slides of studying, he allowed himself 3 minutes of social media. This is an example of",
                "correctAnswer": "Fixed ratio",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed interval",
                  "Variable ratio",
                  "Variable interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "Fixed ratio schedule delivers reinforcement contingent on a set number of responses. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The school teacher delivers the student a break from school work after exactly 1 hour since their last break. Before taking another break they must complete at least one problem on their assignment. What is this schedule of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Fixed interval",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Variable interval",
                  "Fixed ratio",
                  "Variable ratio"
                ],
                "explanation": "Fixed interval schedules deliver reinforcement after the first response after an exact duration time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which schedule of reinforcement typically has a graph with a scallop between delivery of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Fixed interval",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Variable interval",
                  "Fixed ratio",
                  "Variable ratio"
                ],
                "explanation": "Fixed interval schedules typically have a graph that includes a scallop while waiting for reinforcement to be available. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The school teacher delivers the student a break from school work after around 1 hour since their last break. Sometimes it’s 55 min, and sometimes it’s just over an hour. Before taking another break they must complete at least one problem on their assignment. What is this schedule of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Variable interval",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed interval",
                  "Fixed ratio",
                  "Variable ratio"
                ],
                "explanation": "The variable interval schedule delivers reinforcement after the first response after variable durations of time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA delivers praise after every correct response. Which schedule of reinforcement is this?",
                "correctAnswer": "Continuous reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Variable ratio",
                  "Compound schedule",
                  "Concurrent schedule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Continuous reinforcement (CRF) is the delivery of reinforcement for every correct response (FR1). (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The BCBA delivers praise after 1 correct response, and sometimes he delivers praise every 3 or 4 correct responses. It is generally about every 2 correct responses, reinforcement is delivered. What is this schedule of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Variable ratio",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed ratio",
                  "Variable interval",
                  "Fixed interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "Variable ratio schedules of reinforcement deliver reinforcement following a variable number of responses. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following compound schedules of reinforcement does NOT have a clear discriminative stimulus?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mixed & Tandem",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple",
                  "Mixed",
                  "Tandem"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mixed and Tandem schedules of reinforcement do NOT have a clear discriminative stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following compound schedules of reinforcement has a clear discriminative stimulus?",
                "correctAnswer": "Multiple",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mixed",
                  "Tandem",
                  "Mixed & Tandem"
                ],
                "explanation": "A multiple schedule does have a clear discriminative stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which schedule of reinforcement relates most to the Matching Law?",
                "correctAnswer": "Concurrent schedule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fixed interval",
                  "Fixed ratio",
                  "Variable interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "The concurrent schedule of reinforcement relates most to the matching law. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following schedules combines the number of responses and time?",
                "correctAnswer": "Alternative & Conjunctive",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Alternative",
                  "Conjunctive",
                  "Concurrent"
                ],
                "explanation": "Both alternative and conjunctive schedules of reinforcement combine the number of responses and time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 305-322)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Extinction",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "A procedure in which reinforcement for a previously reinforced behavior is no longer followed by reinforcement, resulting in a decrease in the future frequency of that behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": " Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Pivotal behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction occurs when which reinforcement for a previously reinforced behavior is no longer followed by reinforcement, resulting in a decrease in the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is a brief increase in the frequency in responding when extinction is initially implemented?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction burst",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction bursts often occur when there is an increase in the behavior when extinction is initially implemented. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Michael is given attention every time he engages in angry outbursts. His family begins to ignore Michael whenever he engages in angry outbursts. At first, his angry outbursts increase, but then they begin to decrease, to the point where Michael no longer engages in angry outbursts. One day, after not engaging in the behavior for weeks, Michael engages in angry outbursts. What procedure did Michael’s family implement to make angry outbursts decrease?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction occurs when which reinforcement for a previously reinforced behavior is no longer followed by reinforcement, resulting in a decrease in the future frequency of that behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Michael is given attention every time he engages in angry outbursts. His family begins to ignore Michael whenever he engages in angry outbursts. At first, his angry outbursts increase, but then they begin to decrease, to the point where Michael no longer engages in angry outbursts. One day, after not engaging in the behavior for weeks, Michael engages in angry outbursts. What is the term to describe the initial increase in angry outbursts that Michael experienced?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction burst",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction bursts often occur when there is an increase in the behavior when extinction is initially implemented. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Michael is given attention every time he engages in angry outbursts. His family begins to ignore Michael whenever he engages in angry outbursts. At first, his angry outbursts increase, but then they begin to decrease, to the point where Michael no longer engages in angry outbursts. One day, after not engaging in the behavior for weeks, Michael engages in angry outbursts. What is the term to describe the occurrence of angry outbursts after weeks without concern?",
                "correctAnswer": "Spontaneous recovery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Extinction",
                  "Extinction burst"
                ],
                "explanation": "Spontaneous recovery occurs when the behavior of concern returns after extinction has taken place. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Michael is given attention every time he engages in angry outbursts. His family begins to ignore Michael whenever he engages in angry outbursts. At first, his angry outbursts increase, but then they begin to decrease, to the point where Michael no longer engages in angry outbursts. One day, after not engaging in the behavior for weeks, Michael engages in angry outbursts. What was maintaining the angry outbursts from the beginning?",
                "correctAnswer": "Positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Spontaneous recover"
                ],
                "explanation": "Michael was receiving attention whenever he engaged in angry outbursts. This is positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sara would curse while at school, which would result in her getting out of school work. Her teacher began requiring her to complete her school work even when she would curse. Sara began cursing more, initially, but then the behavior quickly decreased. The behavior hadn’t happened for days, when Sara began cursing. What was maintaining Sara’s cursing from the beginning?",
                "correctAnswer": "Negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Positive reinforcement",
                  "Spontaneous recovery"
                ],
                "explanation": "Negative reinforcement was occurring, because Sara would get out of school work (removal of a stimulus) which resulted in an increase of swearing. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sara would curse while at school, which would result in her getting out of school work. Her teacher began requiring her to complete her school work even when she would curse. Sara began cursing more, initially, but then the behavior quickly decreased. The behavior hadn’t happened for days, when Sara began cursing. What procedure did the school teacher implement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Differential reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The school teacher implemented extinction by not allowing Sara to get out of her school work. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sara would curse while at school, which would result in her getting out of school work. Her teacher began requiring her to complete her school work even when she would curse. Sara began cursing more, initially, but then the behavior quickly decreased. The behavior hadn’t happened for days, when Sara began cursing. What is the term to describe the initial increase in cursing, when the teacher required school work completion?",
                "correctAnswer": "Extinction burst",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction ",
                  "Spontaneous recovery",
                  "Negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Extinction bursts often occur when there is an increase in the behavior when extinction is initially implemented. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sara would curse while at school, which would result in her getting out of school work. Her teacher began requiring her to complete her school work even when she would curse. Sara began cursing more, initially, but then the behavior quickly decreased. The behavior hadn’t happened for days, when Sara began cursing. What is the term to describe the occurrence of swearing after days of no cursing?",
                "correctAnswer": "Spontaneous recovery",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction burst",
                  "Negative reinforcement",
                  "Extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Spontaneous recovery occurs when the behavior of concern returns after extinction has taken place. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 457-467)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Automatic reinforcement and punishment",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Ashley loves tequila!  Every time Ashley takes a few shots of tequila, she gets a nice warm, fuzzy feeling.  As a result, Ashley takes more shots.  This best describes:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic  positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic  negative reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This behavior did not require another person. It was automatic positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The boy runs fast down the hill. He falls down and scratches his knee. He is not as likely to run down hills in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic negative punishment",
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The boy did not require another person to deliver the stimulus of pain. This was automatic positive punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The boy runs fast down the hill. His mother scolds him for being reckless. The boy is not as likely to run down hills in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated positive punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Socially mediated negative punishment",
                  "Automatic positive punishment",
                  "Automatic negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Another person delivered the aversive stimulus (scold), which decreased behavior. This is socially mediated positive punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The boy runs fast down the hill. His mother immediately takes away his favorite toy that he is holding. The boy is less likely to run down hills in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Socially mediated positive punishment",
                  "Automatic positive punishment",
                  "Automatic negative punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Another person removed a stimulus, decreasing the behavior. This is socially mediated negative punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The boy runs fast down the hill. He drops his favorite toy which gets lost. The boy is less likely to run down hills in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic negative punishment",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic positive punishment",
                  "Socially mediated negative punishment",
                  "Socially mediated positive punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Another person was not involved, but a stimulus was removed (his toy was lost).This is automatic negative punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The removal of an aversive stimulus without another person present, that increases the likelihood that the preceding behavior will occur again in the future is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic negative punishment",
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated positive punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Automatic negative reinforcement occurs when the removal of an aversive stimulus without another person present, that increases the likelihood that the preceding behavior will occur again in the future. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas sees his friend’s wallet unattended. Thomas takes $20 while his friend isn’t looking. Thomas is likely to do this again in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The friend was not present, and the stimulus was added (money). This is automatic positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas asks his friend for $20. His friend pays up. Thomas is more likely to ask his friend again in the future. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Socially meditated negative reinforcement",
                  "Automatic positive reinforcement",
                  "Automatic negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The friend was present, and delivered the stimulus. This is socially mediated positive reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas has an itch on his back. He reaches and is able to relieve the sensation. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Thomas was able to remove the itching sensation by scratching his own back. This is automatic negative reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas has an itch on his back. He asks his friend to scratch his back. His friend does, and the itching sensation goes away. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                  "Automatic positive reinforcement",
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Thomas was able to have his friend scratch his back, and the aversive stimulus was removed. This is an example of socially mediated negative reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 534-536)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Stimulus control, stimulus discrimination, & conditional discriminations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which term describes a stimulus that indicates the availability of reinforcement:",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔ",
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "SD describes a stimulus that indicates the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which term describes a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SΔ is a term for a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which term describes a stimulus that indicates the availability of punishment?",
                "correctAnswer": "SDP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔ",
                  "SD",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SDP is a stimulus that indicates the availability of punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which term describes a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of punishment?",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔ",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SΔP is a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following will establish stimulus control?",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus discrimination training",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Extinction",
                  "Reinforcement",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Although extinction and reinforcement are essential components to stimulus discrimination training, alone, extinction or reinforcement will not establish stimulus control. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Elaine is given $.25 whenever she asks her grandfather for money. Seeing her grandfather indicates that reinforcement is available. However, when her grandmother is present, Elaine is put in time out for asking for money, which has decreased the frequency of asking for money in her grandmother’s presence. Her grandfather appears to be an:",
                "correctAnswer": " SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔ",
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "SD describes a stimulus that indicates the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Elaine is given $.25 whenever she asks her grandfather for money. Seeing her grandfather indicates that reinforcement is available, when he is absent, reinforcement is unavailable. However, when her grandmother is present, Elaine is put in time out for asking for money, which has decreased the frequency of asking for money in her grandmother’s presence. The grandfather’s absence appears to be an:",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SΔ is a term for a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Elaine is given $.25 whenever she asks her grandfather for money. Seeing her grandfather indicates that reinforcement is available. However, when her grandmother is present, Elaine is put in time out for asking for money, which has decreased the frequency of asking for money in her grandmother’s presence. The grandmother’s absence is likely an:",
                "correctAnswer": "SΔP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SDP",
                  "SΔ",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SΔP is a stimulus that indicates the unavailability of punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Elaine is given $.25 whenever she asks her grandfather for money. Seeing her grandfather indicates that reinforcement is available. However, when her grandmother is present, Elaine is put in time out for asking for money, which has decreased the frequency of asking for money in her grandmother’s presence. The grandmother’s absence is likely an:",
                "correctAnswer": "SDP",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔ",
                  "SD",
                  "SΔP"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SDP is a stimulus that indicates the availability of punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Elaine is given $.25 whenever she asks her grandfather for money. Seeing her grandfather indicates that reinforcement is available. However, when her grandfather is absent, reinforcement is not available. Elaine’s grandfather appears to have:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus control",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Discriminative stimulus",
                  "Antecedent stimuli",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus control is when the antecedent stimulus alters the response reate, latency, duration, or amplitude of a response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 393-396)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Multiple functions of a single stimulus",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "In a behavior chain, the SD for the second behavior is usually the ________ for the first behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "SΔ",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "In a behavior chain, the SD for the second behavior is usually the reinforcer for the first behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In a behavior chain, the reinforcer for the second behavior is usually the ______ for the third behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SΔ",
                  "MO",
                  "Reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "In a behavior chain, the reinforcer for the second behavior is usually the SD for the third behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank opens his fridge and sees a Coke. He grabs the Coke and closes the fridge. He opens the can and hears the “pop”. He then brings the can to his mouth and drinks the coke. The sound “pop” is likely reinforcing which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Opening the can",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Closing the fridge",
                  "Drinking the Coke",
                  "Grabbing the Coke"
                ],
                "explanation": "The “pop” is likely reinforcing the behavior that occurred just before it, which was opening the can. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": " Frank opens his fridge and sees a Coke. He grabs the Coke and closes the fridge. He opens the can and hears the “pop”. He then brings the can to his mouth and drinks the coke. The sound “pop” is likely the SD for which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Drinking the Coke",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Grabbing the coke",
                  "Opening the can",
                  "Opening the fridge"
                ],
                "explanation": "hearing “pop” is likely the SD for drinking the Coke. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank opens his fridge and sees a Coke. He grabs the Coke and closes the fridge. He opens the can and hears the “pop”. He then brings the can to his mouth and drinks the coke. Seeing the Coke in the fridge is likely reinforcing which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Opening the fridge",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Grabbing the Coke",
                  "Opening the Coke",
                  "Hearing “pop”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Opening the fridge is likely being reinforced by seeing the Coke. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Frank opens his fridge and sees a Coke. He grabs the Coke and closes the fridge. He opens the can and hears the “pop”. He then brings the can to his mouth and drinks the coke. Seeing the Coke in the fridge is likely the SD for which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Grabbing the Coke",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Opening the can",
                  "Opening the fridge",
                  "Drinking the Coke"
                ],
                "explanation": "Seeing the drink in the fridge is likely the SD for grabbing the Coke. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jessica hears the doorbell and she opens the door. Her friend is outside and asks if Jessica wants to play. Jessica says “yes”. Her friend says “let’s play outside”. They both go outside and play in their front yard. Seeing her friend outside the door and asking Jessica to play is likely reinforcing which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Opening the door",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Hearing the doorbell",
                  "Saying “yes”",
                  "Going outside"
                ],
                "explanation": "Opening the door took place just before seeing her friend. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jessica hears the doorbell and she opens the door. Her friend is outside and asks if Jessica wants to play. Jessica says “yes”. Her friend says “let’s play outside”. They both go outside and play in their front yard. Seeing her friend outside the door and asking Jessica to play is likely an SD for which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Saying “Yes”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Opening the door",
                  "Hearing the doorbell",
                  "Going outside"
                ],
                "explanation": "Saying “yes” took place right after her friend asked if she wants to play. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jessica hears the doorbell and she opens the door. Her friend is outside and asks if Jessica wants to play. Jessica says “yes”. Her friend says “let’s play outside”. They both go outside and play in their front yard. Her friend saying “let’s play outside” is likely reinforcing which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Saying “yes”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Opening the door",
                  "Hearing the doorbell",
                  "Going outside"
                ],
                "explanation": "Her friend said “let’s play outside” immediately after Jessica said “yes”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jessica hears the doorbell and she opens the door. Her friend is outside and asks if Jessica wants to play. Jessica says “yes”. Her friend says “let’s play outside”. They both go outside and play in their front yard. Her friend saying “let’s play outside” is likely an SD for which behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Going outside",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Saying “yes”",
                  "Opening the door",
                  "Hearing the doorbell"
                ],
                "explanation": "They went outside right after the friend said “let’s play outside”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 435-441)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Unconditioned and conditioned motivating operations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is an unconditioned motivating operation:",
                "correctAnswer": "An increase in painful stimulation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Deprivation of money",
                  "The presence of an abusive parent",
                  "Attention deprivation"
                ],
                "explanation": "An increase in painful stimulation is the only example of a UMO present. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not a type of conditioned motivating operation?",
                "correctAnswer": "Symmetry CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Surrogate CMO",
                  "Transitive CMO",
                  "Reflexive CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Symmetry CMO is not a type of CMO. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph is hungry which increases the value of food as a reinforcer. Hunger in this example appears to be a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Establishing operation for reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abolishing operation for reinforcement",
                  "Establishing operation for punishment",
                  "Abolishing operation for punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "An establishing operation increases the value of a stimulus as a reinforcer or punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What increases the value of a stimulus as a reinforcer or punisher?",
                "correctAnswer": "Establishing operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abolishing operation",
                  "Conditioned motivating operation",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "An establishing operation increases the value of a stimulus as a reinforcer. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What decreases the value of a stimulus as a reinforcer or punisher?",
                "correctAnswer": "Abolishing operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Establishing operation",
                  "Conditioned motivating operation",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "An abolishing operation decreases the value of a stimulus as a reinforcer or punisher. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph warms up when the sun comes up while camping. The reinforcing value of warmth is decreased. This is an example of a(n): ",
                "correctAnswer": "AO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "EO",
                  "MO",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "An abolishing operation is resent with the reinforcing value of a stimulus is decreased. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Establishing operations are a type of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Motivating operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abolishing operation",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Punisher"
                ],
                "explanation": "Establishing operations are a type of motivating operations. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph is hungry which increases the value of food as a reinforcer. Hunger in this example appears to be a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned motivating operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned motivating operation",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Hunger is an unconditioned motivating operation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph warms up when the sun comes up while camping. The reinforcing value of warmth is decreased. This is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Unconditioned motivating operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Conditioned motivating operation",
                  "Unconditioned reinforcer",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Warmth is an unconditioned motivating operation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Joseph is standing outside and he sees a bee. The sight of the bee increases the value of a shoe to be able to smash the bee. The sight of the bee is functioning as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Conditioned motivating operation",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Unconditioned motivating operation",
                  "Discriminative stimulus",
                  "Conditioned reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "The sight of the bee increases the value of the shoe as a reinforcer. This is a learned MO. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375-390)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Transitive, reflexive, surrogate motivating operations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following establishes value altering properties by being temporally paired with an unconditioned motivating operation?",
                "correctAnswer": "Surrogate CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO",
                  "Transitive CMO",
                  "Reflexive CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Surrogate CMO’s gain their value altering properties by being temporally paired with an unconditioned motivating operation. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of motivating operation has been paired with an aversive stimulus, and now functions as a warning stimulus?",
                "correctAnswer": "Reflexive CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Transitive CMO",
                  "Surrogate CMO",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexive CMOs act as warning stimuli and have been paired with aversive stimuli in the past. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which type of motivating operation establishes the reinforcing effectiveness of another stimulus and evokes the behavior that has been reinforced by that other stimulus?",
                "correctAnswer": "Transitive CMO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reflexive CMO",
                  "Surrogate CMO",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The transitive CMO establishes the reinforcing effectiveness of another stimulus and evokes the behavior that has been reinforced by that other stimulus. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You usually watch a cooking show when you are hungry, then you go and make some food. Today, you watch the cooking show right after a meal, however, due to the learning history, you still get up to go cook food. What type of motivating operation does the cooking show appear to be?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-S",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-R",
                  "CMO-T",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Surrogate CMO’s gain their value altering properties by being temporally paired with an unconditioned motivating operation. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You give your child a stuffed animal right before he goes to bed every night. You drive in the car one morning, and give him the stuffed animal. He closes his eyes and tries to go to sleep. The stuffed animal appears to be functioning as which type of MO?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-S",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-R",
                  "CMO-T",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Surrogate CMO’s gain their value altering properties by being temporally paired with an unconditioned motivating operation. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a bee close by. The bee increases the value of the bee going away as a reinforcer. You see a shoe, grab it, and swat the bee to go away. What type of motivating operation is the bee?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-R",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-S",
                  "CMO-T",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexive CMOs act as warning stimuli and have been paired with aversive stimuli in the past. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jessica lives in a group home. Many times Jessica has seen staff completing paperwork, and then staff reprimand Jessica for inappropriate behavior. Now, whenever Jessica sees staff completing paperwork she runs over and rips up the paperwork. The sight of staff completing paperwork increases the value of removing paperwork. The sight of staff completing paperwork now functions as what type of CMO?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-R",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-S",
                  "CMO-T",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexive CMOs act as warning stimuli and have been paired with aversive stimuli in the past. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You purchase a drink from a fast food restaurant. The drink has a lid, which requires a straw. The sight of the drink and lid increases the value of the straw as reinforcement, making the sight of the drink with the lid which type of MO?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-T",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-S",
                  "CMO-R",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The transitive CMO establishes the reinforcing effectiveness of another stimulus and evokes the behavior that has been reinforced by that other stimulus. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "A “Battery Low” message appears on your phone. Removing that message is important to you, so you plug in your phone. The “Battery Low” message appears to be which type of MO?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-R",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-T",
                  "CMO-S",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Reflexive CMOs act as warning stimuli and have been paired with aversive stimuli in the past. The removal of the CMO-R is reinforcing. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While trying to charge your phone, you see the USB to micro USB cord, but do not see the wall plug-in piece. Seeing the USB cord without the wall plug-in piece increases the value of the wall plug in piece, making the cord which type of MO?",
                "correctAnswer": "CMO-T",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "CMO-R",
                  "CMO-S",
                  "CMO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The transitive CMO establishes the reinforcing effectiveness of another stimulus and evokes the behavior that has been reinforced by that other stimulus. (Cooper et al., p. 384-389)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "SDs and MOs",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are hungry and see a bucket of fried chicken in your kitchen. You grab a piece and thoroughly enjoy eating it. Being hungry is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "MO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "SΔ"
                ],
                "explanation": "MOs alter the value of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hungry and see a bucket of fried chicken in your kitchen. You grab a piece and thoroughly enjoy eating it. The sight of the bucket of chicken is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "SΔ",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SD signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hungry and see a bucket of fried chicken in your kitchen. You grab a piece and thoroughly enjoy eating it. For the contingency described, eating the chicken is likely the:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "SΔ",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The reinforcer is the last piece of a contingency, and is the appetitive stimulus which makes the behavior more likely to occur in the future. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You see a rock on the ground. You bend down to pick up the rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. In this 4 term contingency, the sight of the dog appears to be a:",
                "correctAnswer": "MO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "MOs alter the value of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You see a rock on the ground. You bend down to pick up the rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. In this 4 term contingency, the sight of the rock appears to be a:",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Behavior",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SD signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)          {"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You see a rock on the ground. You bend down to pick up the rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. In this 4 term contingency, the dog running away is likely a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Reinforcer",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD",
                  "Behavior",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The reinforcer is the last piece of a contingency, and is the appetitive stimulus which makes the behavior more likely to occur in the future. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You see a rock on the ground. You bend down to pick up the rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. In this 4 term contingency, picking up the rock is the:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "SD",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Picking up the rock is a behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While teaching a child to mand, you make sure he hasn't had food in 2 hours to ensure he is hungry. You have the cookie in sight and say “what would you like?” The child says “Cookie”. You give the child a piece of the cookie. In this 4 term contingency, food deprivation is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "MO",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior",
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "SD"
                ],
                "explanation": "MOs alter the value of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While teaching a child to mand, you make sure he hasn't had food in 2 hours to ensure he is hungry. You have the cookie in sight and say “what would you like?” The child says “Cookie”. You give the child a piece of the cookie. In this 4 term contingency, the sight of the cookie is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "SD",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "Behavior",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The SD signals the availability of reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              },
              {
                "question": "While teaching a child to mand, you make sure he hasn't had food in 2 hours to ensure he is hungry. You have the cookie in sight and say “what would you like?” The child says “Cookie”. You give the child a piece of the cookie. In this 4 term contingency, saying “cookie” is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Reinforcer",
                  "SD",
                  "MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "Saying “cookie” is a behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 377)"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "MOs and reinforcement effects",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "In relation to motivating operations, the increase in reinforcing effectiveness of some stimulus is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Value-altering effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Abative effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "A value-altering effect refers to the increase in reinforcing effectiveness of some stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In relation to motivating operations, the increase or decrease in the current frequency of behavior is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavior-altering effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Value-altering effect",
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Abative effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The behavior-altering effect refers to the increase or decrease in the current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In relation to motivating operations, the increase in the current frequency of behavior is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Evocative effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abative effect",
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Value-altering effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The evocative effect refers to an increase in the current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "In relation to motivating operations, the decrease in current frequency of behavior is a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Abative effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Value-altering effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The abative effect refers to the decrease in current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hungry and see a bucket of fried chicken in your kitchen. You grab a piece and thoroughly enjoy eating it. You being hungry increased the frequency of eating chicken. This effect is referred to as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Evocative effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abative effect",
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Value-altering effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The evocative effect refers to an increase in the current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are hungry and see a bucket of fried chicken in your kitchen. You grab a piece and thoroughly enjoy eating it. You being hungry increased the value of chicken as a reinforcer. This effect is referred to as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Value-altering effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Abative effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "A value-altering effect refers to the increase or decrease in reinforcing effectiveness of some stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You just ate food and are no longer hungry. You walk in to your kitchen and see a bucket of chicken. You do not eat the chicken. Being satiated on food decreased the value of chicken as a reinforcer. This effect is referred to as a(n): ",
                "correctAnswer": "Value-altering effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Abative effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "A value-altering effect refers to the increase or decrease in reinforcing effectiveness of some stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You just ate food and are no longer hungry. You walk in to your kitchen and see a bucket of chicken. You do not eat the chicken. Being satiated on food decreased the current frequency of eating chicken. This effect is referred to as a(n): ",
                "correctAnswer": "Abative effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Value-altering effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The abative effect refers to the decrease in current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You pick up a rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. The sight of a posturing dog increases the current frequency of picking up a rock. This effect is known as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Evocative effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Abative effect",
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Value-altering effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "The evocative effect refers to an increase in the current frequency of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are outside and see a dog posturing as if to attack. You pick up a rock, and as you do so the dog gets scared and runs away. The sight of a posturing dog increases the value of the rock as a reinforcer. This effect is known as a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Value-altering effect",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavior-altering effect",
                  "Evocative effect",
                  "Abative effect"
                ],
                "explanation": "A value-altering effect refers to the increase or decrease in reinforcing effectiveness of some stimulus. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 375)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Behavioral contingencies & functional relations",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The 4 term contingency refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "MO, SD, response, consequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Antecedent, SD, response, consequence",
                  "SD, response, MO, antecedent",
                  "Antecedent, response, SD, MO"
                ],
                "explanation": "The 4 term contingency refers to MO, SD, Response, and Reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The 3 term contingency refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Antecedent, response, consequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "SD, response, consequence",
                  "MO, response, consequence",
                  "Antecedent, response, reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "The 3 term contingency refers to antecedent, response (or behavior), consequence. Consequence is a better term than reinforcement because it also include punishment. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following reflects the main four functions of behavior commonly recognized among behavior analysts?",
                "correctAnswer": "Attention, Automatic, Escape, Tangible",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Attention, Access, Escape, Tangible",
                  "Tangible, Automatic, Escape, Sensory",
                  "Access, Automatic, Tangible, Escape"
                ],
                "explanation": "The four common functions of behavior commonly recognized among behavior analysts include attention, automatic (sensory), escape, and tangible (access). (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be an appropriate intervention for decreasing physical aggression after determining the function to be attention?",
                "correctAnswer": "Planned ignore",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Escape extinction",
                  "DRO",
                  "Sensory extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Planned ignore is the most appropriate, function based, intervention out of the options provided. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following may be an appropriate intervention for decreasing physical aggression after determining the function to be getting out of school work?",
                "correctAnswer": "Escape extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRO",
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Sensory extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Escape extinction is the most appropriate intervention that is function based out of the options provided. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in frequent elopement. You observe Mary and notice that this behavior typically occurs as soon as she is asked to complete a task at school. The teacher typically responds by telling Mary “it’s okay, we will work on this later”. What appears to be the contingency in place?",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated negative reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                  "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                  "Automatic positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "Socially mediated negative reinforcement is correct, because the teacher is permitting the escape. The removal of the school work demands increases the frequency of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in frequent elopement. You observe Mary and notice that this behavior typically occurs as soon as she is asked to complete a task at school. The teacher typically responds by telling Mary “it’s okay, we will work on this later”. What appears to be the function of Mary’s behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Escape",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Access",
                  "Sensory",
                  "Attention"
                ],
                "explanation": "Mary is getting out of school work. This appears to be maintained by escape. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in frequent elopement. You observe Mary and notice that this behavior typically occurs as soon as she is asked to complete a task at school. The teacher typically responds by telling Mary “it’s okay, we will work on this later”. What might be a function based intervention for Mary?",
                "correctAnswer": "Escape extinction",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "DRO",
                  "Planned ignore",
                  "Sensory extinction"
                ],
                "explanation": "Escape extinction is the most appropriate intervention that is function based out of the options provided. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas makes crude jokes frequently. You notice that most people laugh when he tells these jokes, increasing the likelihood that he will tell these jokes again. What contingency appears to be occurring?",
                "correctAnswer": "Socially mediated positive reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Socially mediated negative reinforcement",
                  "Automatic negative reinforcement",
                  "Automatic positive reinforcement"
                ],
                "explanation": "This behavior is socially mediated (other people laughing) and is positive reinforcement, in that the addition of the stimulus (laughing) increases the likelihood of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Thomas makes crude jokes frequently. You notice that most people laugh when he tells these jokes, increasing the likelihood that he will tell these jokes again. What appears to be the function of this behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Attention",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Access",
                  "Sensory",
                  "Escape"
                ],
                "explanation": "Attention (people laughing) appears to be the function of this behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 501-504)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Response and stimulus generalization",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Sara sees the color blue and says “blue.” Sara sees the color sky blue and says “blue”. Sara sees the color dark blue and says “blue”. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when a different stimulus evokes the same response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are teaching your child letters. You have taught it in a structured environment and now are working on identifying letters in different environments. When you are at the mall, you both see the letter “X” on the “Exit” sign. You point to it and ask the child “What letter do you see?”. The child says “X”. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when a different stimulus evokes the same response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Sara is taught to write with her right hand. The next day, her teacher notices that she is writing with her left hand. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits an untrained response which is functionally equivalent to the trained behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a learner emits an untrained response which is functionally equivalent to the trained behavior.",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits an untrained response which is functionally equivalent to the trained behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This occurs when a different stimulus evokes the same response.",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when a different stimulus evokes the same response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Generalization is not always a good thing. Sometimes maladaptive behaviors may generalize to a new form or setting. The nontechnical term commonly used for this is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Overgeneralization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Overgeneralization occurs when maladaptive behaviors generalize to a new form or setting. This is commonly used, but is not a technical term. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The extent to which behavior occurs after the intervention has been removed refers to:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response maintenance",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Overgeneralization",
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response maintenance refers to behavior that occurs after the intervention has been removed. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is trained to give high 5’s by putting her hand out (palm up). She then gives a high 5 by putting her hand with palms facing outwards, without being trained to do so. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits an untrained response which is functionally equivalent to the trained behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is trained to put her pants on by placing her left leg in, then her right leg in. Later, she is observed sitting down and putting both legs in the pants at the same time. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Response generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Stimulus generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Response generalization occurs when a learner emits an untrained response which is functionally equivalent to the trained behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary is trained to put her pants on while in the clinic. Then, she is seen putting her pants on at home without training at home. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Stimulus generalization",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Response generalization",
                  "Response maintenance",
                  "Overgeneralization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Stimulus generalization occurs when a different stimulus evokes the same response. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 615-622)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Behavioral contrast, behavioral momentum, and matching law",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Ms. Rachel is giving Tracy 5 minutes of tablet time for completing  each step of her doing laundry task analysis for a total of 30 minutes possible at the end of the school day. Tracy has been completing each step of her task analysis independently for 4 weeks. Tracy’s mom does not have a tablet at home, and Tracy has been noncompliant since this program began at school. What appears to be the issue?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Tracy is now only extrinsically motivated",
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "Tracy has lost interest in the iPad as a reinforcer"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast is evident in that a program is occurring at school but not at home. Where the program is not being implemented, Tracy is noncompliant. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "When change to an intervention in one setting changes the frequency in that setting, and the frequency changes in the opposite direction in the setting where the intervention remained unchanged. This phenomenon is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral contrast",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "Matching law",
                  "Punishment"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when change to an intervention in one setting changes the frequency in that setting, and the frequency changes in the opposite direction in the setting where the intervention remained unchanged. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Tracy is punished for cursing at school, which has resulted in a decrease in cursing at school. Behavioral contrast is said to occur in this situation of at home, where there is no punishment:",
                "correctAnswer": "Cursing increases",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Cursing decreases",
                  "Cursing remains the same",
                  "Cursing is replaced with a functionally equivalent behavior."
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral contrast occurs when change to an intervention in one setting changes the frequency in that setting, and the frequency changes in the opposite direction in the setting where the intervention remained unchanged. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 337)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Rate of responding is proportional to the rate of reinforcement received from each choice alternative. This is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "Matching law",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "Stimulus generalization"
                ],
                "explanation": "Matching law states that rate of responding is proportional to the rate of reinforcement received from each choice alternative. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 318)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The matching law is applicable with which schedule of reinforcement?",
                "correctAnswer": "Concurrent schedules",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Multiple schedules",
                  "Mixed schedules",
                  "Variable interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "The matching law is applicable to concurrent schedules where two options are available at the same time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 318)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John mows his neighbors’ lawns. Mrs. Green pays $15, Mrs. Red pays $10, and Mrs. Black pays $20. All lawns are the same size and require the same effort. John only has time to mow one lawn, according to the matching law, whose lawn will John mow? ",
                "correctAnswer": "Mrs. Black",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mrs. Green",
                  "Mrs. Red",
                  "No lawns"
                ],
                "explanation": "Matching law states that rate of responding is proportional to the rate of reinforcement received from each choice alternative. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 318)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is known as a metaphor to describe a rate of responding and its resistance to change following an alteration in reinforcement conditions?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral momentum",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Matching law",
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Variable interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral momentum is a metaphor to describe a rate of responding and its resistance to change following an alteration in reinforcement conditions. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 493)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The high-probability request sequence is based on which behavioral metaphor?",
                "correctAnswer": "Behavioral momentum",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Matching law",
                  "Behavioral contrast",
                  "Variable interval"
                ],
                "explanation": "Behavioral momentum is a metaphor to describe a rate of responding and its resistance to change following an alteration in reinforcement conditions. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 493)"
              },
              {
                "question": "To conduct a high-probability request sequence, the learner starts by presenting 3-5:",
                "correctAnswer": "High probability requests",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Low probability requests",
                  "Appetitive stimuli",
                  "Aversive stimuli"
                ],
                "explanation": "The high-p request sequence is conducted by first presenting 3-5 high probability requests, then a low probability request. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 493)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jeremy often refuses to brush his teeth. His father gives several requests Jeremy enjoys doing such as spinning in a circle, jumping, giving 5, etc. Jeremy is then asked to brush his teeth, and he complies. This procedure is known as:",
                "correctAnswer": "High-probability request sequence",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Behavioral momentum",
                  "Differential reinforcement",
                  "Stimulus discrimination training"
                ],
                "explanation": "The high-p request sequence is conducted by first presenting 3-5 high probability requests, then a low probability request. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 493)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Contingency-shaped behavior & rule governed behavior",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "You are told not to drink soda because it is unhealthy. You immediately stop drinking soda, even though you have never personally felt the negative side effects of drinking soda. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule-governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule-governed behavior is behavior that occurs as a result of a stated rule, without directly coming in to contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are told not to drink soda because it is unhealthy. You immediately stop drinking soda, even though you have never personally felt the negative side effects of drinking soda. Being told about the negative effects of soda is a:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A rule is a verbal statement outlining a contingency, without requiring actual contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You drink soda every day. One day you choke on the soda and the frequency of that behavior decreases. This behavioral change is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is controlled by temporally close consequences. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "This is a verbal statement outlining a contingency, without requiring actual contact with the contingency.",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "A rule is a verbal statement outlining a contingency, without requiring actual contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of behavior is controlled by temporally close consequences?",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is controlled by temporally close consequences. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What type of behavior is controlled by a verbal statement describing a contingency?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule-governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule-governed behavior is behavior that occurs as a result of a stated rule, without directly coming in to contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Even though he has never been in a car accident or received a ticket, John usually buckles his seat belt without being told every time he sits in a vehicle. John buckling his seat belt is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule-governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule-governed behavior is behavior that occurs as a result of a stated rule, without directly coming in to contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John rarely wore his seatbelt. Luckily he was wearing a seatbelt when he got in a car accident, and remained unharmed. From that day on John wore his seatbelt daily. John’s seatbelt wearing behavior appears to be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is controlled by temporally close consequences. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary has never smoked a cigarette because she is underage, and does not want to have legal problems. Mary’s behavior appears to be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Rule-governed behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                  "Shaping",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rule-governed behavior is behavior that occurs as a result of a stated rule, without directly coming in to contact with the contingency. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary smokes cigarettes even though she is a minor. She is arrested and fined for this illegal behavior. Mary does not smoke again. Mary’s behavior appears to be:",
                "correctAnswer": "Contingency-shaped behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rule-governed behavior",
                  "Contingency",
                  "Rule"
                ],
                "explanation": "Contingency shaped behavior is controlled by temporally close consequences. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 703)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Echoics and Mands",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which verbal operant is a repeat of another speaker’s verbal behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Echoic",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic is the verbal operant which is a repeat of another speaker’s verbal behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If I say “run” to a girl, this is a mand under which condition:",
                "correctAnswer": "There is a dog running toward the girl",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The girl asked what my dog is doing",
                  "The girl said “run” and I was repeating her",
                  "The girl asked me what I like to do"
                ],
                "explanation": "The mand is a verbal operant where the speaker asks for what they “need”/”want”. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "If I say “run” to a girl, this is an echoic verbal operant under which condition?",
                "correctAnswer": "The girl said “run”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "There is a dog running toward the girl",
                  "The girl asked what my dog is doing",
                  "The girl asked me what I like to do"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic is the verbal operant which is a repeat of another speaker’s verbal behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which verbal operant is controlled by a motivating operation?",
                "correctAnswer": "Mand",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Echoic",
                  "Tact",
                  "Intraverbal"
                ],
                "explanation": "The Mand is a verbal operant which is controlled by a motivating operation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What does echoic behavior produce for the speaker?",
                "correctAnswer": "Generalized conditioned reinforcement",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The item requested",
                  "Escape",
                  "Additional verbal behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic behavior results in generalized conditioned reinforcement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is produced for the speaker as reinforcement for a mand?",
                "correctAnswer": "The item requested",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Generalized conditioned reinforcement",
                  "Escape",
                  "Additional verbal behavior"
                ],
                "explanation": "The item requested is produced for the speaker following a mand. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary says “duck” to her friend standing next to her. This is a mand if:",
                "correctAnswer": "A Frisbee is flying toward Mary’s friend",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "There is a duck nearby",
                  "The friend asked “Mary, what it is your favorite food?”",
                  "The friend says “duck”."
                ],
                "explanation": "The Mand is a verbal operant which is controlled by a motivating operation. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary says “duck” to her friend standing next to her. This is echoic behavior if:",
                "correctAnswer": "The friend says “duck”.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A Frisbee is flying toward Mary’s friend",
                  "There is a duck nearby",
                  "The friend asked “Mary, what it is your favorite food?”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic is the verbal operant which is a repeat of another speaker’s verbal behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ally says “cookie”. This would be a mand if:",
                "correctAnswer": "It resulted in Ally getting a cookie",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "If another speaker said “cookie”",
                  "It resulted in praise",
                  "Mary sees a cookie"
                ],
                "explanation": "The item requested is produced for the speaker following a mand. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Ally says “cookie”. This would be echoic behavior if:",
                "correctAnswer": "If another speaker said “cookie”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "It resulted in Ally getting a cookie",
                  "It resulted in praise",
                  "Mary sees a cookie"
                ],
                "explanation": "Echoic is the verbal operant which is a repeat of another speaker’s verbal behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Tacts and Intraverbals",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The therapist is teaching verbal operant to a learner. She holds up a toy car with her hand and asks the learner “what is it?”. The learner says “car”. The therapist then provides the learner with a piece of cookie. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Echoic",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Mand"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "On a field trip to the zoo, Lisa saw the sign to the petting area. Upon entering, a sheep walked by her. Lisa pointed and said “Sheep”. Lisa exhibited which verbal operant?",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Mand",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "I ask my friend “where are your glasses?” And she responds “on the table”, this is an example of which verbs operant?",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Echoic",
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intraverbal operants are evoked by a verbal SD and does not have point to point correspondence. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": " Aliana is in the playground with her family. Suddenly, she sees a cat and says “cat.” Her mom says “good job, that is a cat.” This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "You are driving with your young child in the car. A firetruck drives by while you are at a red light. The child says “firetruck!”. This is an example of what type of verbal behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Tact",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mand",
                  "Intraverbal",
                  "Echoic"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary says “truck”. This would be a tact if:",
                "correctAnswer": "Mary saw a truck",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mary was asked what her favorite type of vehicle is",
                  "Mary’s mom said “truck”",
                  "Mary is given a toy truck"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary says “truck”. This would be an intraverbal operant if:",
                "correctAnswer": "Mary was asked what her favorite type of vehicle is",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Mary saw a truck",
                  "Mary’s mom said “truck”",
                  "Mary is given a toy truck"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intraverbal operants are evoked by a verbal SD and does not have point to point correspondence. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John says “How old are you”, to which Phillip replies “22”. Phillip’s behavior is an example of a(n):",
                "correctAnswer": "Intraverbal",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Echoic",
                  "Mand",
                  "Tact"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intraverbal operants are evoked by a verbal SD and does not have point to point correspondence. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Harold says “pizza”. This would be a tact if:",
                "correctAnswer": "A picture of a pizza was present.",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Harold was asked “What’s your favorite food?”",
                  "Harold is given a pizza",
                  "Someone else said “Pizza”"
                ],
                "explanation": "The tact is a verbal operant in which the speaker names things they see, hear, feel, etc. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Harold says “pizza”. This would be an intraverbal operant if:",
                "correctAnswer": "Harold was asked “What’s your favorite food?”",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "A picture of a pizza was present.",
                  "Harold is given a pizza",
                  "Someone else said “Pizza”"
                ],
                "explanation": "Intraverbal operants are evoked by a verbal SD and does not have point to point correspondence. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 530-531)          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Measurable dimensions of behavior",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "The product of measurement is:",
                "correctAnswer": "Data",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Fluency",
                  "Response",
                  "Artifacts"
                ],
                "explanation": "Data is the product of measurement. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 127)"
              },
              {
                "question": "The dead man test helps in identifying:",
                "correctAnswer": "What constitutes a behavior",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "The environmental variables in the environment",
                  "Potential reinforcers",
                  "All answers are correct"
                ],
                "explanation": "The dead man’s test states that if a dead man can do it, it isn’t a behavior."
              },
              {
                "question": "Which one is not a measurable dimension of behavior?",
                "correctAnswer": "Topography",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Temporal locus",
                  "Repeatability"
                ],
                "explanation": "Topography is not a measurable dimension of behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of behavior states that behavior occurs at a certain point in time?",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal locus",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Frequency"
                ],
                "explanation": "Temporal locus states that behaviors occur at a certain point in time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of behavior states that behavior occurs during some amount of time.",
                "correctAnswer": "Temporal extent",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Repeatability",
                  "Temporal locus",
                  "Rate"
                ],
                "explanation": "Temporal extent states that behavior occurs during some amount of time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which dimension of behavior states that behavior can occur repeated through time, and can be counted.",
                "correctAnswer": "Repeatability",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Temporal extent",
                  "Temporal locus",
                  "Rate"
                ],
                "explanation": "Repeatability states that behavior can occur repeatedly through time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John engaged in 3 angry outbursts per hour. Which measure is this an example of?",
                "correctAnswer": "Rate",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Frequency",
                  "Duration",
                  "IRT"
                ],
                "explanation": "Rate is a measure that calculates the frequency of the behavior across time. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John engaged in an episode of angry outbursts for 3 minutes. This is an example of which measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Duration",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Rate",
                  "Frequency",
                  "IRT"
                ],
                "explanation": "Duration measures the amount of time a behavior occurs. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John engaged in an angry outburst 3 seconds after being prompted to complete a chore. This is an example of which measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Latency",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "IRT",
                  "Frequency",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "Latency is the measure from the stimulus to the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 75)"
              },
              {
                "question": "John engaged in an angry outburst, then 3 seconds later engaged in another angry outburst. This is an example of which measure?",
                "correctAnswer": "IRT",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Latency",
                  "Frequency",
                  "Duration"
                ],
                "explanation": "Inter Response Time refers to the amount of time between to occurrences of behavior.          {"
              }
            ]
          },
          {
            "name": "Advantages and disadvantages of using continuous and discontinuous measurement procedures",
            "quizquestion": [
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is not a discontinuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording is a continuous measurement procedure. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "What is another name for discontinuous measurement procedures?",
                "correctAnswer": "Time sampling",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Event recording",
                  "Temporal locus"
                ],
                "explanation": "Time sampling (not to be confused with momentary time sampling) is another name for discontinuous measurement procedures. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following underestimates how often the behavior is occurring?",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole Interval Recording ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial Interval Recording",
                  "Duration",
                  "Rate"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole interval recording underestimates the measure of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following overestimates how often the behavior occurs?",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial interval recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Duration",
                  "Rate",
                  "Whole interval recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording overestimates the measure of the behavior. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jose engages in disruptive behaviors in class frequently. To measure this behavior you create measurement intervals and record a “yes” if he was disruptive during the ENTIRE session. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole interval recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling",
                  "Event recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole interval recording records if the behavior occurred during the ENTIRE session. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jose engages in disruptive behaviors in class frequently. To measure this behavior you create measurement intervals and record a “yes” if he was disruptive at any time during the session. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial interval recording ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling",
                  "Event recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording records if the behavior occurred at any time during the session. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Jose engages in disruptive behaviors in class frequently. To measure this behavior you check on Jose once every 30 minutes and record if he was disruptive at that moment. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Momentary time sampling",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial interval recording ",
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Event recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Momentary time sampling occurs by measuring if the behavior occurred at the end of an interval. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Which of the following is a continuous measurement procedure?",
                "correctAnswer": "Event recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling"
                ],
                "explanation": "Event recording is a continuous measurement procedure. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in hand flapping frequently, making it difficult to record this behavior. You create intervals, and document if the behavior occurred during the ENTIRE interval. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Whole interval recording",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Partial interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling",
                  "Event recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Whole interval recording records if the behavior occurred during the ENTIRE session. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
              },
              {
                "question": "Mary engages in hand flapping frequently, making it difficult to record this behavior. You create intervals and document “yes” if the behavior occurred at all during the session. This is an example of:",
                "correctAnswer": "Partial interval recording ",
                "wrongAnswer": [
                  "Whole interval recording",
                  "Momentary time sampling",
                  "Event recording"
                ],
                "explanation": "Partial interval recording records if the behavior occurred at any time during the session. (Cooper et al., 2007, p. 88-93)"
			  }
            ]
          }
        ]
      }	  
    ]
  }
}
